<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BriefBot</title>
        <description>Brexit, explained</description>
        <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>BriefBot</title>
            <url>http://example.com/image.png</url>
            <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2016, Explaain</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortgage lending climbed in August, says CML]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2016/sep/22/mortgage-lending-august-cml-housing-market-eu-vote</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2016/sep/22/mortgage-lending-august-cml-housing-market-eu-vote</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:13:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Figures show resilience of housing market despite fears of crash following vote to leave EU<br></p><p>Gross mortgage lending hit its highest August level since before the financial crash, figures show, as the housing market appeared to defy fears of a crash after the Brexit vote.</p><p>The Council of Mortgage Lenders (CML) said its members had advanced a total of £22.5bn during the month, 7% higher than July’s figure and up 15% year on year.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2016/sep/22/mortgage-lending-august-cml-housing-market-eu-vote">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK manufacturing expands strongly in September - CBI]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/TQj_zCeGa20/uk-britain-industrialoutput-cbi-idUKKCN11S0WU</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/TQj_zCeGa20/uk-britain-industrialoutput-cbi-idUKKCN11S0WU</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[LONDON, (Reuters) - - British manufacturing grew strongly in September and orders flowed in at an above-average rate, adding to signs the economy has avoided an immediate hit from June's Brexit vote, an industry survey showed on Thursday.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:T6YwghH5uPs:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:T6YwghH5uPs:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=TQj_zCeGa20:T6YwghH5uPs:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:T6YwghH5uPs:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=TQj_zCeGa20:T6YwghH5uPs:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/TQj_zCeGa20" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[David Miliband claims Corbyn has made Labour 'unelectable' - Politics live]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/blog/live/2016/sep/22/labour-leadership-jeremy-corbyn-david-miliband-claims-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable-politics-live</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/blog/live/2016/sep/22/labour-leadership-jeremy-corbyn-david-miliband-claims-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable-politics-live</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:05:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rolling coverage of all the day’s political developments as they happen</p><p class="block-time published-time"> <time datetime="2016-09-22T10:05:49.124Z">11.05am <span class="timezone">BST</span></time> </p><p>Labour party staff are demanding seats on the party’s national executive committee. <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-37437611">According to the BBC, </a>which broke the story, the move was prompted by newspaper reports claiming that, if Jeremy Corbyn is re-elected leader, some staff working for the party could be replaced by people deemed more loyal to him. Corbyn has filled the leader’s office with people strongly committed to his brand of politics, but most staff at Labour HQ are not seen as committed Corbynistas.</p><p>Staff working for the party are represented by GMB and Unite and their convenors, Jim Harvey and Tim Waters, wrote to Corbyn on Monday this week asking him to “pledge your support for unionised Labour Party workers”. Interestingly, they cited Theresa May’s commitment to putting workers on company boards as a reason why Labour staff should be represented on the NEC.</p><p>It is disappointing that while the Tory prime minister has promised worker representation on company boards that Labour Party workers are currently unrepresented on their own executive. It is therefore only right that the Labour party should lead by example and ensure worker representation on the NEC. </p><p>It would be deeply hypocritical of the party to espouse the importance of staff representation in other organisations and companies and not to act itself to put into practice the demands it places on others.</p><p>As a lifelong and committed trade unionist myself, and as leader of the Labour party, I want to make it absolutely clear that I, and my senior management team, are not supportive of any compulsory redundancies. </p><p>At this stage, no changes to staff have been proposed and nor would they ever be outside of the context of a properly structured change management programme will full trade union engagement. </p><p class="block-time published-time"> <time datetime="2016-09-22T09:44:09.172Z">10.44am <span class="timezone">BST</span></time> </p><p>The <strong>Bank of England</strong> has warned over a “challenging” outlook for financial stability in the UK as the nation faces “uncertainty and adjustment” following the Brexit vote, the Press Association reports.</p><p>The Bank’s financial policy committee (FPC) said that while the financial system has been resilient since the decision to quit the EU, there were concerns over the impact on the UK’s public finances, commercial property and over-indebted borrowers. </p><p>But it said bank capital standards will not be relaxed following Brexit, telling lenders they could expect rules “at least as great as that currently planned”. </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/blog/live/2016/sep/22/labour-leadership-jeremy-corbyn-david-miliband-claims-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable-politics-live">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[English Devolution Post-Brexit: Cameron Exit Stage Left, Cue Mrs May]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/nikki-knowles/brexit_b_12132854.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/nikki-knowles/brexit_b_12132854.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Devolution has been one of the core policies of the Conservatives since regaining power in 2010. It will be one of the greatest downward transfers of power from Whitehall to the regions in English constitutional history. However, in light of the other monumental constitutional change that is going to take place, Brexit, not to mention the recent change in administration, where does this leave English devolution?<br />
<br />
It's well known that Theresa May is not as fanatical about Metro Mayors as Osborne or Cameron. It's still uncertain if Mrs May will do away with the position but policy surrounding them is already differing from that of the last administrations. Downing Street have said areas that did not want an elected mayor would not have one forced upon them. However, out of all of the devolution deals struck to date, having a metro mayor has been a requisite. Number 10 press office insists this does not represent a change in policy despite obviously representing one.<br />
<br />
Mrs May's primary concerns regarding English devolution is that she's nervous about giving senior Labour politicians a platform and giving them the opportunity to consolidate and reinforce their fragmenting heartlands. She is also anxious about the local hostility being created over the imposed mayors. <br />
<br />
In spite of allegations, Mrs May is going cold on Metro Mayors, yet she has not abandoned English devolution plans. Gears continue to whir in Parliament to enable mayors to be elected in May 2017 and Mayoral candidates have started to be selected. Furthermore, her cabinet appointments are telling on what her plans for English devolution may be. <br />
<br />
English devolution was at the heart of Greg Clark's agenda whilst he was at the DCLG. In his view, regional devolution was to be a driver for house-building and infrastructure investments; but fundamentally regional growth to balance the UK economy which is dominated by professional services in the south east of the country.  In this aim, he was vehemently supported by Cameron and the treasury. <br />
<br />
In his new role as Secretary of State for BEIS, Clark's drive for decentralisation is set to continue and devolution of economic powers to regions will be a priority for this new department and at the heart of the new government's Industrial Strategy. BEIS has also announced that each of their ministers will have specific areas for which they are responsible as 'local growth champions'.<br />
<br />
Replacing Clark as the new DCLG Secretary of State is Sajid Javid; his priorities for his new role "are to build more homes and ... devolve powers to local areas". Indeed, in his previous role as Secretary of State for Business, Innovation and Skills he was seen as a 'devolution champion', helping to give local authority more power over skills and apprenticeship policy. Seen as a close ally of George Osborne, Javid shares his desire to see powers devolved so he's unlikely to allow devolution policy to falter now.<br />
The role of Minister for the Northern Powerhouse in the Department for Communities and Local Government (DCLG) has been kept and is now held by Andrew Percy. A Yorkshire MP and former local Councillor in Hull, Percy believes in decentralising responsibilities and powers to local government and has already started touring northern cities and regions. <br />
<br />
There's still a question mark over the new Chancellor of the Exchequer's dedication to devolution but if appointments are anything to go by, Jim O'Neill has been appointed Commercial Secretary to the Treasury. O'Neill is a furious advocate for devolution, and a former chair of the Cities Growth Commission. He will be responsible for city devolution, including the Northern Powerhouse and industrial strategy.<br />
<br />
In light of Brexit, it would be easy for English devolution to be forgotten about but at this time, more than ever, English devolution is tremendously important for the UK's future. If Mrs May allows all the surrendered EU powers to reside in Westminster and not the regions, she will oversee the greatest centralisation of power since the Blair era, undoing what the Conservatives have strived to do for the last six years - diminish central government. Before Article 50 is triggered, Mrs May needs to ensure that regional government is equipped in understanding, structure and oversight to take on the extra powers and responsibility that Brexit will bestow. <br />
<br />
While there are strong indicators that English devolution will be at the heart of this Government's growth strategy, a clear commitment needs to be made by Number 10 and 11 that the process of devolution is not being kicked into the long grass and is set to continue. Conflicting messages and vague assurances could undermine the process and at this time of economic and democratic uncertainty, the business community and local government need some guarantee that the Government has an industrial strategy for the whole of the UK and plan for Brexit and beyond. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rules Of The Game]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/john-watson/the-rules-of-the-game_1_b_12128794.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/john-watson/the-rules-of-the-game_1_b_12128794.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[What is this talk of gerrymandering?<br />
<br />
"I have never believed in questioning or second-guessing the decision of the referee." The words appear in the final paragraph of David Laws' book Coalition and the referee he is referring to is the British electorate which so brutally rejected his party in May 2015.  Obviously Laws himself must have regarded the decision as a very disappointing one but his acceptance of the verdict made in accordance with the system is refreshing, and a pleasant break from the usual whinge that rules which produce the wrong result (according to the preferences of the speaker) must in some way be wrong or unfair.  The  proposals for changes in constituency boundaries have brought the whingers out in force.<br />
<br />
"An affront to democracy", "A dog's dinner", that is the very least of it.  No lesser person than Emily Thornberry, the Shadow Foreign Secretary, is reported as saying, "it's very obvious gerrymandering.  The whole thing stinks".  Well that sounds terrible, doesn't it?  No one suggests that the Boundary Commissioners themselves have misbehaved, of course.  They are an independent body under the control of the Speaker but in practice chaired by a High Court Judge, so it must be the rules which they have to apply in making their recommendations which are wrong.  Yes, that must be it, a recommendation made in accordance with wicked Tory rules to be forced through in due course by a wicked Tory majority.  Labour's prospects at the next election unfairly trashed.  No wonder that it has given the Thornberrys of this world indigestion.<br />
<br />
Most normal people have better things to do than read the rules which the Boundary Commission use to make recommendations.  Still, in view of the appalling threat to our democracy, perhaps it would be a good thing to take a peep inside the Guide to the 2018 Review of Parliamentary Constituencies which sets them out at schedule D.  Well no, they won't win the Booker Prize and the lack of racy language betrays that they are simply copied from the Parliamentary Constituencies Act 1986, but they are short and fairly clear.  For those with a taste for such things here is a <a href="http://boundarycommissionforengland.independent.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2016-07-11-Guide-to-2018-review-Final-Version.pdf" target="_hplink">link</a>.<br />
<br />
Of course the fact that the rules are in the 1986 act does not make all of them thirty years old. They were added to in 1992 and 2011 and it is the latter changes which require that the current review should reduce the number of constituencies in the UK to 600 and provide that (save in certain exceptional circumstances - e.g. constituencies of over 12,000 km², etc.) no constituency may have more than 95% or less than 105% of the average number of electors.  As the average is 74,769 that sets a maximum of 78,507 and a minimum of 71,031.<br />
<br />
This requirement, which must be strictly applied, can be contrasted with a number of factors which the Boundary Commission may take into account if they think fit.  Those include existing constituency boundaries, special geographical considerations and things of that sort; but, although that may help the Commissioners to select boundaries, they cannot override the maximum and minimum limits.<br />
<br />
It is these limits on constituency size which seem to have caused the outrage.  For obvious reasons the review process has to work from historic data, and the law requires that the calculations are done by reference to the register of voters two years and ten months before a final report has to be presented to the House of Commons.  The final report arising from the present review is to be presented in 2018 and so boundaries are to be drawn on the assumption that the number of electors in any area is the number who were registered in December 2015.  No account is taken of those who have registered since or, indeed, of foreigners living in the area who are not entitled to register.  MPs from areas where there is more than the usual number of these think this unfair.  If unregistered voters were included, or if the rules had set a later date, their area would have more representation.<br />
<br />
One would like to say that these protests arose from aspirations to achieve the purest possible form of democracy but, alas, it is hard to do so.  For many years a failure to update the system biased it heavily against the Conservatives and the fact that the latter could not outvote the combination of Labour and the Liberal Democrats blocked any reform in 2013.  Labour MPs did not protest then, of course.  They simply sat on the advantage given them and toasted the fact that Tories did not have the majority they needed to level the playing field.<br />
<br />
This article is not about hypocrisy, however, but about something rather different.  Maybe you would get a different result if the "review date" was a month or two later.  Maybe it would be better if foreigners without votes were counted.  Perhaps it would or perhaps it would not, but the fact is that we have a system which on the face of it is reasonably fair, and it is no good ranting on about it being unfair if the result doesn't happen to suit you.<br />
<br />
We have seen much of the same in relation to the Brexit referendum, of course.  I have always been a Remain and didn't particularly care for the result, but I accept that the referendum was the route chosen to decide the matter, that that route has been followed and that a decision has been made.  It is tedious in the extreme to hear those who argue for a second referendum biased towards a Remain view by giving votes to 16-year-olds (after all they have to live with the system for longer, poor dears), weighting the vote against those who are sixty-five (after all they haven't got long to go, poor dears) or simply removing the vote from everyone who lives south of the River.  Maybe these would be wonderful systems or maybe they would not, but they don't happen to be the one chosen.<br />
<br />
There comes a stage, of course, when systems of decision-making have to be updated.  Sometimes that means wholesale change, as with the 1832 reform act or the introduction of female suffrage; more often it is just a question of adjusting rules or changing their application.  At that stage a decision has to be made as to what the optimum rules will be and usually there is a choice with much to be said for one version or another.  Once that choice has been made it will dictate the results when the rules come to be applied.<br />
<br />
That is how rules work and for the system to be successful it is important to keep to the order.  First you make the rules. Then you apply them.  If you cry "foul" and start changing the rules every time the result of their application does not suit you, you might as well not have rules at all.  Then there would be nothing to stop the strongest from imposing their will on the weakest.  That would be a bad result in a country which claims to work by the rule of law.<br />
<br />
The Report of the Boundary Commission is the beginning of a process of consultation and that process will no doubt throw up a number of changes to the plan before it is finally adopted.  What cannot be changed, however, are the minimum number of electors in a constituency and how that number is measured.  Emily Thornberry and her friends should accept that.  It is one thing to argue in the consultation how the rules should be applied.  That is what the process is for.  It is quite another to start shouting "gerrymandering" or "disgraceful" simply because on this occasion the result of applying the rules does not suit you.<br />
<br />
Frst oublished in the <a href="http://www.shawsheet.com" target="_hplink">Shaw Sheet.</a> ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK economy faces challenging period after Brexit vote, says Bank]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:35:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Financial policy committee warns withdrawal from the EU poses risks but will not be used to reduce regulation of banks</p><p>Bank of England financial policymakers have warned that the UK economy faces a “challenging period of uncertainty and adjustment” following the Brexit vote. </p><p>However the Bank, providing a quarterly update on the health of the financial system, said the UK’s withdrawal from the European Union would not be used as a way to reduce regulation on the banking sector.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Britain In A State Of Hidden Civil War? Time To Face Facts]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/chris-erskine/is-britain-in-a-state-of-_b_12113408.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/chris-erskine/is-britain-in-a-state-of-_b_12113408.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:21:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons.jpg"><img alt="2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons-thumb.jpg" width="570" height="398" /></a><br />
<br />
Commentators talk of 'seismic 'shifts in the political landscape, varying states of post-Brexit 'crisis' and hard-to-dispute daily assertions, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2016/sep/21/brexit-care-older-disabled-people-eu-workers-uk" target="_hplink">with supporting evidence</a>, that we live in uncertain and tumultuous times. Yes, agreed, but when are we going to get to the heart of the matter? Does this state of near constant turmoil, brought into sharp relief by the EU Referendum, not turn our suspicions to the theory of a persistent and obvious menace - Britain is in a state of hidden civil war.<br />
<br />
If a civil war isn't fought with the fire of ammunition, can it be cultivated by an untamed media, self-interested legislators and cowardly, unaccountable corporations? What happens if it's a near-undetectable, low hum sounding throughout all of our lives? If we don't notice it, we're agents of it and unable to resist. How do we choose sides? How can we win? Let's start by facing up to it.<br />
<br />
Britain's hidden civil war is a state that was exposed, first via<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2008/dec/28/markets-credit-crunch-banking-2008" target="_hplink"> the financial crisis of 2008</a>, when the tide went out and revealed the vested interests of the dominant and most powerful elements of our society, sustained over the following eight years in the interests of the same, prevailing forces, before turning its latest trick: the campaign to leave or remain in the EU aiming to skewer what remained of cohesive society. <br />
<br />
At first glance, the idea of a civil war within these lands may seem crazy, but just how far-fetched is this in the age of the<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-36138337" target="_hplink"> Hillsborough revelations</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News_International_phone_hacking_scandal" target="_hplink">phone tapping by the media </a>and the <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/sir-philip-green-issues-grovelling-8798217" target="_hplink">disappearance of thousands of BHS jobs </a>in the name of creating unimaginable individual wealth? We fear terrorism, nuclear disaster and other unlikely, catastrophic events more readily than civil war as our state of conflict is, perhaps, our 'new normal'.<br />
<br />
The signs of militarised violence are replaced with domestic violence and abuse, household debt and <a href="http://pocketmoneyloans.com/" target="_hplink">payday loans</a>, deterioration of the NHS, increases in racial tensions, fragmentation of communities and zero-hours contracts. It is the environment in which 'us versus them' cultures proliferate amongst people without power and privilege, without the means to determine their own laws, leaving the road clear for those that do. <br />
<br />
Just who does really benefit from ideas such as Brexit, austerity and privatisation? These are the questions found at the heart of the work of a number of artists from the UK and around the world that are stepping up to the plate - not just now, but constantly - to examine the constant attacks on people who can't ascend the accepted economic and political systems. Those people might be migrants, the unemployed and, perhaps, the artists themselves.<br />
<br />
An artist and activists role is often to challenge what is true, acquire knowledge of alternatives and, as a result, challenge the norms that become engrained. Newcastle is home to <a href="http://thenewbridgeproject.com/hidden-civil-war-exhibitions/" target="_hplink">Hidden Civil War</a>, a concentrated period of art expression throughout October, inviting artists such as <a href="http://www.spellingmistakescostlives.com/" target="_hplink">Darren Cullen</a> - the originator of the 'pop-up' Pocketmoney Loans for children outlet as well as a series of maimed Action Men toys - and <a href="http://dedomenici.com/" target="_hplink">Richard De Domenici</a>, who held a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2016/jan/19/richard-dedomenici-death-social-housing-camden-peoples-theatre-art-matrix-redux" target="_hplink">funeral cortege for London's social housing provision </a>earlier in the year, to find and reveal evidence of our hidden civil war. <br />
<br />
Asking artists to do it, often in collaboration with communities, means we get to appreciate and celebrate alternative voices and expressions of life with honesty, whilst also disrupting and dis-lodging mainstream forms of knowledge and understanding. Hidden Civil War won't be some 'lefty finger pointing exercise', as the organisers we know that we are truly all in this together, in as much as we are all economic addicts and unwittingly complicit.<br />
<br />
There are no simple solutions to identifying and solving Britain's hidden civil war - we don't know who is fighting or who we should be rooting to win - but that cannot mean simple surrender. Placing art at the heart of our exploration is no mistake, it's vital, but it is not in isolation. Voices and ideas from the areas of food, land, travellers, domestic violence, poverty, asylum and debt are all vital to finding grains of truth that allow us to face up to our Hidden Civil War. To face difficult truths in troubled times, we require deep collaboration, reflection and above all, listening. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battles of Britain, table-tennis trickery and the brilliant Lamar Jackson | Classic YouTube]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week’s roundup also features drone surfing, hardcore whiff-whaff, and the best way to overtake a peloton</p><p>1) It doesn’t get easier for Brendan Rodgers. A fortnight after his side <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/13/barcelona-celtic-champions-league-match-report">took a pasting in Spain</a>, it’s ‘Battle’ of Britain week: Celtic versus Manchester City on Wednesday. He can take heart, though, from some notable BoB classics – including <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qsDPlK2qpEw">Celtic’s 2-1 1970 European Cup semi-final win </a>over Don Revie’s Leeds in front of 136,000 at Hampden Park; Rangers winning both legs of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ndai-x2F1GM&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=30s">1992’s clash with Leeds</a>; Alex Ferguson’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3xh4-t9fwg">Aberdeen undoing Uefa Cup holders Ipswich</a> in 1981; and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vZIXnyLboOY">Celtic beating Liverpool</a> on the way to the 2003 Uefa Cup final. </p><p>2) Life’s good right now for Lamar Jackson – Louisville Cardinals’ Heisman Trophy favourite and teen <a href="http://www.campusrush.com/lamar-jackson-louisville-cardinals-football-2010380683.html">Sports Illustrated coverstar</a>. Here’s a flavour: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHiKOxR9XU8">an Eminem backed showreel</a>, a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC-bMQWpM7I">high-school highlight</a>, some more <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=65Y5YR7zGqg">high-school highlights</a>, an engaging <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=avhiLsvHAtY">post-game chat</a>, and this: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W90diVFAZVU">HE HAS THE JETS, AND HE TURNS THEM ON</a>. He’s the American football version of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RoUc0iAjHvY">this kid</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bank of England says UK faces 'challenging period' for financial stability]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/vZKGmOr22wE/uk-britain-boe-idUKKCN11S0N6</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/vZKGmOr22wE/uk-britain-boe-idUKKCN11S0N6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:00:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[LONDON (Reuters) - Britain still faces a "challenging period" for financial stability despite resilience seen after the European Union referendum, and rules for banks must remain tight, the Bank of England said on Thursday.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=vZKGmOr22wE:gxw86aOU4e4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=vZKGmOr22wE:gxw86aOU4e4:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=vZKGmOr22wE:gxw86aOU4e4:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=vZKGmOr22wE:gxw86aOU4e4:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=vZKGmOr22wE:gxw86aOU4e4:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/vZKGmOr22wE" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Revolutionary’ European Tour proposals risk turning golf into a gimmick | Ewan Murray]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:59:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week the European Tour announced details of the World Super 6 Perth which includes 54 holes of stroke play, six-hole match play games and a 90m knockout hole. Will hitting shots on the run or through rings of fire be next?<p>At times like these, the PGA Tour properly flexes its financial muscle. This week’s Tour Championship at East Lake concludes a four-event series which delivers $34m in prize monies. That’s before the epic bonus pool for the FedEx Cup, starting with a $10m first prize, is even taken into account.</p><p>These riches are deemed grotesque by some, even if they still lag behind the peak of American team sports. It also raises a smile that the PGA Tour’s strength is endorsed immediately before the Ryder Cup, an iconic competition to which it has no commercial attachment. Perhaps the proximity of this playoff series is actually detrimental to the biennial meeting of Europe and the United States, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/20/jordan-spieth-ryder-cup-fedex-cup-10m" title="">given how narratives overlap</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[David Miliband Says Jeremy Corbyn Has Made Labour 'Unelectable']]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/david-miliband-says-jeremy-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable_n_12132344.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/david-miliband-says-jeremy-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable_n_12132344.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">David Miliband has claimed the Labour Party has not been further from power since the 1930s as part of a stinging attack on Jeremy Corbyn.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>The one-time favourite for the Labour leadership branded the party &ldquo;unelectable&rdquo; and said Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s &ldquo;half-hearted&rdquo; campaigning for Britain to remain in the European Union was &ldquo;a betrayal of millions of working people&rdquo;.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Meanwhile, Mr Corbyn has insisted his leadership style is unlikely to change should he beat challenger Owen Smith and be named the winner of the contest for the Labour top job on Saturday.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Voting in the leadership battle closed at noon on Wednesday and Mr Corbyn is the overwhelming favourite to take victory.</p><br />
</div><br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">&nbsp;But Mr Miliband, the former foreign secretary, has set out a damning assessment of the incumbent.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Writing in The New Statesman, he said: &ldquo;The main charge against Jeremy Corbyn is not just that his strategy is undesirable because it makes the party unelectable. That is only half the story.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;The real issue is that his strategy makes the party unelectable because it is in many aspects undesirable.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Mr Miliband is particularly critical of Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s &ldquo;egregious&rdquo; stance on foreign policy.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;But the electorate can see through the domestic policy, too,&rdquo; he said.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;Nationalisation cannot be the answer to everything; anti-austerity speeches cannot explain everything; corporate taxation cannot pay for everything.&nbsp;It doesn&rsquo;t add up. It wouldn&rsquo;t work. People are not stupid.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-party-conference-staff-warning-aggressive-violent-conduct_uk_57e2ca0de4b0e81629a8da48" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/ETQtJm" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
     <br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">&nbsp;Mr Miliband said it is &ldquo;disastrous&rdquo; that people are branded &ldquo;closet Tories&rdquo; or &ldquo;Tory Lite&rdquo; if they disagree with Mr Corbyn.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>The president of the International Rescue Committee claimed Labour had slipped from a party fit for government to a &ldquo;secondary influence on national decision making&rdquo;, adding: &ldquo;We have not been further from power since the 1930s.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Meanwhile, Mr Corbyn has promised to work with Mr Smith and other internal critics if he is confirmed as leader on Saturday in order to heal the rift which saw him lose a confidence vote among the parliamentary party by a margin of 172-40.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Mr Smith has said he will not accept a place in Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s shadow cabinet if the current leader retains power.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>In a statement following the close of polls, Mr Corbyn said: &ldquo;As far as I am concerned, the slate will be wiped clean this weekend.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;If I am re-elected leader, I will reach out to and work with all Labour MPs to form a broad and effective opposition to this divisive and floundering Tory government.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;All Labour party members and MPs have a responsibility to work within the democracy of our party and respect the leadership of whoever is elected.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>But Mr Corbyn has set himself against proposals from deputy leader Tom Watson to return to the electoral college system which gave MPs and unions more say over the choice of a leader.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;I think we have to stick with one-member one-vote,&rdquo; he said.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Labour&rsquo;s ruling National Executive Committee has put off a decision on MPs&rsquo; demand to be allowed to elect members of Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s shadow cabinet.</p><br />
</div><br />
<p>&nbsp;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/wI8CK3" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour has no option but to hold together | Jonathan Reynolds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[History is littered with examples of failed breakaway parties. A split is out of the question if we are to challenge Conservative hegemony<p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/labour" title="">Labour</a> has a had a torrid time of late. Since last summer the tone of the party’s internal debate has been shrill and bitter. Views have become increasingly polarised, and speculation about a possible split commonplace. We have been likened to a couple who want to divorce but who choose to stay together because we cannot afford to sell the house. Now the polls have closed and, in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/21/corbyn-camp-predicts-comfortable-victory-as-leadership-polls-close" title="">the aftermath of Jeremy Corbyn’s anticipated victory</a> on Saturday, people will almost certainly again raise the question of whether Labour should simply split and let its warring factions walk away from each other.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/20/get-serious-labour-rebels-deal-with-brexit-catastrophe">Get serious, Labour rebels, and deal with the Brexit catastrophe | Polly Toynbee</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit is risking student numbers and vital research funding, says head of Oxford University after it is named world's best]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The institution's Vice Chancellor says other universities are already trying to poach her academics]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit vote is 'major issue' for Lloyd's as profits rise to £1.46bn]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Insurance market is in robust shape, says chief executive, but it now needs to focus on continuing to trade across Europe</p><p>Lloyd’s of London’s chief executive, Inga Beale, has described the Brexit vote as a “major issue for us to deal with”, as the insurance market reported higher profits.</p><p>The world’s oldest insurance market reported a profit of £1.46bn for the first half of this year, up from £1.2bn a year ago. </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermarkets plan to shrink packets and use cheaper ingredients to save money after Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:06:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Waugh Zone September 22, 2016]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/the-waugh-zone-september-_29_n_12131428.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/the-waugh-zone-september-_29_n_12131428.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:04:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://big.assets.huffingtonpost.com/the_waugh_zone.jpg" alt=“"><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<em>The five things you need to know on Thursday, September 22, 2016…</em><br />
<br />
<br />
<img alt="jeremy corbyn" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/4687352/thumbs/o-JEREMY-CORBYN-570.jpg?8" /><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>1) WARRING PEACE</strong><br />
<br />
After months of bitter infighting, the Labour leadership election ballot closed at midday yesterday. But is the war really over? That’s upto Jeremy Corbyn as he and his team meet Tom Watson, Rosie Winterton, PLP chair John Cryer to try to hammer out a deal over Shadow Cabinet elections.<br />
<br />
Jezza declared in his close-of-poll statement (and on the BBC too, so it was no slip of the tongue) that he wanted to ‘wipe the slate clean’ for all those former frontbenchers who had criticised him and backed Owen Smith. It proved that the ‘conciliators’ around the leader are playing to his natural instinct to avoid conflict, but there are some hardliners who still want him to ram his new mandate down the PLP’s throat.<br />
<br />
In his BBC interview, Corbyn showed Laura Kuenssberg his olive tree from which he’s offering his olive branches to MPs. But <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-purge-costs-party-majority-on-bristol-city-council_uk_57e13713e4b05d791371487b" target="_hplink">as HuffPost revealed this week</a>, the tree was itself given to him by a Labour councillor - who has been suspended for suggesting deselection of MPs. <br />
<br />
And on avoiding conflict more broadly, Corbyn underlined his preference for jaw-jaw to war-war in his Ken Loach interview, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-minister-for-peace-diasarmament-nuclear-non-proliferation_uk_57e29fc9e4b0e81629a8ab13?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">revealing his plan for a new Minister for Peace and a Minister for Disarmament</a> (full marks to the Telegraph’s Asa Bennett for spotting it at the end of the hour-long documentary). If he’d called it a ‘Minister for Peacekeeping’, that may have pre-empted the ridicule that followed online. Then again, it may not. And as a keen reader of novels, did Corbyn have any idea that 1984 included a ‘Ministry of Peace’?<br />
<br />
Ahead of the Liverpool conference, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-party-conference-staff-warning-aggressive-violent-conduct_uk_57e2ca0de4b0e81629a8da48?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">we reveal that party staff have been issued with an unprecedented advice note</a> on how to respond to threats of “aggression and potential violence” from activists.  Moreover, amid fears of a ‘clear out’ of alleged ‘moderates’ at HQ, staff weren’t exactly reassured when Corbyn wrote to them saying “at this stage” no “compulsory” redundancies were planned in the party.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>2) BONUS OF PROOF</strong><br />
<br />
Andrew Lansley is disliked on the Left for his NHS reforms and on the Right for his avid Remainer views. Now the former Health Secretary has combined his twin interests by calling for a £5bn-year ‘Brexit Bonus’ for the NHS.<br />
<br />
In his NHS Providers annual lecture, Lord (yes, he’s a peer don’t forget) Lansley tried to call the bluff of the Leavers by saying they’d promised extra cash post-Brexit, and should now prove they can deliver.<br />
<br />
As it happens, it’s Lansley’s own clinical commissioning group (CCG) structure that is causing controversy on several fronts today. Different CCGs have differing funding rates for a breast cancer drug that charities say could save thousands of lives. And on IVF treatment too, there’s a local lottery, with parts of England failing to hit the Nice guidelines, while Scotland guarantees three cycles. As with mental health funding (see below), that Lansley localism has a political downside.<br />
<br />
On the EU more generally, Leavers are delighted that the OECD has admitted it was too gloomy about the immediate impact of a Brexit vote (though it is still gloomy about 2017). <br />
<br />
As for Labour’s stance on free movement, more former shadow ministers are joining Rachel Reeves in saying curbs are crucial. <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">Jonathan Reynolds today tells HuffPost</a>:”People who have a genuine emotional concern about the scale of immigration want to see that addressed.” Chuka Umunna said yesterday that immigration was the missing issue in his party’s leadership election. One to watch.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>3) A RATIO HORNBLOWER</strong><br />
<br />
It’s not just ‘hard Brexit’ that worries some in the Treasury.  Tory MPs believe the Chancellor has real concerns about some of the horn-blowing rhetoric from No.10 on taking on company ‘fatcats’ and plans to name and shame firms with large inequality ratios on pay.<br />
<br />
As part of her mission to be on the side of the ‘ordinary working class’ voter, May and her team want a US-style annual publication of the ratio “between the CEO’s pay and the average company worker’s pay”.<br />
<br />
But the FT reports that officials have warned the PM that the calculation could produce perverse results where some big banks (like Goldman Sachs) end up looking “fairer” than retailers such as John Lewis/Waitrose, which prides itself on an enlightened pay policy.  Simply because banks have fewer low-paid staff, they come out with a better ratio.<br />
<br />
Downing Street seems undeterred by what it calls ‘anomalies’. But May is famously a Waitrose shopper (and unafraid to say so), and officials are hinting they may reconsider the ‘one size fits all’ approach to how the data is presented.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>BECAUSE YOU’VE READ THIS FAR…</strong><br />
<br />
Watch this pizza delivery guy’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KNMFmT4V_60" target="_hplink">wheelie fail in Clapham</a><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>4) GIANT LEAP FOR MANC KIND</strong><br />
<br />
George Osborne’s shot across Theresa May’s bows over the Northern Powerhouse looks like it may have paid off. Having launched his new think tank to boost his pet project last week (accompanied by a slightly menacing interview on the Today prog) the former Chancellor appears to have got his way.<br />
<br />
<a href="http://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/prime-minister-theresa-may-olympic-11909364" target="_hplink">Writing for the Manchester Evening News</a>, May has lavished praise on the Northern Powerhouse.  Having struggled to even utter the phrase after she entered No.10, the PM uses it no fewer than five times in her short article. May pledged that she “will ensure the whole machinery of government gets behind it.” <br />
<br />
The Sun reports that Osbo has however ducked the chance to put his own political future where his mouth is.  Asked if he would run for the Tory candidacy for Manchester’s Metro Mayor, he replied that he was “flattered by the interest and committed to making the new Greater Manchester mayor a success, but I will do that from the House of Commons, not the town hall.” The fact that the Tories have a snowball’s chance in hell of winning is, of course, a mere detail.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>5) MENTAL WEALTH SPENDING</strong><br />
<br />
Long the ‘cinderella’ of the NHS and care system, mental health has in recent years risen up the political agenda. But according to Luciana Berger, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/government-to-slash-mental-health-funding-again-figures-show_uk_57e29667e4b004d4d8618eb3?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">the Government is still failing to deliver</a>. <br />
<br />
The former shadow health minister has some new figures showing that funding will be cut again in many areas and the postcode lottery will keep on producing losers as well as winners. At least 73 local areas will see their GP mental health budgets slashed in 2016/2017.<br />
<br />
The gap between the smallest and largest spends will also widen: Haringey’s Clinical Commissioning Group (CCG) will put 16 percent of its budget on mental health, for West Hampshire that figure will be 5 percent.<br />
<br />
Jeremy Hunt had promised that CCGs are committed to increasing the proportion of their funding that goes into mental health. But Berger said the commitment had not been met. As an aside, I wonder if she is one of the ex shadow ministers planning a return to the Corbyn frontbench? She worked well with him on mental health, and he’s been a lifelong campaigner on the issue…<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If you’re reading this on the web, sign-up <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/newsletter/uk-politics?pop=nls&nls=uk-politics&ncid=tweetlnkushpmg00000067" target="_hplink">HERE</a> to get the WaughZone delivered to your inbox.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<em>Got something you want to share? Please send any stories/tips/quotes/pix/plugs/gossip to Paul Waugh (paul.waugh@huffingtonpost.com), Ned Simons (ned.simons@huffingtonpost.com), Martha Gill (martha.gill@huffingtonpost.com) and Owen Bennett (owen.bennett@huffingtonpost.com)<em><br />
 ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Brexit economy: post-referendum data defies gloomy UK predictions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:35:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guardian analysis of key economic figures gives rounded assessment three months after the vote</p><p>• Help fund our journalism by becoming a <a href="https://membership.theguardian.com/uk/supporter?INTCMP=gdnwb_copts_editorial_mem_brexitdashboardstoryfooter_footer">Guardian supporter</a></p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/ng-interactive/2016/sep/21/how-has-the-brexit-vote-affected-the-uk-economy-september-verdict">How has the Brexit vote affected the UK economy? September verdict</a> </p><p>Fears that Britain will slide into a post-referendum recession have been allayed after a Guardian analysis showed the latest news on the economy has confounded analysts’ gloomy expectations, with consumer spending strong, unemployment low and the housing market holding steady.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lloyd's Of London rues Brexit vote result]]></title>
            <link>http://news.sky.com/story/lloyds-of-london-sees-europe-trading-threat-after-eu-vote-10588019</link>
            <guid>http://news.sky.com/story/lloyds-of-london-sees-europe-trading-threat-after-eu-vote-10588019</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Lloyd's of London has described the UK's vote to leave the EU as a "major issue for us", saying it is working on a plan to ensure it can still trade across Europe.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour Must Support The End Of Free Movement To Be Credible Again, Says Remain-Backing MP]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_n_12131110.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_n_12131110.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:17:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<p>Labour needs to stop &ldquo;sulking&rdquo; about the EU referendum result and vow to end freedom of movement, one of the party&rsquo;s northern heartland MPs has warned.</p><br />
<p>Jonathan Reynolds, who has represented the Greater Manchester seat of Stalybridge and Hyde since 2010, believes keeping the EU&rsquo;s free movement rules in exchange for Single Market membership would be &ldquo;unacceptable&rdquo; to millions of Labour voters.</p><br />
<p>The Remain-campaigning Reynolds told HuffPost UK that people&rsquo;s &ldquo;genuine emotional concerns&rdquo; about uncontrolled immigration cannot be dealt with just by pointing to reports and statistics which talk up the economic benefit of freedom of movement.</p><br />
<p>In a dig at colleagues such as Chuka Umunna who are calling for the Government to try and negotiate a compromise over freedom of movement in a Brexit deal, Reynolds said a &ldquo;tweak&rdquo; to the status quo &ldquo;would not wash with people.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>He also argued campaigning for a second referendum &ldquo;would be seen as an insult to a lot of voters&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>His comments come days after three other high profile Labour MPs &ndash; <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-mp-freedom-of-movement-brexit_uk_57dfb7eae4b0d584f7f1b89b">Rachel Reeves, Emma Reynolds and Steven Kinnock &ndash; all called for an end to free movement to the UK.</a></p><br />
<p>Speaking to the HuffPost UK, Reynolds said: &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s a credible position to take that we can continue with freedom of movement or have a second referendum on this.</p><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;We can&rsquo;t be sitting around sulking about the result of the referendum. That&rsquo;s not going to be good for Labour; that&rsquo;s not going to be good for the country.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>With huge parts of traditional Labour voting areas backing Leave, including Reynolds&rsquo; own constituency, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/owen-bennett/labour-party-brexit_b_11916786.html">the party is struggling to put together a coherent post-Brexit plan.</a></p><br />
<p>Tottenham MP David Lammy believes Parliament should block the decision, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/owen-smith-euro-schengen-eu-referendum_uk_57d51cd4e4b0ac5a02de76dc">while leadership contender Owen Smith is calling for a second referendum once the Brexit deal is known.</a></p><br />
<p>Reynolds is clear that freedom of movement has to go, even if that means quitting the Single Market.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;Anyone who spent a lot of time talking to people in the EU referendum, particularly in a constituency like mine, cannot fail to appreciate how strongly people feel about freedom of movement and why, whatever the economic advantages and disadvantages of leaving the Single Market, they are frankly not willing to even engage in that conversation unless there is a recognition of their concerns about that.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And that&rsquo;s not always about personal impact on wages or personal impact on their community it is about a concern about what is, frankly, a record level of immigration to the UK and concerns about our ability as a nation to absorb that scale of immigration.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And yes there was in the referendum a considerable amount of racism and clearly an increase in hate crimes and that is unacceptable but we cannot say that everyone who has a concern about immigration was behaving in that way because that is simply not true.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;I cannot accept a view I sometimes hear from other politicians and people in the media this idea that everyone who has a concern about immigration in my constituency is somehow a person with racist tendencies or leanings and I know that from my constituency and I think we have to acknowledge that.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><br />
<br />
<p>Reynolds claimed Labour politicians had in the past been too fearful to discuss freedom of movement reform out of fear of &ldquo;giving an inch to the kind of racial dog-whistling politics which is a component of Ukip.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;That has led us to just dismiss genuine concerns, and also we&rsquo;ve tried to win arguments on immigration by asking people to look at the data on the impact on wages or to give them statistical information from the census and that&rsquo;s not how you win an argument on it.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;People who have a genuine emotional concern about the scale of immigration want to see that addressed.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>Despite campaigning for Remain, Reynolds now believes that Brexit will allow the UK to stop &ldquo;a number of things we&rsquo;ve gone along with as we were part of the EU which frankly we&rsquo;re not that keen on&rdquo; - citing agricultural subsidies as one example.</p><br />
<p>Reynolds is keen to emphasis that an end to freedom of movement does not mean an end to immigration, but believes the country needs to address the reason why migration is so high.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;It will take time to address the skills shortages and to get the skill system aligned to reduce that level of immigration, but it has to be possible.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>A spokesman for Jeremy Corbyn said the Labour leader believes that &ldquo;if freedom of movement means the freedom to exploit cheap labour in a race to the bottom, it will never be accepted in any future relationship with Europe.&rdquo;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/owen-bennett/labour-party-brexit_b_11916786.html" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/dIFlPu" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
     <br />
 ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May more trusted than Corbyn on Britain's key issues, poll finds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protecting NHS, reducing immigration and Brexit trade deals emerge as voter priorities in survey and PM wins on all three</p><p>Theresa May is more trusted than Jeremy Corbyn to tackle the most urgent problems in post-Brexit Britain, including safeguarding the NHS, according to a new poll seen exclusively by the Guardian.</p><p>Asked what politicians’ priorities should be, the top three choices in the Britain Thinks poll were safeguarding the health service, significantly reducing immigration and striking new trade deals as Britain leaves the European Union.<br></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Minister says boss Boris Johnson never wanted Brexit and only backed Leave to become Tories' 'heir apparent']]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 23:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In a BBC documentary to be broadcast this week, the Foreign Office Minister claims the now Foreign Secretary wanted Brexit to lose]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FA: Brexit will not derail plans to host final stages of Euro 2020 or 2028 bid]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 20:23:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[• FA’s Martin Glenn says vote to leave EU will not affect hosting of 2020 games<br />• Chairman Greg Clarke says FA is reaching out to friends in Uefa over 2028 bid<p>The Football Association has insisted Brexit will not derail its plans to hold the final stages of Euro 2020 at Wembley, hoping it will act as precursor to an England bid to host the 2028 European Championship.</p><p>Since the FA won the right to stage the 2020 semi-finals and final at Wembley as one of 12 venues for the tournament, which will be scattered across Europe under a plan drawn up by the former Uefa president Michel Platini, the UK has voted to leave the European Union.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's next for Apple's €13bn tax battle?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:50:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Margrethe Vestager is on a US charm offensive, making the case about recovering alleged unpaid taxes – but she has been met with more offense than charm</p><p>In the wake of last month’s controversial decision by the European Commission to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/aug/30/apple-pay-back-taxes-eu-ruling-ireland-state-aid">seek “recovery of illegal state aid” for alleged unpaid taxes in Ireland</a> from Apple of up to €13bn – plus interest – the European competition commissioner, Margrethe Vestager, went to the United States this week on a “charm offensive” to make her case to government officials, lawmakers and trade officials.</p><p>Vestager met with US treasury secretary Jacob Lew, had a closed-door session with members of the US Senate finance committee, and spoke at the Global Antitrust Enforcement Symposium at Georgetown University, where she gave a vigorous defense of the EC’s decision.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With a Brexiteer in charge, the UK's ghastly, hypocritical, wasteful aid policy might change. And I say that as a Remainer]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Labour Leadership Election Result Will Follow These 8 Ridiculous Moments]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/the-labour-leadership-election-result-will-follow-these-8-ridiculous-moments_n_12121724.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/the-labour-leadership-election-result-will-follow-these-8-ridiculous-moments_n_12121724.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 17:41:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p>Today, as ballots closed for the Labour leadership election, voters got a chance to sit back and reflect on the latest bizarre instalment of &lsquo;<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/politics">Politics 2016</a>&rsquo;.</p><br />
<p>As if <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/eu-referendum">Brexit</a> and a <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/theresa-may">new prime minister</a> weren&rsquo;t enough for the country to contend with, Her Majesty&rsquo;s Official Opposition has had a tough and turbulent time navigating court cases, expelling tens of thousands of members and witnessing open civil war among its MPs.</p><br />
<p>Below, we&rsquo;ve detailed the highlights of what must be one of the busiest 12-week periods in Labour&rsquo;s history - for better or worse.</p><br />
<h3>1.&nbsp;Shadow cabinet shambles</h3><br />
<p>It all began with Labour MPs&rsquo; mass resignation from the shadow cabinet, precipitated by then-shadow foreign secretary <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-sacks-hilary-benn-as-shadow-foreign-secretary-over-attempted-leadership-coup_uk_576f20b0e4b0d2571149c098">Hilary Benn&rsquo;s firing</a>.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">MPs trying to work in parliament tomorrow <a href="https://t.co/6uqlfMP8Zc">pic.twitter.com/6uqlfMP8Zc</a></p>&mdash; Mollie Goodfellow (@hansmollman) <a href="https://twitter.com/hansmollman/status/747168831634800640">June 26, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>21 MPs resigned across three days, leaving Jeremy Corbyn to try to rebuild his team and plugging portfolio with the minority of those who backed him.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>The leader even got tackled by David Cameron, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/david-cameron-jokes-newly-elected-labour-mp-will-probably-get-shadow-cabinet-job_uk_577139a4e4b0d257114a174e">who said of a new Labour MP elected in June&rsquo;s by-election</a>: &ldquo;I think I&rsquo;d advise her to keep her mobile phone on, I think she might be in the shadow cabinet by the end of the day.&rdquo;</p><br />
<h3>2.&nbsp;Media mix-up</h3><br />
<p>With the new shadow cabinet firmly in place, apart from a minor blip involving another resignation, Corbyn decided to invite the media in to film them all getting stuck in.</p><br />
<p>But it wasn&rsquo;t until the television cameras all crammed into the room to record their every word that he turned against this idea, uttering the now immortal words...</p><br />
<br />
<p>It wasn&rsquo;t long before camera crews were ordered out of the room and the MPs positioned around Corbyn, including deputy Labour leader Tom Watson, were quite literally reshuffled and replaced.&nbsp;</p><br />
<h3>3. Court kerfuffles</h3><br />
<p>Things only got worse when law suit after law suit dragged Labour through the courts. First it was a millionaire donor challenging Corbyn&rsquo;s right to automatically appear on the leadership ballot paper, then it was members challenging their exclusion from the election, before the High Court got involved and gave the all-clear to wiping 130,000 from Labour&rsquo;s selectorate.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Stat from latest Conservative fundraising email: Labour have had more High Court battles than leadership hustings this summer.</p>&mdash; Stephen Bush (@stephenkb) <a href="https://twitter.com/stephenkb/status/762680009786023936">August 8, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Senior judges spent days hearing arguments from the Labour party and Labour members fighting against one another.&nbsp;</p><br />
<h3>4. &lsquo;Fucking useless&rsquo;</h3><br />
<p>Next followed an outburst by Corbyn&rsquo;s right-hand-man and shadow chancellor, John McDonnell, who <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/john-mcdonnell-insists-calling-labour-mps-fing-useless-was-a-joke_uk_5785f4e4e4b08078d6e76c91">let slip</a> that he believed those &ldquo;plotting&rdquo; to oust their leader were &ldquo;fucking useless&rdquo;.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">John &quot;the plotters are fucking useless&quot; McDonnell says &quot;abuse is just not acceptable in our political system&quot;.</p>&mdash; Kevin Schofield (@PolhomeEditor) <a href="https://twitter.com/PolhomeEditor/status/756470146840100864">July 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>&ldquo;It was a stand up comedy event. I know I promised Jeremy Corbyn I wouldn&rsquo;t do any more jokes - I broke my promise to him,&rdquo; he told the BBC.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m an ordinary bloke. I used some bad language.&nbsp;If my mother was still alive today she&rsquo;d be coming down and telling me she was going to wash my mouth out with soap.&nbsp;</p><br />
</div><br />
<h3>5. Fathers For Justice</h3><br />
<p>Next in the bizarre series of events, Corbyn himself became the target of protest - as two &lsquo;Fathers For Justice&rsquo; campaigners stormed and occupied his roof.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>Activists Bobby Smith and Martin Matthews scaled the Islington MP&rsquo;s home to protest his failing to engage with them over access rights for dads.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Corbyn now realising how annoying people who refuse to step down can be. <a href="https://t.co/bXLKUT8fXX">https://t.co/bXLKUT8fXX</a></p>&mdash; Asa Bennett (@asabenn) <a href="https://twitter.com/asabenn/status/761529982925598720">August 5, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>They came down six hours later, saying:&nbsp;&ldquo;Point made.&nbsp;Thank you for all the support.&rdquo;</p><br />
<h3>6. Traingate</h3><br />
<p>Perhaps the strangest and most unlikely of scandals to rock Westminster came when Richard Branson personally intervened to censure Corbyn, releasing CCTV images of the Labour leader ignoring free seats as he walked through a train he claimed was &ldquo;ram-packed&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>Leaving the Liberal Democrats&rsquo; press office <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/the-lib-dem-press-office_uk_57e25325e4b004d4d8613853?utm_hp_ref=uk">to do as it so often does</a> and use the subject to mock its political opponents with a cutting 404 page.&nbsp;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It isn't a scandal until the LibDems make a vaguely amusing 404 page about it <a href="https://t.co/wYChV0CK6R">pic.twitter.com/wYChV0CK6R</a></p>&mdash; Jack Tindale (@JackTindale) <a href="https://twitter.com/JackTindale/status/768138302780235776">August 23, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>To remind yourself of just how many times Corbyn changed the story behind how he came to be sitting on the floor of a Virgin service filming, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-train-explanation-change_uk_57bd97afe4b0f78b2b4c727a">check out our timeline</a>.</p><br />
<h3>7.&nbsp;Smith&rsquo;s schlong comment</h3><br />
<p>Corbyn&rsquo;s leadership contender Owen Smith gave quite the spate of &ldquo;colourful&rdquo; comments this summer, many of which were labelled sexist.</p><br />
<p>But that reached a peak when Smith was forced to deny claims he had made a joke about his &ldquo;29-inch penis&rdquo; at a campaign rally.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I was going to ask why people are talking about Owen Smith's penis but I don't think I actually want to know</p>&mdash; Abi Wilkinson (@AbiWilks) <a href="https://twitter.com/AbiWilks/status/770069144528101376">August 29, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>His campaign spokesperson told The Huffington Post UK Smith had been making a &ldquo;self-depreciating joke about his height&rdquo;, a claim that failed to win over his detractors.&nbsp;</p><h3>8.&nbsp;1980s throwback</h3><br />
<p>Then, in a gift to political satirists across the country, Corbyn announced a campaign event at which he would <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/mick-hucknalls-jeremy-corbyn-ub40-joke-is-pretty-brutal-but-quite-funny_uk_57ce9801e4b085cf1ecf70ce">officially be endorsed by UB40</a>.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>It prompted much commentary, and even this comment from Simply Red&rsquo;s Mick Hucknall.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Jeremy Corbyn has much in common with UB40. They are currently as divided as his Labour Party.</p>&mdash; Mick Hucknall (@mjhucknall) <a href="https://twitter.com/mjhucknall/status/773086294901686276">September 6, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>The other UB40 band (those who split but insisted they had the rights to the name) were even tracked down and asked for their feelings on Corbyn.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;Ali, Astro &amp; Mickey have always been great supporters of the Labour Party, and they look forward to the new leader taking the Labour party back into government at the earliest opportunity,&rdquo; <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/ub40-shared-feelings-jeremy-corbyns-8780397" target="_blank">a spokesperson told the Mirror</a>.</p><br />
<h3>NOW READ:</h3><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/dan-jarvis-jeremy-corbyn-labour-leadership-election-shadow-cabinet_uk_57dbb59fe4b0d584f7f09d38" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/zpgpdx" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ryder Cup 2016: Tiger Woods may have adverse influence, claims Westwood]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 16:49:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[• Westwood: ‘He could have an adverse effect in the USA team room’<br />• Ryder Cup veteran also queries ‘non-selection’ of Bubba Watson<p>The first blow of the phoney war which always precedes a Ryder Cup has been landed by Lee Westwood, who has pointed towards the potentially “adverse” influence of Tiger Woods as a vice-captain of the USA.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/paul-casey-fedex-cup-finale-european-tour-ryder-cup">Paul Casey’s FedEx finale may spring change in Europe’s qualification rules</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit: UK economy faces uncertain future after shock referendum result, say two independent reports]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-economy-reports-future-uncertain-a7321071.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-economy-reports-future-uncertain-a7321071.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Expert forecasts come in midst of political party conference season - in which country's fortunes outside the EU are the central theme.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Philip Pullman calls for UK to adopt EU plans to protect authors' royalties]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 13:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>His Dark Materials author has appealed for EU directive to be introduced in Britain, to block ‘unfair practices that currently prevent authors making a living’</p><p>His Dark Materials author Philip Pullman has welcomed a “badly need[ed]” new proposal from the European Commission that would protect authors who achieve unexpected success from missing out on royalties.</p><p>Pullman was speaking as president of the Society of Authors, which is pressing the UK government to adopt clauses from the <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/transparency/regdoc/rep/1/2016/EN/1-2016-593-EN-F1-1.PDF">new EU draft directive on the digital single market</a> in order to “avoid unfair practices that currently prevent authors making a living from writing”. The Society highlighted the case of Horrid Henry author Francesca Simon, who has not received any royalties from the television and film adaptations of her <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/childrens-books-site/2016/may/25/francesca-simon-i-love-writing-in-the-first-person">Horrid Henry books</a>, despite the series being broadcast in 44 countries with more than 1.5m DVDs sold.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Voters showing no signs of ‘buyer’s remorse’ over Brexit, top pollster says]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/voters-showing-no-signs-of-buyers-remorse-over-brexit-top-pollst/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/voters-showing-no-signs-of-buyers-remorse-over-brexit-top-pollst/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 12:56:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brits in the EU: are you applying for citizenship?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 08:45:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you live or work in an EU country and are applying for citizenship due to the Brexit vote, we want to hear from you<br></p><p>After Britain’s vote to leave the European Union, British citizens living and working across the EU <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/jun/27/leave-vote-prompts-rush-dual-nationality-eu-passports">have been weighing up their futures</a>.<br></p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/13/zero-chance-eu-citizens-keep-same-rights-post-brexit-expert">Zero chance EU citizens in UK will keep same rights post-Brexit, says expert</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>