<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BriefBot</title>
        <description>Brexit, explained</description>
        <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 16:32:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>BriefBot</title>
            <url>http://example.com/image.png</url>
            <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2016, Explaain</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[British official meets EU ambassadors to discuss Brexit - sources]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/PT_KhGULtBI/uk-britain-eu-meeting-idUKKCN11S1R6</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/PT_KhGULtBI/uk-britain-eu-meeting-idUKKCN11S1R6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:43:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[BRUSSELS (Reuters) - A senior British official made clear during a meeting with ambassadors from European Union countries in London this week that his government wants a signal from the EU about what kind of Brexit deal it is willing to accept before triggering divorce talks, EU sources said.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=PT_KhGULtBI:FUEd0vR58yg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=PT_KhGULtBI:FUEd0vR58yg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=PT_KhGULtBI:FUEd0vR58yg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=PT_KhGULtBI:FUEd0vR58yg:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=PT_KhGULtBI:FUEd0vR58yg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/PT_KhGULtBI" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Chuka Umunna: We Should Be Prepared To Sacrifice Single Market Membership To Axe Freedom Of Movement]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/chuka-umunna-single-market-free-movement-brexit_n_12136040.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/chuka-umunna-single-market-free-movement-brexit_n_12136040.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:07:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p>Chuka Umunna today confirmed he too would sacrifice access to the Single Market if it meant keeping the current freedom of movement rules.</p><br />
<p>The former Shadow Business Secretary, who was one of the most high profile Remain campaigners in the EU referendum, is the latest high-profile Labour figure to definitively call for an end to free movement in any post-Brexit deal.</p><br />
<p>The HuffPost UK today revealed respected <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3?utm_hp_ref=uk">Labour MP Jonathan Reynolds believed freedom of movement has to be axed</a>, as does fellow backbenchers Rachel Reeves, Stephen Kinnock and Emma Reynolds, following June&rsquo;s Brexit vote.</p><br />
<p>Umunna, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/chuka-umunna-launches-vote-leave-watch-to-hold-brexiters-to-account-for-referendum-promises_uk_577fb202e4b07a99eadc755a?utm_hp_ref=chuka-umunna">who is chairman of Vote Leave Watch</a>, is calling on Theresa May to try and strike a Brexit deal which will allow restrictions on free movement and Single Market membership.</p><br />
<p>However, he today told the HuffPost he is clear which goal should take priority.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;If continuation of the free movement we have is the price of Single Market membership then clearly we couldn&rsquo;t remain in the Single Market, but we are not at that point yet.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>Umunna has been actively seeking out alternative immigration arrangements for the UK post-Brexit, and earlier this month <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/uk-immigration-system-australia_uk_57cda444e4b085cf1ecf3237?vbtvwusiiqw7b9">quizzed the Australian High Commissioner to the UK over his country&rsquo;s points-based system.</a></p><br />
<p>In an interview with HuffPost UK this morning, Stalybridge and Hyde MP <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3?utm_hp_ref=uk">Jonathan Reynolds argued that people&rsquo;s &ldquo;genuine emotional concerns&rdquo; </a>about uncontrolled immigration cannot be dealt with just by pointing to reports and statistics which talk up the economic benefit of freedom of movement.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;Anyone who spent a lot of time talking to people in the EU referendum, particularly in a constituency like mine, cannot fail to appreciate how strongly people feel about freedom of movement and why, whatever the economic advantages and disadvantages of leaving the Single Market, they are frankly not willing to even engage in that conversation unless there is a recognition of their concerns about that.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And that&rsquo;s not always about personal impact on wages or personal impact on their community it is about a concern about what is, frankly, a record level of immigration to the UK and concerns about our ability as a nation to absorb that scale of immigration.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And yes there was in the referendum a considerable amount of racism and clearly an increase in hate crimes and that is unacceptable but we cannot say that everyone who has a concern about immigration was behaving in that way because that is simply not true.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;I cannot accept a view I sometimes hear from other politicians and people in the media this idea that everyone who has a concern about immigration in my constituency is somehow a person with racist tendencies or leanings and I know that from my constituency and I think we have to acknowledge that.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/J2GWXr" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
     <br />
 ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson 'Wanted To Lose Brexit Vote To Become Prime Minister', Sir Alan Duncan Claims]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/boris-johnson-wanted-to-lose-brexit-vote-to-become-prime-minister-sir-alan-duncan-claims_n_12137872.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/boris-johnson-wanted-to-lose-brexit-vote-to-become-prime-minister-sir-alan-duncan-claims_n_12137872.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p>A senior Tory minister has claimed <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/boris-johnson" target="_blank">Boris Johnson</a> wanted the Brexit campaign to lose by a small margin so he could take over from David Cameron as prime minister.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>Sir Alan Duncan, formerly a backbench MP but now serving under Johnson in the Foreign Office, said he thought one of the most prominent Leave campaigners wanted to lose for fear of &ldquo;total chaos&rdquo;.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>There was much speculation in the run up to Johnson declaring which side he would fight for in the referendum campaign, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/02/21/boris-johnson-eu-brexit-supports_n_9286400.html">having penned a mixed series of pro- and anti-EU articles</a>.</p><br />
<p>But despite backing Vote Leave, Johnson &ldquo;wished&rdquo; the group to lose so he could become the next prime minister, Sir Alan revealed in a <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/BBC">BBC</a> documentary due to be aired later today.&nbsp;The comments were made on June 22, one day before the vote.</p><br />
<br />
<p>&ldquo;I think it will be 52 Remain and 48 Leave,&rdquo; Sir Alan predicted. &ldquo;I think there are a lot of Leave people who don&rsquo;t believe it, and I&rsquo;ve always thought that Boris&rsquo;s wish was to lose by one so that he could be the heir apparent without having to have all the - you know, shit - of clearing up all the mess, that&rsquo;s always been my view of Boris.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;By championing leave, he can be the great heir apparent of the future, darling of the activists, but actually it would be quite good if he didn&rsquo;t actually win the referendum because there would be total chaos.&rdquo;</p><br />
<br />
<p>Sir Alan also revealed how he thought Boris reacted to the news his campaign had been successful.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;Well I think he&rsquo;s bumbling &lsquo;what do I do now? what do I do now?&rsquo;&rdquo; the Rutland and Melton MP said.</p><br />
<p>The comments are being revealed for the first time in a show title &lsquo;Brexit: A Very British Coup?&rsquo; being aired on BBCT Two at 9pm on Thursday.</p><br />
<p>The Huffington Post UK contacted Johnson&rsquo;s office for comment but did not receive one by the time this story went live.&nbsp;</p><br />
<h3>NOW READ:</h3><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/02/21/boris-johnson-eu-brexit-supports_n_9286400.html" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/cF7u7y" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit: UK must leave EU by early 2019, says European Parliament president Martin Schulz]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-must-leave-eu-by-2019-theresa-may-martin-schulz-european-parliament-president-a7323411.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-must-leave-eu-by-2019-theresa-may-martin-schulz-european-parliament-president-a7323411.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[He has warned that it would not be good for the British to vote in Brussels elections while Brexit talks are on-going]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK economy faces challenging period after Brexit vote, says Bank]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:11:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Financial policy committee warns withdrawal from the EU poses risks but will not be used to reduce regulation of banks</p><p>The vote for Brexit has created a “challenging period of uncertainty and adjustment” Bank of England policymakers have said.</p><p>In a quarterly update on the health of the financial system on Thursday, the Bank’s policy makers also said the UK’s withdrawal from the European Union would not be used as a way to reduce regulation on the banking sector.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson never wanted Brexit and only backed Leave to become 'heir apparent' to Tory throne, says minister]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 23:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In a BBC documentary to be broadcast this week the Foreign Office Minister claims the now Foreign Secretary, who was his boss, wanted Brexit to lose]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK universities draw up plans for EU campuses ahead of Brexit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:25:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Higher education chiefs, struggling with uncertainty and challenges in regulation and funding, look to soften blow of EU exit</p><p>British universities are considering plans to open branches inside the European Union in an effort to soften the blow of Britain’s exit, as they struggle to navigate new challenges in regulation and funding.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-building-schemes-tuition-fees-new-students">Bricks and mortar boards: UK universities embark on major building schemes</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Brexit economy: post-referendum data defies gloomy UK predictions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:35:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guardian analysis of key economic figures gives rounded assessment three months after the vote</p><p>• Help fund our journalism by becoming a <a href="https://membership.theguardian.com/uk/supporter?INTCMP=gdnwb_copts_editorial_mem_brexitdashboardstoryfooter_footer">Guardian supporter</a></p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/ng-interactive/2016/sep/21/how-has-the-brexit-vote-affected-the-uk-economy-september-verdict">How has the Brexit vote affected the UK economy? September verdict</a> </p><p>Fears that Britain will slide into a post-referendum recession have been allayed after a Guardian analysis showed the latest news on the economy has confounded analysts’ gloomy expectations, with consumer spending strong, unemployment low and the housing market holding steady.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[English Devolution Post-Brexit: Cameron Exit Stage Left, Cue Mrs May]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/nikki-knowles/brexit_b_12132854.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/nikki-knowles/brexit_b_12132854.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:55:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Devolution has been one of the core policies of the Conservatives since regaining power in 2010. It will be one of the greatest downward transfers of power from Whitehall to the regions in English constitutional history. However, in light of the other monumental constitutional change that is going to take place, Brexit, not to mention the recent change in administration, where does this leave English devolution?<br />
<br />
It's well known that Theresa May is not as fanatical about Metro Mayors as Osborne or Cameron. It's still uncertain if Mrs May will do away with the position but policy surrounding them is already differing from that of the last administrations. Downing Street have said areas that did not want an elected mayor would not have one forced upon them. However, out of all of the devolution deals struck to date, having a metro mayor has been a requisite. Number 10 press office insists this does not represent a change in policy despite obviously representing one.<br />
<br />
Mrs May's primary concerns regarding English devolution is that she's nervous about giving senior Labour politicians a platform and giving them the opportunity to consolidate and reinforce their fragmenting heartlands. She is also anxious about the local hostility being created over the imposed mayors. <br />
<br />
In spite of allegations, Mrs May is going cold on Metro Mayors, yet she has not abandoned English devolution plans. Gears continue to whir in Parliament to enable mayors to be elected in May 2017 and Mayoral candidates have started to be selected. Furthermore, her cabinet appointments are telling on what her plans for English devolution may be. <br />
<br />
English devolution was at the heart of Greg Clark's agenda whilst he was at the DCLG. In his view, regional devolution was to be a driver for house-building and infrastructure investments; but fundamentally regional growth to balance the UK economy which is dominated by professional services in the south east of the country.  In this aim, he was vehemently supported by Cameron and the treasury. <br />
<br />
In his new role as Secretary of State for BEIS, Clark's drive for decentralisation is set to continue and devolution of economic powers to regions will be a priority for this new department and at the heart of the new government's Industrial Strategy. BEIS has also announced that each of their ministers will have specific areas for which they are responsible as 'local growth champions'.<br />
<br />
Replacing Clark as the new DCLG Secretary of State is Sajid Javid; his priorities for his new role "are to build more homes and ... devolve powers to local areas". Indeed, in his previous role as Secretary of State for Business, Innovation and Skills he was seen as a 'devolution champion', helping to give local authority more power over skills and apprenticeship policy. Seen as a close ally of George Osborne, Javid shares his desire to see powers devolved so he's unlikely to allow devolution policy to falter now.<br />
The role of Minister for the Northern Powerhouse in the Department for Communities and Local Government (DCLG) has been kept and is now held by Andrew Percy. A Yorkshire MP and former local Councillor in Hull, Percy believes in decentralising responsibilities and powers to local government and has already started touring northern cities and regions. <br />
<br />
There's still a question mark over the new Chancellor of the Exchequer's dedication to devolution but if appointments are anything to go by, Jim O'Neill has been appointed Commercial Secretary to the Treasury. O'Neill is a furious advocate for devolution, and a former chair of the Cities Growth Commission. He will be responsible for city devolution, including the Northern Powerhouse and industrial strategy.<br />
<br />
In light of Brexit, it would be easy for English devolution to be forgotten about but at this time, more than ever, English devolution is tremendously important for the UK's future. If Mrs May allows all the surrendered EU powers to reside in Westminster and not the regions, she will oversee the greatest centralisation of power since the Blair era, undoing what the Conservatives have strived to do for the last six years - diminish central government. Before Article 50 is triggered, Mrs May needs to ensure that regional government is equipped in understanding, structure and oversight to take on the extra powers and responsibility that Brexit will bestow. <br />
<br />
While there are strong indicators that English devolution will be at the heart of this Government's growth strategy, a clear commitment needs to be made by Number 10 and 11 that the process of devolution is not being kicked into the long grass and is set to continue. Conflicting messages and vague assurances could undermine the process and at this time of economic and democratic uncertainty, the business community and local government need some guarantee that the Government has an industrial strategy for the whole of the UK and plan for Brexit and beyond. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mary Berry Quitting Bake Off Deemed 'Worse Than Brexit' By Upset Viewers]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/everyone-is-despairing-more-about-mary-berry-quitting-bake-off-than-brexit_n_12133672.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/everyone-is-despairing-more-about-mary-berry-quitting-bake-off-than-brexit_n_12133672.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:59:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><div id="vidible_14745448691" class="vdb_player vdb_56c6056ee4b01f2b7e1b5f3556be00124076e70ee4171d93" vdb_params="m.fwkeyvalues=sponsorship%3DSPONSORSHIP_NAME&amp;m.fwsitesection=composer"></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Today Mary Berry broke the nation&rsquo;s hearts. She announced, defiantly, that she would be <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/mary-berry-great-british-bake-off_uk_57e39e2be4b0e81629a8ff55?6cjqbqn57pj6h6w29">quitting the Great British Bake Off</a>.</p><br />
<p>Hundreds were left distraught when they heard the news, already reeling after presenters <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/13/great-british-bake-off-mel-and-sue_n_11992668.html">Mel and Sue&rsquo;s announcement</a> they would not be appearing in Bake Off series eight, under its new guise on Channel 4.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a> without Mary Berry is like baking without an oven.</p>&mdash; Nick Harvey (@mrnickharvey) <a href="https://twitter.com/mrnickharvey/status/778884388096446464">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Such was the same feeling of despair that Remainers felt waking up on June 24 to discover Britain had voted to <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/EU-referendum">leave the EU</a> that Berry&rsquo;s exit was branded &ldquo;Berryexit&rdquo; by some viewers.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Have sneaking suspicion that <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Berryexit?src=hash">#Berryexit</a> may put trauma of <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Brexit?src=hash">#Brexit</a> into perspective <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a></p>&mdash; Paul Taggart (@PaulAdamTaggart) <a href="https://twitter.com/PaulAdamTaggart/status/778895004131553280">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>But there were other parallels between Berry&rsquo;s departure from the country&rsquo;s favourite cooking show and the high-stakes referendum.</p><br />
<p>Some suggested the fraught discussions at <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/media">Channel 4</a> about how to replace three of Bake Off&rsquo;s four stars mirrored the frantic discussions about how to implement Brexit.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Inside Channel4: &quot;But what does Bake Off mean now?&quot;<br>&quot;Bake Off means Bake Off.&quot;<br>&quot;But what will Bake Off look like?&quot;<br>&quot;Bake Off means Bake Off&quot;</p>&mdash; Jessica Elgot (@jessicaelgot) <a href="https://twitter.com/jessicaelgot/status/778894128952307712">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Others suggested a job-swap between embattled Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn and national treasure Berry.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">What if... what if Jeremy Corbyn were to present Bake-Off and Mary Berry got to be leader of the Labour party?</p>&mdash; Jonn Elledge (@JonnElledge) <a href="https://twitter.com/JonnElledge/status/778892074351529984">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>While there were fears - as pun-ridden as the Bake Off competition itself - that Berry could have accidentally triggered &ldquo;Arctic Roll 50&rdquo;.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">It's fine. Nothing will actually happen until Mary Berry triggers Arctic Roll 50. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Breadxit?src=hash">#Breadxit</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a></p>&mdash; Claire Davies (@cloudavies) <a href="https://twitter.com/cloudavies/status/775438359485349888">September 12, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I think Mary Berry just triggered Arctic Roll 50 <a href="https://t.co/9YINJoE0t6">https://t.co/9YINJoE0t6</a></p>&mdash; Elena Cresci (@elenacresci) <a href="https://twitter.com/elenacresci/status/778885045142577152">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Even in Westminster, there were reports of MPs more interested in Bake Off&rsquo;s crumbling line-up than the day&rsquo;s politics.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Full marks to the person in parliament who just screamed &quot;Mary Berry's staying&quot; so loudly it could be heard at the other end of corridor.</p>&mdash; Jim Waterson (@jimwaterson) <a href="https://twitter.com/jimwaterson/status/778882992739672064">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Leaving an astute Twitter user to suggest Theresa May not use the same negotiators as Channel 4 when it comes to battling out the terms of Brexit.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I know we're short of Brexit negotiators, but lets not employ the person at Channel 4 who masterminded the Love Productions deal. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a></p>&mdash; Lissa Evans (@LissaKEvans) <a href="https://twitter.com/LissaKEvans/status/778893578928025600">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>There was no shortage of people genuinely claiming today&rsquo;s news was &ldquo;worse than Brexit&rdquo;. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s how much us Brits love a soggy bottom.&rdquo; one person lamented.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center" data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/BBCBreaking">@BBCBreaking</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/BBCNews">@BBCNews</a> worse than Brexit</p>&mdash; Tom (@_tom_burke_) <a href="https://twitter.com/_tom_burke_/status/778882802318249984">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Worse than Brexit. <a href="https://t.co/0kepKE8Dgf">https://t.co/0kepKE8Dgf</a></p>&mdash; Peter Evans (@picklepete) <a href="https://twitter.com/picklepete/status/778884464789291008">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is worse than Brexit. In fact, we should call it Berrexit. <a href="https://t.co/nEdSV74kxk">https://t.co/nEdSV74kxk</a></p>&mdash; Georgia ♡ (@giordizzle) <a href="https://twitter.com/giordizzle/status/778883846079123457">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mary leaves, Paul to remain. Probably worse than brexit <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/iceicebaby?src=hash">#iceicebaby</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a></p>&mdash; Raj (@Rajjohal7) <a href="https://twitter.com/Rajjohal7/status/778901515872440325">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mary Berry leaving <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a> is worse than Brexit.</p>&mdash; Natsby (@natthornton) <a href="https://twitter.com/natthornton/status/778892165946769408">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mary Berry leaving <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a> is literally worse than <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Brexit?src=hash">#Brexit</a>, that's how much  us Brits love a soggy bottom.  </p>&mdash; Skye (@FlexinFerg) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlexinFerg/status/778890941625208832">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Mary Berry leaving <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GBBO?src=hash">#GBBO</a> is literally worse than <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Brexit?src=hash">#Brexit</a>, that's how much  us Brits love a soggy bottom.  </p>&mdash; Skye (@FlexinFerg) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlexinFerg/status/778890941625208832">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is worse than brexit <a href="https://t.co/A9c68iHRvX">https://t.co/A9c68iHRvX</a></p>&mdash; Harjot (@24Harj) <a href="https://twitter.com/24Harj/status/778884342621802496">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>As one person eloquently put it:</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">this whole gbbo ordeal is worse than brexit what the fuck has happened this country <a href="https://t.co/FxU4LcGIJt">https://t.co/FxU4LcGIJt</a></p>&mdash; annabel (@wstrspace) <a href="https://twitter.com/wstrspace/status/778894797276839936">September 22, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><center><div class="opinary-widget-wrapper" style="width: 100%; max-width: 1200px; height:100%; margin:0 auto;">  <div class="opinary-widget" style="position:relative; padding-top: 100%;">    <iframe class="opinary-iframe" no-mw-resize src="//compass.pressekompass.net/compasses/huffpostUK/BakeOffChannel4_huffpostUK" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: none;" ></iframe>  </div></div></center></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit, insurance, debt and help to buy]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fears that Britain will slide into a post-referendum recession have been allayed after a <em>Guardian</em>&nbsp;newspaper analysis showed the latest news on the economy has confounded analysts&rsquo; gloomy expectations, with consumer spending strong, unemployment low and the housing market holding steady.</p>
<p>The finding comes as a leading think tank toned down its earlier dire warnings of&nbsp;economic turmoil for the UK and its neighbours in the event of a leave vote.</p>
<p>The Paris-based Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development said prompt action by the Bank of England to cut interest rates had cushioned the blow from June&rsquo;s Brexit vote but it still believes the UK will suffer a sharp slowdown next year amid heightened uncertainty.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the boss of&nbsp;Kier Group,&nbsp;one of the country&rsquo;s biggest construction firms, says the London property market has &lsquo;definitely softened&rsquo; since the Brexit vote.</p>
<p>Haydn Mursell told the <em>BBC</em> that&nbsp;demand around&nbsp;the rest of the country is still&nbsp;good, but the capital had&nbsp;taken most&nbsp;of the impact.&nbsp;Housebuilders and estate agents were already reporting a slowing of London&rsquo;s housing market before the referendum.</p>
<p><strong>Insurance rip-off</strong></p>
<p>Elderly&nbsp;drivers and homeowners are being ripped off by insurance providers catering specifically to over 50s, consumer campaigners have warned, as they are paying up to four times as much for cover offered by regular providers.</p>
<p>A mystery shop by Which? found some year-long policies offered by specialist providers were between &pound;110 and &pound;1,134 more expensive than the best deal given by a normal insurer.</p>
<p><em>The Telegraph</em> reports that, last night, experts said it was &lsquo;unacceptable&rsquo; for trusted brands including Age UK and Saga to overcharge old and vulnerable customers just because were less likely to question the value of deals.</p>
<p>James Daley, director at Fairer Finance, said: &lsquo;These firms should be more careful about claiming they offer good value to over 50s and then in practice offering some of them very bad value.&rsquo;</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft</strong></p>
<p class="story-body__introduction">Microsoft has been criticised over its Windows 10 software by consumer rights group Which?.</p>
<p>The body said it had received hundreds of complaints about the upgrade, including lost files, emails no longer syncing and broken wi-fi and printing.&nbsp;In some cases, it said, users had had to pay for their computer to be repaired.</p>
<p>Microsoft defended its software and highlighted that it provided help online and by phone.</p>
<p>Which? surveyed more than 5,500 of its members in June, and said that 12 per cent of the 2,500 who had upgraded to Windows 10 had later reverted to an earlier version.</p>
<p><strong>Living wage</strong></p>
<p>The national living wage (NLW) falls short of providing a decent standard of income to low-paid staff and will need to increase sharply to offset rising rents and slowing wages growth,&nbsp;<em>The Guardian</em> reports.</p>
<p>After a six-month review, <a class="u-underline" href="http://www.livingwage.org.uk/living-wage-commission" target="_blank" data-link-name="in body link">the Living Wage Commission</a> said it had assessed the &lsquo;best available evidence on living standards&rsquo; and concluded that the &pound;7.20 an hour NLW for the over 25s, introduced in April, was failing to provide the basic needs of low-paid households.</p>
<p><strong>Debt</strong></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Bailiffs, utility companies and local councils who chase struggling parents over unpaid debts may be unwittingly inflicting real damage to children&rsquo;s mental health, The Children&rsquo;s Society has warned.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">A report by the charity, <a href="https://www.childrenssociety.org.uk/breathing-space-embargo" target="_blank"><i>The Damage of Debt</i></a><i>,</i> finds that children in low-income families with multiple debts are at far higher risk of suffering from mental health problems than those in families who owe money to a single type of creditor.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">For families in poverty, the crucial factor is the number of types of debts rather than the total amount owed. The more types of debt the worse a child&rsquo;s mental health is likely to be.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The findings suggest that having to juggle a range of creditors, from utility companies to stores, banks and payday loan companies, all of which may be seeking to claw back debts at the same time, ramps up the pressure on financially stressed households, who may also owe money to friends, family and other members of the community.</p>
<p><strong>Help to Buy</strong></p>
<p>The Bank of England says use of&nbsp;the Help to Buy mortgage guarantee scheme has &lsquo;declined significantly&rsquo; over the past year.</p>
<p>In the first three months of 2016, the scheme made up only 3 per cent of total mortgage lending for house purchases, the Bank&rsquo;s Financial Policy Committee says.</p>
<p>In other housing news, the Council of Mortgage Lenders estimates that gross mortgage lending reached &pound;22.5 billion in August &ndash; 7 per cent higher than July&rsquo;s lending total of &pound;21.1 billion. In addition to the month-on-month rise, lending rose 15 per cent year-on-year, from &pound;19.5 billion in August 2015. This is the highest August figure since 2007 when gross lending reached &pound;33.6 billion.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">&nbsp;<strong>Energy</strong></p>
<p>Angry customers who waited-in for&nbsp;energy supplier&nbsp;E.On&nbsp;are to receive some recompense.</p>
<p>The company has paid &pound;3.1 million after admitting to&nbsp;Ofgem, the&nbsp;energy watchdog,&nbsp;that its agents missed 35,000&nbsp;appointments between 2011 and 2015.&nbsp;E.On came forward to Ofgem and has paid out &pound;1.2 million to householders and &pound;1.9 million to energy charities.</p>
<p>Under Ofgem rules,&nbsp;if an appointment is&nbsp;missed, customers&nbsp;should receive &pound;20 to&nbsp;&pound;22. Because that&nbsp;wasn&rsquo;t paid immediately, those affected have received double.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/">Brexit, insurance, debt and help to buy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Brexit bounce continues – ten forecasters up their predictions for 2016 growth]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:49:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Brexit bounce continues. HM Treasury has today <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/554343/PU797forecast_for_the_uk_economy_sept.pdf" target="_blank">released forecasts</a> of the economists it follows, as it does every month. Last time, there was a flurry of downgrades and forecasts of an immediate recession. Now, these forecasts are being torn up by everyone, including by the FT (although you can bet the FT won&rsquo;t report on the upgrades as eagerly as it did the downgrades).</p>
<p>The average new forecast suggests GDP will grow by 1.8 per cent this year, far better than the 1.5 per cent forecast last month. This back to where the consensus was <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/529303/forecast_for_the_uk_economy_june_2016.pdf">before</a> the Brexit vote. The OECD, which had previously predicted &ldquo;immediate&rdquo; uncertainty after a Brexit vote, has today also upgraded to 1.8pc for this year, saying instead that the pain will be felt next year (it predicts 0.9pc growth).</p>
<p>When you take a look at the forecasts made by city heavyweights, the signs are also encouraging. Bank of America Merrill Lynch, Barclays Capital, JP Morgan, Citigroup and Morgan Stanley are amongst ten forecasters to hike their GDP growth predictions from two months ago. Of these, three &ndash; Pantheon, Bank of America and Barclays &ndash; have boosted their forecasts by a healthy 0.4 points. And Daiwa Capital Markets makes the biggest revision: shifting its July prediction of 1.4 per cent GDP growth up to 1.9 per cent. Admittedly, not everyone is as optimistic: three of the city forecasts keep their predictions the same, whilst two firms &ndash; Capital Economics and Scotiabank &ndash; have revised their GDP bets downwards by 0.1 per cent. But the panic that seemed to grip the financial experts in the run-up to the referendum, and in the immediate aftermath, seems to be subsiding.</p>
<p>The Office of National Statistics, in its snapshot of the health of the UK economy which is also published today, agrees with that assessment. In the words of their chief economist Joe Grice:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;As the available information grows, the referendum result appears, so far, not to have had a major effect on the UK economy. So it hasn&rsquo;t fallen at the first fence but longer-term effects remain to be seen. The index of services published soon and the preliminary estimate of third quarter GDP, published at the end of October will add significantly to the evidence.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>This sounds as if Q3 growth &ndash; July, August and September &ndash; is shaping up rather nicely. The ONS adds that sterling slump (badly needed for a country with a trade deficit as large as Britain&rsquo;s) has not jacked up prices in the way that many had feared. Nor has George Osborne&rsquo;s suggestion of an 18 per cent <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/may/20/eu-referendum-george-osborne-house-prices-brexit">house price crash</a> materialized. At the time, Osborne&rsquo;s allies said he was not exaggerating and that the economic advice he received was far more pessimistic than he let on. If true, this raises serious questions about the quality of economic advice being issued at the Treasury.</p>
<p>The theory was that consumer confidence would collapse, as Britain would panic about Brexit. But <a href="http://www.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/the-brexit-bounce-thats-making-doom-mongers-look-foolish/">as Ross Clark argued in his cover piece recently</a>, why would that be the case? Brexit would only happen if a majority voted for it, and if they did then why would they go on to suffer a crisis of confidence if they got what they wanted?</p>
<p>The ONS today says &lsquo;there are no signs of a sharp collapse in consumer confidence as some early fears had suggested&rsquo; and that there was no indication that &lsquo;referendum fears&rsquo; were biting any sub-sectors in the manufacturing industry. Of course, Brexit hasn&rsquo;t happened yet &ndash; and&nbsp;nor will the turbulence be over for some time. But&nbsp;the wilder forecasts issued by HM Treasury &ndash; and&nbsp;immediate recession, house price crash, half-a-million&nbsp;job losses &ndash; don&rsquo;t seem to be in the pipeline just yet.</p>
<p>Indeed,&nbsp;Britain&rsquo;s healthy employment rate of 74.5 per cent fits, in the ONS&rsquo;s own words, &lsquo;with a picture of broad strength in the UK economy in the run up to and in the period immediately following the EU referendum&rsquo;. Not that you&rsquo;d have known by reading most of the economic and financial commentary at the time. This isn&rsquo;t surprising: economists are not clairvoyants, nor are pundits. None saw the crash coming. But not so long ago, there was a lot of panic about a populist post-fact Britain that didn&rsquo;t believe in experts. The picture now emerging is of a healthy and sceptical Britain that values its experts but knows that, sometimes, they&rsquo;re capable of all being wrong.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/">The Brexit bounce continues &#8211; ten forecasters up their predictions for 2016 growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit U-turns: who is rowing back on their Project Fear warnings?]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:35:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the run-up to the referendum, we were warned Brexit would unleash misery. George Osborne suggested a vote for Brexit would lead to a DIY recession. And numerous business bosses and the great and the good piled in to add their warnings to the doom-mongering. Yet in the weeks since the referendum, their predictions of chaos have not come true. What&rsquo;s more, many of those shouting the loudest about the consequence of Brexit are&nbsp;now furiously rowing back on their warnings. Here, The Spectator compiles the&nbsp;Brexit u-turns and&nbsp;referendum backtracking:</p>
<p>In the aftermath of the vote, many major banks and financial institutions continued to warn that Brexit spelt bad news for the economy. <strong>Credit Suisse</strong> were among them; in a Treasury report in August, they predicted the UK&rsquo;s economy would go into <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/546720/2016_08_forecomp_august_2016.pdf">recession</a> next year. Now, just weeks later, they&rsquo;ve cancelled that forecast to suggest&nbsp;instead that the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ad13cdf6-7428-11e6-bf48-b372cdb1043a">economy would grow</a> by 0.5 per cent next year. <strong>Morgan Stanley</strong> also cancelled their prediction of a 2017 &lsquo;Brecession&rsquo; to&nbsp;offer a similar, more optimistic picture of the UK economic outlook. The investment bank also <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/?_ga=1.192455779.83446721.1455897487">upped its GDP forecast</a> again this month.</p>
<p><strong>London City Airport</strong>&lsquo;s boss Declan Collier <a href="http://www.cityam.com/243707/brexit-would-leave-london-isolated-according-boss-city">warned</a> before Brexit that a vote to &lsquo;Leave&rsquo; would &lsquo;undermine the free flow of trade and travel&rsquo;. Yet just a month after the referendum, things were <a href="http://www.itv.com/news/london/2016-07-27/london-city-airport-gets-344m-expansion-and-a-promise-of-a-boost-to-the-economy/">looking much rosier</a> for the airport following the announcement of a &pound;344m expansion. Collier said the news &lsquo;sent a strong message that London and the UK are very much open for business&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Nissan</strong> is one of the most important foreign investors in the UK, so when&nbsp;the carmaker&rsquo;s boss Carlos&nbsp;Ghosn said that Brexit could cause the company to reconsider its investments in Britain, people sat up and listened. That was in <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-24859486">November 2013</a>, yet after the referendum Ghosn has struck a <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36981182">somewhat more positive note</a> about how he is &lsquo;reasonably optimistic&rsquo; over Brexit, whatever happens.</p>
<p><strong>Donald Tusk</strong> couldn&rsquo;t have been clearer in making his thoughts known about Brexit in the run-up to the referendum. The European Council president said a British exit from the EU <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-eu-referendum-36515680">could</a> trigger &lsquo;the end of Western political civilisation&rsquo;. Yet the day after the vote, he was somewhat more sober-minded, saying that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/live/eu-referendum/donald-tusk/">it was business as usual</a>: &lsquo;What has happened happened, and we have to move on with our regular agenda.&rsquo;</p>
<p><strong>GlaxoSmithKline</strong>&lsquo;s boss made it clear he thought&nbsp;Brexit was bad news for business. Sir Andrew Witty&nbsp;said that it was better for Britain to stay in the EU than &lsquo;trying to plot a new course&rsquo; outside. And he went on to say, <a href="http://www.cityam.com/240597/eu-referendum-now-top-life-science-bosses-warn-of-brexit-risk-including-gsk-astrazeneca-and-pfizer-in-open-later">back in May</a>, that &lsquo;leaving the EU would create uncertainty and potentially add complexity&rsquo;. Just weeks after the referendum, though, GSK announced plans to invest &pound;275m in three of its British plants. And here is Witty speaking about their post-Brexit investment:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;It [the investment] is testament to our skilled UK workforce and the country&rsquo;s leading position in life sciences.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Rob Wainwright, the British head of <strong>Europol</strong>, said in the run-up to the referendum that Brexit &lsquo;would make it harder for Britain to fight terrorism and crime.&rsquo; But in the aftermath of the vote, he struck a <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/07/europol-chief-rows-back-brexit-project-fear-warnings/">more positive note</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;We&rsquo;re dealing very much with a globalised problem that requires close co-operation with our European neighbours, particularly in information sharing. That&rsquo;s going to continue of course, even after the UK leaves the EU.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Siemens</strong>&lsquo;s Chief Executive waited until after the EU referendum to say that Brexit <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36680572">could hit investment</a>.&nbsp;Juergen Maier said the company&rsquo;s short-term investments in Britain were &lsquo;on ice&rsquo;. Yet, just weeks later, it was announced Siemens would continue to pump money into Britain. In an apparent contradiction of the company&rsquo;s&nbsp;earlier warnings, Maier&nbsp;said that whether the UK was in or out of the EU, it <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36771595">remained</a> a &lsquo;good place to do business&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Barack Obama</strong> was undoubtedly one of the highest profile figures from overseas to intervene in the Brexit debate. He famously warned that a Britain outside the EU would find itself &lsquo;at the back of the queue&rsquo; in trade talks with the US. Afterwards, however, the President&rsquo;s spokesman&nbsp;Eric Schultz made it clear that the special relationship &lsquo;had not suffered because of the vote&rsquo;.</p>
<p>As the architect of Project Fear, <strong>George Osborne</strong> was one of the first to backtrack following Brexit. In the lead-up to the vote, the then-Chancellor indicated there would be a recession&nbsp;if Britain voted &lsquo;Leave&rsquo;. But speaking days&nbsp;after the referendum vote emerged, he softened his rhetoric to say the economy would merely undergo an &lsquo;adjustment&rsquo;. And where was his much-touted &rsquo;emergency budget&rsquo;? Osborne wasn&rsquo;t keen to be drawn on that either, and booted the budget football away by saying there would &lsquo;have to be action&rsquo; &ndash; without daring to mention his original plan of action.</p>
<p><strong>Michael Saunders&nbsp;</strong>was all doom and gloom about Brexit when he joined the&nbsp;Monetary Policy Committee earlier this year. Speaking in May, he said privately that a vote to leave the EU could force interest rates up to as much as 3.5 per cent <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/personal-banking/mortgages/brexit-will-force-rates-up-to-35pc-within-18-months-says-newest/">by Christmas</a>. Yet in an interview in September, Saunders changed his tune by suggesting that a <a href="http://www.cityam.com/249761/uk-economy-slow-less-than-expected-after-brexit-vote-says">further cut</a> in interest rates could be on the cards.</p>
<p><em>We&rsquo;ll keep all the backtracking up to date over the weeks and months ahead. If there&rsquo;s a Brexit U-turn that you think should be included, then email tgoodenough@spectator.co.uk</em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/">Brexit U-turns: who is rowing back on their Project Fear warnings?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson 'didn't want Brexit win']]></title>
            <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37439890</link>
            <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37439890</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:00:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Boris Johnson campaigned to leave the EU to become the Conservative "heir apparent" - and did not expect to win, Sir Alan Duncan claimed the day before June's referendum.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foreign Office minister Alan Duncan insults boss Boris Johnson as he claims he never wanted Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/foreign-office-minister-alan-duncan-insults-boss-boris-johnson-a/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/foreign-office-minister-alan-duncan-insults-boss-boris-johnson-a/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermarkets plan to shrink packets and use cheaper ingredients to save money after Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:06:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit is risking student numbers and vital research funding, says head of Oxford University after school is named world's best]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The institution's Vice Chancellor says other universities are already trying to poach her academics]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With a Brexiteer in charge, the UK's ghastly, hypocritical, wasteful aid policy might change. And I say that as a Remainer]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTO says EU failed to rein in Airbus subsidies]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/NbrlO8BkSs4/uk-eu-usa-aircraft-idUKKCN11S1U1</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/NbrlO8BkSs4/uk-eu-usa-aircraft-idUKKCN11S1U1</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 16:13:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[GENEVA (Reuters) - The World Trade Organization said on Thursday the European Union had failed to rein in billions of dollars in subsidies to planemaker Airbus , prompting Washington to call for an immediate halt to support to unwind damage to U.S. jobs.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=NbrlO8BkSs4:tBBcABXsIIg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=NbrlO8BkSs4:tBBcABXsIIg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=NbrlO8BkSs4:tBBcABXsIIg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=NbrlO8BkSs4:tBBcABXsIIg:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=NbrlO8BkSs4:tBBcABXsIIg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/NbrlO8BkSs4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch top Tory insult and do scathing impression of Boris Johnson - who's now his boss]]></title>
            <link>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/watch-top-tory-insult-scathing-8892872</link>
            <guid>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/watch-top-tory-insult-scathing-8892872</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[&#xa; Sir Alan Duncan claims Boris never wanted to win the Brexit vote because then he&#x27;d have to deal with the &quot;s&#x2a;&#x2a;&#x2a;&quot;&#xa; ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seeking to protect NATO, Britain could yet thwart EU defence plans]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/ElD7o3IGm-c/uk-eu-defence-idUKKCN11S21G</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/ElD7o3IGm-c/uk-eu-defence-idUKKCN11S21G</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 16:12:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[BRUSSELS/BERLIN (Reuters) - Britain will resist new European Union defence proposals if it feels they undermine NATO, British officials say, in a warning to France and Germany that London will defend its military interests even as it negotiates to leave the EU bloc.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ElD7o3IGm-c:uCE3DqKecmI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ElD7o3IGm-c:uCE3DqKecmI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=ElD7o3IGm-c:uCE3DqKecmI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ElD7o3IGm-c:uCE3DqKecmI:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=ElD7o3IGm-c:uCE3DqKecmI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/ElD7o3IGm-c" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is Britain In A State Of Hidden Civil War? Time To Face Facts]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/chris-erskine/is-britain-in-a-state-of-_b_12113408.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/chris-erskine/is-britain-in-a-state-of-_b_12113408.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:21:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons.jpg"><img alt="2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons.jpg" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2016-09-21-1474442793-4503815-BrexitImageCreativeCommons-thumb.jpg" width="570" height="398" /></a><br />
<br />
Commentators talk of 'seismic 'shifts in the political landscape, varying states of post-Brexit 'crisis' and hard-to-dispute daily assertions, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2016/sep/21/brexit-care-older-disabled-people-eu-workers-uk" target="_hplink">with supporting evidence</a>, that we live in uncertain and tumultuous times. Yes, agreed, but when are we going to get to the heart of the matter? Does this state of near constant turmoil, brought into sharp relief by the EU Referendum, not turn our suspicions to the theory of a persistent and obvious menace - Britain is in a state of hidden civil war.<br />
<br />
If a civil war isn't fought with the fire of ammunition, can it be cultivated by an untamed media, self-interested legislators and cowardly, unaccountable corporations? What happens if it's a near-undetectable, low hum sounding throughout all of our lives? If we don't notice it, we're agents of it and unable to resist. How do we choose sides? How can we win? Let's start by facing up to it.<br />
<br />
Britain's hidden civil war is a state that was exposed, first via<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2008/dec/28/markets-credit-crunch-banking-2008" target="_hplink"> the financial crisis of 2008</a>, when the tide went out and revealed the vested interests of the dominant and most powerful elements of our society, sustained over the following eight years in the interests of the same, prevailing forces, before turning its latest trick: the campaign to leave or remain in the EU aiming to skewer what remained of cohesive society. <br />
<br />
At first glance, the idea of a civil war within these lands may seem crazy, but just how far-fetched is this in the age of the<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-36138337" target="_hplink"> Hillsborough revelations</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News_International_phone_hacking_scandal" target="_hplink">phone tapping by the media </a>and the <a href="http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/sir-philip-green-issues-grovelling-8798217" target="_hplink">disappearance of thousands of BHS jobs </a>in the name of creating unimaginable individual wealth? We fear terrorism, nuclear disaster and other unlikely, catastrophic events more readily than civil war as our state of conflict is, perhaps, our 'new normal'.<br />
<br />
The signs of militarised violence are replaced with domestic violence and abuse, household debt and <a href="http://pocketmoneyloans.com/" target="_hplink">payday loans</a>, deterioration of the NHS, increases in racial tensions, fragmentation of communities and zero-hours contracts. It is the environment in which 'us versus them' cultures proliferate amongst people without power and privilege, without the means to determine their own laws, leaving the road clear for those that do. <br />
<br />
Just who does really benefit from ideas such as Brexit, austerity and privatisation? These are the questions found at the heart of the work of a number of artists from the UK and around the world that are stepping up to the plate - not just now, but constantly - to examine the constant attacks on people who can't ascend the accepted economic and political systems. Those people might be migrants, the unemployed and, perhaps, the artists themselves.<br />
<br />
An artist and activists role is often to challenge what is true, acquire knowledge of alternatives and, as a result, challenge the norms that become engrained. Newcastle is home to <a href="http://thenewbridgeproject.com/hidden-civil-war-exhibitions/" target="_hplink">Hidden Civil War</a>, a concentrated period of art expression throughout October, inviting artists such as <a href="http://www.spellingmistakescostlives.com/" target="_hplink">Darren Cullen</a> - the originator of the 'pop-up' Pocketmoney Loans for children outlet as well as a series of maimed Action Men toys - and <a href="http://dedomenici.com/" target="_hplink">Richard De Domenici</a>, who held a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2016/jan/19/richard-dedomenici-death-social-housing-camden-peoples-theatre-art-matrix-redux" target="_hplink">funeral cortege for London's social housing provision </a>earlier in the year, to find and reveal evidence of our hidden civil war. <br />
<br />
Asking artists to do it, often in collaboration with communities, means we get to appreciate and celebrate alternative voices and expressions of life with honesty, whilst also disrupting and dis-lodging mainstream forms of knowledge and understanding. Hidden Civil War won't be some 'lefty finger pointing exercise', as the organisers we know that we are truly all in this together, in as much as we are all economic addicts and unwittingly complicit.<br />
<br />
There are no simple solutions to identifying and solving Britain's hidden civil war - we don't know who is fighting or who we should be rooting to win - but that cannot mean simple surrender. Placing art at the heart of our exploration is no mistake, it's vital, but it is not in isolation. Voices and ideas from the areas of food, land, travellers, domestic violence, poverty, asylum and debt are all vital to finding grains of truth that allow us to face up to our Hidden Civil War. To face difficult truths in troubled times, we require deep collaboration, reflection and above all, listening. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lloyd's of London readying EU move plans]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/LmxMF7XS6G4/uk-britain-eu-lloyd-s-of-london-idUKKCN11S106</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/LmxMF7XS6G4/uk-britain-eu-lloyd-s-of-london-idUKKCN11S106</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:31:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[LONDON (Reuters) - The Lloyd's of London insurance market is already working on plans to move some business to the European Union, aiming to be ready for the shift as soon as Britain starts divorce proceedings from the bloc, its chairman said on Thursday.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=LmxMF7XS6G4:VLbOTe5NDtI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=LmxMF7XS6G4:VLbOTe5NDtI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=LmxMF7XS6G4:VLbOTe5NDtI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=LmxMF7XS6G4:VLbOTe5NDtI:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=LmxMF7XS6G4:VLbOTe5NDtI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/LmxMF7XS6G4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swiss climbdown over free movement may deal blow to UK hopes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MPs vote for local preference in job hires but plan does not include fixed limits on EU immigration</p><p>The Swiss parliament has largely caved in to EU intransigence on free movement in a decision that could deal a blow to British government hopes of being able to both control immigration and retain enhanced single market access after Brexit. </p><p>Swiss MPs approved legislation on Wednesday that would promote some local preference in job hires, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/06/swiss-eu-standoff-striking-similarities-uk-predicament">a compromise they hope will allow</a> vital economic relations with the bloc to be preserved following a 2014 referendum vote to cap EU immigration.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bank of England's Forbes sees no case for further rate cut]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/ZL_UUePf-Nc/uk-britain-eu-boe-forbes-idUKKCN11S19H</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/ZL_UUePf-Nc/uk-britain-eu-boe-forbes-idUKKCN11S19H</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:29:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[LONDON (Reuters) - Bank of England policymaker Kristin Forbes said she did not see a case for a further interest rate cut to help Britain's economy after June's vote to leave the European Union, putting her at odds with the majority of her fellow rate-setters.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ZL_UUePf-Nc:1NnvtcfKG_c:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ZL_UUePf-Nc:1NnvtcfKG_c:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=ZL_UUePf-Nc:1NnvtcfKG_c:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=ZL_UUePf-Nc:1NnvtcfKG_c:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=ZL_UUePf-Nc:1NnvtcfKG_c:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/ZL_UUePf-Nc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK manufacturing expands strongly in September - CBI]]></title>
            <link>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/TQj_zCeGa20/uk-britain-industrialoutput-cbi-idUKKCN11S0WU</link>
            <guid>http://feeds.reuters.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~3/TQj_zCeGa20/uk-britain-industrialoutput-cbi-idUKKCN11S0WU</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[LONDON, (Reuters) - - British manufacturing grew strongly in September and orders flowed in at an above-average rate, adding to signs the economy has avoided an immediate hit from June's Brexit vote, an industry survey showed on Thursday.<div class="feedflare"> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:bGT2xqi_r0M:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:bGT2xqi_r0M:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=TQj_zCeGa20:bGT2xqi_r0M:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.reuters.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?a=TQj_zCeGa20:bGT2xqi_r0M:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Reuters/UKTopNews?i=TQj_zCeGa20:bGT2xqi_r0M:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Reuters/UKTopNews/~4/TQj_zCeGa20" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour Must Support The End Of Free Movement To Be Credible Again, Says Remain-Backing MP]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_n_12131110.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_n_12131110.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:17:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<br />
<p>Labour needs to stop &ldquo;sulking&rdquo; about the EU referendum result and vow to end freedom of movement, one of the party&rsquo;s northern heartland MPs has warned.</p><br />
<p>Jonathan Reynolds, who has represented the Greater Manchester seat of Stalybridge and Hyde since 2010, believes keeping the EU&rsquo;s free movement rules in exchange for Single Market membership would be &ldquo;unacceptable&rdquo; to millions of Labour voters.</p><br />
<p>The Remain-campaigning Reynolds told HuffPost UK that people&rsquo;s &ldquo;genuine emotional concerns&rdquo; about uncontrolled immigration cannot be dealt with just by pointing to reports and statistics which talk up the economic benefit of freedom of movement.</p><br />
<p>In a dig at colleagues such as Chuka Umunna who are calling for the Government to try and negotiate a compromise over freedom of movement in a Brexit deal, Reynolds said a &ldquo;tweak&rdquo; to the status quo &ldquo;would not wash with people.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p><strong><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/chuka-umunna-single-market-free-movement-brexit_uk_57e3e201e4b0db20a6e8b057?ofa9iv33bb3zvvx6r">UPDATE:&nbsp;Chuka Umunna: We Should Be Prepared To Sacrifice Single Market Membership To Axe Freedom Of Movement</a></strong></p><br />
<p>He also argued campaigning for a second referendum &ldquo;would be seen as an insult to a lot of voters&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>His comments come days after three other high profile Labour MPs &ndash; <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-mp-freedom-of-movement-brexit_uk_57dfb7eae4b0d584f7f1b89b">Rachel Reeves, Emma Reynolds and Steven Kinnock &ndash; all called for an end to free movement to the UK.</a></p><br />
<p>Speaking to the HuffPost UK, Reynolds said: &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s a credible position to take that we can continue with freedom of movement or have a second referendum on this.</p><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;We can&rsquo;t be sitting around sulking about the result of the referendum. That&rsquo;s not going to be good for Labour; that&rsquo;s not going to be good for the country.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>With huge parts of traditional Labour voting areas backing Leave, including Reynolds&rsquo; own constituency, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/owen-bennett/labour-party-brexit_b_11916786.html">the party is struggling to put together a coherent post-Brexit plan.</a></p><br />
<p>Tottenham MP David Lammy believes Parliament should block the decision, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/owen-smith-euro-schengen-eu-referendum_uk_57d51cd4e4b0ac5a02de76dc">while leadership contender Owen Smith is calling for a second referendum once the Brexit deal is known.</a></p><br />
<p>Reynolds is clear that freedom of movement has to go, even if that means quitting the Single Market.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;Anyone who spent a lot of time talking to people in the EU referendum, particularly in a constituency like mine, cannot fail to appreciate how strongly people feel about freedom of movement and why, whatever the economic advantages and disadvantages of leaving the Single Market, they are frankly not willing to even engage in that conversation unless there is a recognition of their concerns about that.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And that&rsquo;s not always about personal impact on wages or personal impact on their community it is about a concern about what is, frankly, a record level of immigration to the UK and concerns about our ability as a nation to absorb that scale of immigration.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;And yes there was in the referendum a considerable amount of racism and clearly an increase in hate crimes and that is unacceptable but we cannot say that everyone who has a concern about immigration was behaving in that way because that is simply not true.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;I cannot accept a view I sometimes hear from other politicians and people in the media this idea that everyone who has a concern about immigration in my constituency is somehow a person with racist tendencies or leanings and I know that from my constituency and I think we have to acknowledge that.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><br />
<br />
<p>Reynolds claimed Labour politicians had in the past been too fearful to discuss freedom of movement reform out of fear of &ldquo;giving an inch to the kind of racial dog-whistling politics which is a component of Ukip.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;That has led us to just dismiss genuine concerns, and also we&rsquo;ve tried to win arguments on immigration by asking people to look at the data on the impact on wages or to give them statistical information from the census and that&rsquo;s not how you win an argument on it.</p><br />
<p>&ldquo;People who have a genuine emotional concern about the scale of immigration want to see that addressed.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>Despite campaigning for Remain, Reynolds now believes that Brexit will allow the UK to stop &ldquo;a number of things we&rsquo;ve gone along with as we were part of the EU which frankly we&rsquo;re not that keen on&rdquo; - citing agricultural subsidies as one example.</p><br />
<p>Reynolds is keen to emphasis that an end to freedom of movement does not mean an end to immigration, but believes the country needs to address the reason why migration is so high.</p><br />
<p>He said: &ldquo;It will take time to address the skills shortages and to get the skill system aligned to reduce that level of immigration, but it has to be possible.&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>A spokesman for Jeremy Corbyn said the Labour leader believes that &ldquo;if freedom of movement means the freedom to exploit cheap labour in a race to the bottom, it will never be accepted in any future relationship with Europe.&rdquo;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><div class="opinary-widget-wrapper" style="width: 100%; max-width: 1200px; height:100%; margin:0 auto;">  <div class="opinary-widget" style="position:relative; padding-top: 100%;">    <iframe class="opinary-iframe" no-mw-resize src="//compass.pressekompass.net/compasses/huffpostUK/BrexitFreeMovement_huffpostUK" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: none;" ></iframe>  </div></div></div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/owen-bennett/labour-party-brexit_b_11916786.html" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/dIFlPu" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[David Miliband Says Jeremy Corbyn Has Made Labour 'Unelectable']]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/david-miliband-says-jeremy-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable_n_12132344.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/david-miliband-says-jeremy-corbyn-has-made-labour-unelectable_n_12132344.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">David Miliband has claimed the Labour Party has not been further from power since the 1930s as part of a stinging attack on Jeremy Corbyn.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>The one-time favourite for the Labour leadership branded the party &ldquo;unelectable&rdquo; and said Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s &ldquo;half-hearted&rdquo; campaigning for Britain to remain in the European Union was &ldquo;a betrayal of millions of working people&rdquo;.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Meanwhile, Mr Corbyn has insisted his leadership style is unlikely to change should he beat challenger Owen Smith and be named the winner of the contest for the Labour top job on Saturday.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Voting in the leadership battle closed at noon on Wednesday and Mr Corbyn is the overwhelming favourite to take victory.</p><br />
</div><br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">&nbsp;But Mr Miliband, the former foreign secretary, has set out a damning assessment of the incumbent.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Writing in The New Statesman, he said: &ldquo;The main charge against Jeremy Corbyn is not just that his strategy is undesirable because it makes the party unelectable. That is only half the story.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;The real issue is that his strategy makes the party unelectable because it is in many aspects undesirable.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Mr Miliband is particularly critical of Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s &ldquo;egregious&rdquo; stance on foreign policy.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;But the electorate can see through the domestic policy, too,&rdquo; he said.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;Nationalisation cannot be the answer to everything; anti-austerity speeches cannot explain everything; corporate taxation cannot pay for everything.&nbsp;It doesn&rsquo;t add up. It wouldn&rsquo;t work. People are not stupid.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-party-conference-staff-warning-aggressive-violent-conduct_uk_57e2ca0de4b0e81629a8da48" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/ETQtJm" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
     <br />
<p class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text">&nbsp;Mr Miliband said it is &ldquo;disastrous&rdquo; that people are branded &ldquo;closet Tories&rdquo; or &ldquo;Tory Lite&rdquo; if they disagree with Mr Corbyn.</p><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>The president of the International Rescue Committee claimed Labour had slipped from a party fit for government to a &ldquo;secondary influence on national decision making&rdquo;, adding: &ldquo;We have not been further from power since the 1930s.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Meanwhile, Mr Corbyn has promised to work with Mr Smith and other internal critics if he is confirmed as leader on Saturday in order to heal the rift which saw him lose a confidence vote among the parliamentary party by a margin of 172-40.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Mr Smith has said he will not accept a place in Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s shadow cabinet if the current leader retains power.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>In a statement following the close of polls, Mr Corbyn said: &ldquo;As far as I am concerned, the slate will be wiped clean this weekend.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;If I am re-elected leader, I will reach out to and work with all Labour MPs to form a broad and effective opposition to this divisive and floundering Tory government.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>He added: &ldquo;All Labour party members and MPs have a responsibility to work within the democracy of our party and respect the leadership of whoever is elected.&rdquo;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>But Mr Corbyn has set himself against proposals from deputy leader Tom Watson to return to the electoral college system which gave MPs and unions more say over the choice of a leader.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>&ldquo;I think we have to stick with one-member one-vote,&rdquo; he said.</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="content-list-component mt-paragraph text"><br />
<p>Labour&rsquo;s ruling National Executive Committee has put off a decision on MPs&rsquo; demand to be allowed to elect members of Mr Corbyn&rsquo;s shadow cabinet.&nbsp;</p><br />
</div><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><div class="opinary-widget-wrapper" style="width: 100%; max-width: 1200px; height:100%; margin:0 auto;">  <div class="opinary-widget" style="position:relative; padding-top: 100%;">    <iframe class="opinary-iframe" no-mw-resize src="//compass.pressekompass.net/compasses/huffpostUK/CorbynOliveBranch_huffpostUK" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: none;" ></iframe>  </div></div></div></div><br />
     <br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3" data-iframely-url="//dk79lclgtez2i.cloudfront.net/wI8CK3" data-template="inline"></a></div></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thursday September 22 2016]]></title>
            <link>http://www.theweek.co.uk/am/thursday-september-22-2016</link>
            <guid>http://www.theweek.co.uk/am/thursday-september-22-2016</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:37:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="short-teaser"> Company news, markets and financial talking points, available from 8am Monday to Friday</p> <div class="field-collection-container clearfix"><div class="field field-name-field-items field-type-field-collection field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25482" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Next leg of crisis 'to bring greatest debt jubilee'</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> The approaching third leg of the global financial crisis will prompt the greatest ever debt jubilee, says a report from the UN. "Alarm bells have been ringing over the explosion of corporate debt levels in emerging economies, which now exceed $25 trillion. Damaging deflationary spirals cannot be ruled out," it says. The Daily Telegraph says the chapter may prove to be the "definitive crisis of globalised capitalism". </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25483" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Supermarkets 'to shrink sizes rather than raise prices'</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Supermarkets will shrink packet sizes and switch to cheaper ingredients to offset an increase in costs after the Brexit vote, warns the Bank of England, saying food retailers are planning to "re-engineer products" rather than increase prices because of the slide in the pound. Shoppers are "highly price-sensitive" so grocers will use other means to hold prices at pre-referendum levels, it adds. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25484" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Fed policymakers expect rates rise this year</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> The majority of Federal Reserve policymakers expect a hike in US interest rates by the end of the year, minutes from the group's September meeting show. At the gathering, the Fed opted to hold rates between 0.25% and 0.5%, but three officials opposed the decision - the most dissents since December 2014. The Fed said: "The case for an increase in the federal funds rate has strengthened”. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25485" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Apple in talks for F1 team owner McLaren</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Apple is reportedly in talks for a shock £1.5bn deal to buy McLaren Technology Group, the F1 team owner and supercar-maker. A deal would shake up both the technology and motoring industries. The tech giant's interest in McLaren also highlights its ambition to produce an electric and driverless car. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25486" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Brexit: small business confidence at four-year low</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Confidence among small businesses is at a four-year low amid growing anxiety that the economy will weaken dramatically as Britain prepares for Brexit. A survey by the Federation of Small Businesses shows that confidence has fallen for the third consecutive quarter. The lobby group described the study as a wake-up call for politicians to act to "avoid an economic slowdown". </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25487" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Quote of the day… The trouble with low interest rates</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> "As Donald Trump, Bernie Sanders and plenty of others have argued by keeping the interest rates low, the Fed has created a 'false economy' flooding the market with cheap money, via ultra-low interest rates, and driving stock markets to unsustainable highs (emphasis on the unsustainable)." The Guardian’s Jana Kasperkevic on the trouble with US interest rates policy. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full field-collection-view-final"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25488" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">THE NUMBERS... AT 0730 GMT</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> FTSE 100: up +0.06 to 6834.77<br /> Dow Jones: up +0.90 to 18293.70<br /> Dax: up +0.41 to 10436.49<br /> Cac 40: up +0.48 to 4409.55<br /> Nikkei: up +1.91 to 16807.62<br /> Hang Seng: up +0.30 to 23740.96<br /> US dollar: buys €0.89100 and £0.76480<br /> Sterling: buys $1.30750 and €1.16490<br /> Oil: $47.07 up +0.26 </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> </div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour has no option but to hold together | Jonathan Reynolds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[History is littered with examples of failed breakaway parties. A split is out of the question if we are to challenge Conservative hegemony<p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/labour" title="">Labour</a> has a had a torrid time of late. Since last summer the tone of the party’s internal debate has been shrill and bitter. Views have become increasingly polarised, and speculation about a possible split commonplace. We have been likened to a couple who want to divorce but who choose to stay together because we cannot afford to sell the house. Now the polls have closed and, in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/21/corbyn-camp-predicts-comfortable-victory-as-leadership-polls-close" title="">the aftermath of Jeremy Corbyn’s anticipated victory</a> on Saturday, people will almost certainly again raise the question of whether Labour should simply split and let its warring factions walk away from each other.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/20/get-serious-labour-rebels-deal-with-brexit-catastrophe">Get serious, Labour rebels, and deal with the Brexit catastrophe | Polly Toynbee</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortgages, wealth, banking and students]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 08:20:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fixed interest rate of mortgages could fall to less than 1 per cent next year if the Bank of England cuts the base rate again, in a move that would give the housing market a boost, <em>The Guardian</em> reports.</p>
<p>Rates on two-year, fixed-rate mortgages &ndash; already at record lows &ndash; could fall even further because of tough competition among lenders to attract new customers, according to leading City analysts.</p>
<p>Super-cheap home loans could give the market a boost after the vote for Brexit, which forced Threadneedle Street to cut rates to 0.25 per cent&nbsp;in August. This was the first rate-cut for more than seven years and economists expect the Bank to cut the base rate again &ndash; to just 0.1 per cent, possibly in November.</p>
<p>According to analysts at Bernstein, which is based in the City, another rate cut from the Bank of England would drive standard two-year fixed-rate mortgages to 1.1 per cent &ndash; and to less than 1 per cent for customers with a good credit rating.</p>
<p><strong>Housing</strong></p>
<p>The prices of London&rsquo;s most expensive homes will remain depressed until 2019, suffering from&nbsp;a cocktail of stamp duty hikes and post-referendum uncertainty, according to <em>The Telegraph</em>.</p>
<p>The first post-Brexit forecast for the&nbsp;prime central London housing market&nbsp;from Savills suggested there will be a 9 per cent fall in house prices this year, followed by two years of flat prices.&nbsp;It said that in 2019, prices in the capital will start to rise with an increase of 8 per cent.</p>
<p>This is far less downbeat than estimates from&nbsp;Soci&eacute;t&eacute; G&eacute;n&eacute;rale soon after the referendum, which claimed that house prices in&nbsp;the most expensive postcodes of central London could fall by as much as 50 per cent.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth</strong></p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font">British citizens have become the third-richest in the world after average wealth grew last year but it is those at the very top who have benefited most, research claims.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font">On average, Britons had &euro;95,600 (&pound;86,000) in savings, pensions and investments in 2015, after debts had been taken away &ndash; up 0.8 per cent compared to the previous year.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><em>Thisismoney</em> reports that the increase has seen Britain move up from fifth position in 2014 to third last year, when it was second only to Switzerland and USA in the net per-capital wealth league compiled by insurer and asset manager Allianz SE.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Banking</strong></p>
<p>Forty per cent of 55,000 consumers surveyed worldwide report decreased dependence on their traditional bank and increased excitement about alternatives, according to EY <em>2016 Global Consumer Banking Survey.</em></p>
<p>A lack of trust, changing consumer behaviors and expectations set by digital innovators and increased competition from new players are eroding traditional bank relevance. Retail banks scored just 75.1 out of a maximum value of 100 on inaugural EY Bank Relevance Index, which evaluates how customers interact with banks now and how they expect to in the future.</p>
<p><strong>Utility providers</strong></p>
<p>Employees waste an average of &pound;210 and &pound;310 a year on electricity and dual fuel bills respectively because they have not switched providers, according to new data from Mercer Harmonise. The data shows that, on average, employees could reduce their electricity bills by 18 per cent and their gas bills by 22 per cent.</p>
<p>Mercer Harmonise, a service from Mercer, a global consulting&nbsp;company, analysed data from 330 users of its latest service, a price comparison tool&nbsp; which allows employees to find the best provider across a range of services.</p>
<p><strong>Amazon</strong></p>
<p>Amazon&rsquo;s algorithms encourage customers pay more than they need to for popular products and appear to give more prominence to items that benefit the retail giant, according to an <a class="u-underline" href="https://www.propublica.org/article/amazon-says-it-puts-customers-first-but-its-pricing-algorithm-doesnt" target="_blank" data-link-name="in body link">investigation by ProPublica</a>.</p>
<p><em>The Guardian</em> reports that the investigation looked at 250 frequently purchased products over several weeks to see which ones were chosen to appear in the highly-prized &lsquo;buy box&rsquo; that pops up first as a suggested purchase.</p>
<p>Amazon not only sells products directly itself, but also allows other retailers to sell their own products through its platform. This means that the same product &ndash; say a particular set of headphones &ndash; could be offered by dozens of different vendors at different prices and with different shipping costs.</p>
<p><strong>Students</strong></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As more than half a million&nbsp;young people prepare to start university over the next two weeks, instead of enjoying Fresher&rsquo;s Week many will be preparing rent strike action&nbsp;and drawing up strict budget plans to stay in the black.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The latest research from SunLife reveals that despite stereotypes of blowing cash on going out, students actually budget more carefully than their parents and grandparents.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">According to SunLife&rsquo;s Cash Happy report, young people (18-24) are the most likely of all age groups to keep close track of their finances, with 60 per cent saying they formally budget, up from 59 per cent last year.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">In comparison, among their parent&rsquo;s generation and older (over 55s) just over a third formally budget.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/">Mortgages, wealth, banking and students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amber Rudd's offshore business past exposed]]></title>
            <link>http://www.theweek.co.uk/76848/amber-rudds-offshore-business-past-exposed</link>
            <guid>http://www.theweek.co.uk/76848/amber-rudds-offshore-business-past-exposed</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:15:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="primary-image"> <div id="file-100884" class="file file-image file-image-jpeg file-default"> <div class="content"> <img src="http://cdn2.theweek.co.uk/sites/theweek/files/styles/article_main_image/public/2016/09/160922_tax_returns_cameron.jpg?itok=99PwLQQD" alt="" /><div class="field field-name-field-file-credits field-type-text field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">Credits&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even">Jack Taylor/Getty Images</div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div> <p class="short-teaser"> Home Secretary&#039;s role in Bahamas-based companies shines fresh spotlight on politicians&#039; links to tax havens</p> <span class="field field-name-field-article-type field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden"> <span class="field-item even"><a href="/one-minute-read">One-Minute Read</a></span> </span><div class="field field-name-field-published-date field-type-datetime field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><span class="date-display-single">Thursday, September 22, 2016 - 12:15pm</span></div> </div></div><div class="field field-name-field-related-articles field-type-node-reference field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">See related&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"> <div class="node node-article node-promoted even node-inline-teaser"> <h5><span><a href="/panama-papers/71379/panama-papers-david-camerons-tax-returns-show-hypocrisy-is-rife">Panama Papers: David Cameron&#039;s tax returns show hypocrisy is rife</a></span></h5> <div class="content"> </div> </div> </div> </div></div><div class="field field-name-body"> <div class="field-item even"> <div class="field field-name-field-related-articles field-type-node-reference field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">See related&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><a href="/75644/ford-aims-to-sell-first-driverless-car-by-2021">Ford aims to sell first driverless car by 2021</a></div> <div class="field-item odd"><a href="/67776/google-accepts-blame-for-self-driving-car-crash">Google and Fiat-Chrysler team up for self-driving car</a></div> </div></div><p>Five months after the sensational Panama Papers laid bare David Cameron's past involvement in an offshore investment fund, another top Tory has been linked with a tax haven.</p> <p>Home Secretary Amber Rudd has been named as a past director of two companies registered in the Bahamas, which imposes no income, corporate or wealth taxes and was named among 30 "unco-operative tax havens" by the European Union last year.</p> <p>The politician was among the directors of more than 175,000 companies in the Caribbean island named in a cache of 1.3 million files passed to German newspaper Suddeutsche Zeitung and shared with the International Bureau of Investigative Journalists and media partners including <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/bahamas-leaks-reveal-amber-rudd-involvement-offshore-firms">The Guardian</a> and the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37432666">BBC</a>.</p> <p>In its report, the Guardian also revealed that Rudd, in a separate business venture, was a director of Monticello plc, which found itself at the centre of an investigation into alleged "share ramping" that led to a co-director being jailed.</p> <p>Rudd, who supported Cameron when he faced questions over his own offshore dealings, has not commented personally on the reports.</p> <p>A spokesperson said: "It is a matter of public record that Amber had a career in business before entering politics. Monticello was thoroughly investigated 16 years ago and those who acted wrongly were identified and prosecuted."</p> <p>Following the revelations, Green Party speaker on finance Molly Scott Cato MEP said: "[Prime Minister] Theresa May made clear that she would lead a government that works for everyone and would encourage a more ethical approach to business.</p> <p>"In this context it is difficult to see how she can continue to have confidence in Amber Rudd as home secretary."</p> <p>Liberal Democrat leader Tim Farron tweeted Rudd "must provide clarity".</p> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en-gb"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Serious questions for Amber Rudd-she must provide clarity. The public are sick of the idea of politicians tying to dodge the rules they make</p> <p>&mdash; Tim Farron (@timfarron) <a href="https://twitter.com/timfarron/status/778662949401559044">21 September 2016</a></p></blockquote> <p> According to the documents, Rudd was director of the Bahamas-based Advanced Asset Allocation Fund and Advanced Asset Allocation Management between 1998 and 2000. It is not clear if she invested in the firms or if they were used to avoid any tax and there is no suggestion of any wrongdoing.</p> <p>Former associate Alistair Buchanan told the BBC the companies were used to market an investment fund to investors and were registered in the Bahamas purely for administrative purposes. "You could not set up those funds in England at that time, now you can," he said.</p> <p>Rudd's links to Monticello came after it bought out The Zinc Corporation, at which she was a director, in 1999.</p> <p>She resigned her position the following year, five months after trading in Monticello's shares was suspended following co-director Mark O'Hanlon making false statements that massively inflated the company's value.</p> <p>O'Hanlon was eventually convicted of making a false statement and sentenced to 18 months in prison in 2007. He was later jailed again in 2013 on an unrelated fraud charge. </p> </div> </div><div class="field field-name-field-category-secondary field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><a href="/economy">Economy</a></div> </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Nate Silver on his high horse over Trump – again?]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 17:12:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago, the pollster Nate Silver wrote a best-selling book saying (in effect) that political pundits talk&nbsp;rot and that only data-armed policy&nbsp;analysts like him could be relied on to know&nbsp;what was going on. He&rsquo;d based his reputation on the 2012 US election, whose results he predicted. YouGov predicted it too, but Silver has a greater gift for self-publicity.</p>
<p>His theory was later placed in doubt when he failed to predict the result of the UK General Election in a BBC documentary &mdash; which later <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2015/07/revealed-the-documentary-the-bbc-dont-want-you-to-see/" target="_blank">mysteriously disappeared</a>. Despite this, he continues to&nbsp;encourage epigones in Britain, who can (and still do) come out with columns attacking folk&nbsp;for their inferior, prejudice-driven analysis. Today, Nate Silver is&nbsp;at it again &mdash; over Trump:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Never seen otherwise-smart people in so much denial about something as they are about Trump&rsquo;s chances. Same mistake as primaries, Brexit. <a href="https://t.co/qBPRKoZV4R">https://t.co/qBPRKoZV4R</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Nate Silver (@NateSilver538) <a href="https://twitter.com/NateSilver538/status/778563584888627200">September 21, 2016</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Yes, a lot of&nbsp;people feel&nbsp;certain that America just won&rsquo;t choose Trump &ndash; but&nbsp;Mr S&nbsp;suspects that doesn&rsquo;t really make them in &lsquo;denial&rsquo;. Given the recent performance of pollsters, from the Israeli election to Brexit,&nbsp;who&rsquo;s to say that the figures are any more accurate than the instinct of someone with decent judgement?</p>
<p>The idea that pollsters have &lsquo;done a Newton&rsquo; on politics is one of the great comic vanities of our times. The polls are all over the shop:&nbsp;witness last year&rsquo;s general election, and Brexit. If your starting position is that you&rsquo;re simply smarter than anyone else, or can see more clearly due to your superior grasp of data, then you can end up getting egg on your face. &nbsp;A bit like the person who wrote this:-</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9622242" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48.png" alt="Screen Shot 2016-09-21 at 15.21.48" width="629" height="446" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48.png 629w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-300x213.png 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-582x413.png 582w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-146x104.png 146w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px"></p>
<p>Might the media have been justified in freaking out about Donald Trump&rsquo;s polls, even if the numbers&nbsp;were small?
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spec_health_2" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/">Why is Nate Silver on his high horse over Trump &#8211; again?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeremy Corbyn Set To Be Reelected UK Labour Party Leader Despite Bitter Battle With His Own MPs]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/jeremy-corbyn-set-to-be-reelected-uk-labour-party-leader_n_12138176.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/21/jeremy-corbyn-set-to-be-reelected-uk-labour-party-leader_n_12138176.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:35:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<br />
<p>Barring a last minute upset, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/jeremy-corbyn/">Jeremy Corbyn</a> is set to be comfortably reelected leader of the British Labour Party on Saturday. His opponent, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/owen-smith/">Owen Smith</a>, who had the support of most Labour MPs,&nbsp;never had much chance of winning.</p><br />
<p>For Corbyn&rsquo;s supporters, the grassroots Labour members who gave him a shock landslide victory when he was first elected leader in 2015, he is a breath of fresh air who has returned the party to its leftwing roots after years of &ldquo;Blairite&rdquo; centrism and compromises with the right.</p><br />
<p>But for the overwhelming majority of Labour MPs, in the words of former Labour foreign secretary David Miliband, Corbyn is not only &ldquo;<a href="http://www.newstatesman.com/politics/uk/2016/09/new-times-david-miliband-why-left-needs-move-forward-not-back" target="_blank">unelectable</a>&rdquo;, his policy platform is &ldquo;undesirable&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>Labour is arguably now two parties. One in parliament. And one in the rest of the country.</p><br />
<p>In expectation of victory, Corbyn has said he wants to &ldquo;wipe the slate clean&rdquo; and is encouraging the MPs who quit his top team en masse, the shadow cabinet,&nbsp;to return to the fold. The Labour leader has offered a public olive branch - he is growing an actual olive tree on the balcony of his parliamentary office - to his critics.</p><br />
<p>But following a bitter leadership campaign plagued by Twitter trolling, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/jul/12/angela-eagles-constituency-office-vandalised-after-leadership-bid-launch" target="_blank">bricks</a> through windows and allegations of sexism and <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-has-made-labour-unsafe-for-jews-says-mp-ruth-smeeth_uk_57751e83e4b0d18f7514b2f4">anti-Semitism</a> -&nbsp;unity will be hard to achieve. The distrust runs deep. Labour MP Peter Kyle, who has been targeted by supporters of Corbyn for what they see as disloyalty, said &ldquo;Jeremy is the first person I have ever come across who uses an olive branch as a weapon to beat people with&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>In a sign of the deep split in Labour, party staff have been issued an unprecedented warning they may face &ldquo;aggressive and potentially violent&rdquo; situations at the annual conference in Liverpool, which begins this weekend.</p><br />
<p>With Labour at war, Prime Minister <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/theresa-may/">Theresa May</a>&rsquo;s new post-<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/news/eu-referendum/">Brexit</a> Conservative government, which has a narrow majority in parliament, is left to its own devices. And even some Tory MPs are worried. Former minister Anna Soubry has warned &ldquo;<span class="s1">as a democracy, we need a good strong Opposition who are credible, who test government and hold them to account&rdquo;.</span></p><br />
<br />
<h3>Why they hate Corbyn</h3><br />
<p>The Labour leadership battle was triggered earlier this summer following the Brexit vote, when 80% of Labour&rsquo;s 230 MPs passed a vote of no confidence in Corbyn. Smith, who served as work and pensions spokesman on Corbyn&rsquo;s frontbench, was the sacrificial lamb thrown into the contest at a time MPs feared that May, who took over from David Cameron in July, would force a snap general election.</p><br />
<p>For those Labour MPs, 67-year-old Corbyn is too leftwing and too incompetent to win power for the party. In their eyes, he has underperformed even by the low standards they set for him. His poll numbers with the British public at large are bad. A <a href="https://yougov.co.uk/news/2016/09/15/voting-intention-conservatives-38-labour-31/" target="_blank">YouGov survey</a> this month showed voters believed May made a better PM than Corbyn would by a margin of 50% to 18%. And in local elections, Labour&rsquo;s recent performance has been, according to election expert professor Tony Travers, &ldquo;abysmal&rdquo;.&nbsp;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><div><div style="left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 0px; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.2493%;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wXFG14qdIZ4?wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=0&amp;enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" style="top: 0px; left: 0px; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;"></iframe></div></div></div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>The party establishment is almost united in its criticism of Corbyn. Tony Blair, who won three elections for Labour, has repeatedly warned his party against choosing Corbyn. As have previous leaders Gordon Brown, Ed Miliband and Neil Kinnock. Corbyn&rsquo;s victory on Saturday, Lord Kinnock claimed, would doom the party to be out of power for the rest of his lifetime.</p><br />
<p>Ed Balls, the former Labour cabinet minister, warned this week: &ldquo;I<span class="s1">t&rsquo;s not the members of the party who elect the government, it&rsquo;s the voters. I don&rsquo;t remember a time where <a href="https://twitter.com/BBCNewsnight?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor" target="_blank">the Labour Party membership and its views have become so disconnected&nbsp;</a>from where the marginal seat, the swing voter, the centre-left voter, is.&rdquo;</span></p><br />
<p>On policy, Corbyn is at odds with much of his parliamentary party. His is opposed to the renewal of Britain&rsquo;s nuclear weapons and has displayed a lukewarm commitment to the Nato alliance have. The final straw for many MPs, was Corbyn&rsquo;s perceived lack of commitment to keeping the UK in the European Union during the referendum. Labour is a staunchly pro-EU party. However Corbyn voted to leave Europe at the last referendum in 1975 - and many MPs suspect he is not too upset at the Brexit result.</p><br />
<p>And where they agree on policy, Corbyn is accused by many backbenchers of lacking the political ability to do damage to the Tories, under Cameron and now May.&nbsp;His <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-mp-pmqs-fucking-disaster_uk_56f29162e4b08af01be9ec60">performance at prime minister&rsquo;s questions</a> was famously branded a &ldquo;fucking disaster&rdquo;&nbsp;by Labour MP John Woodcock. MPs were up in arms at a behind the scenes <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-staff-upset-at-vice-news-jeremy-corbyn-documentary-over-accusations-of-leaks-to-tories_uk_574edd65e4b026d1d87c4c23">Vice News documentary</a> which revealed Corbyn decided against exploiting the resignation of a Conservative cabinet minister to hammer Cameron over cuts to welfare.&nbsp;</p><br />
<br />
<h3>Why they love Corbyn</h3><br />
<p>However, among an apparent majority of Labour Party members it is a different story. Corbyn&rsquo;s support among the grassroots is is vocal, extremely loyal and with the help of his Momentum campaign group, well organised. Why, they ask, should they listen to Brown, Balls and the Miliband brothers given they lost the 2010 and 2015 general elections.</p><br />
<p>The move against Corbyn, the Islington North MP who has been in parliament for over 30 years,&nbsp;only deepened their fervour. For the &lsquo;Corbynistas&rsquo;,&nbsp;his style, less slick-advertising salesman, more sincere geography teacher, appeals.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>Labour, they argue, lost in 2015 as it offered voters merely austerity-lite rather than a inspirational and substantive progressive alternative to Cameron&rsquo;s public spending cuts. Labour&rsquo;s poll numbers, it is argued, are a fault of the MPs who launched a coup. And they remain unconvinced Smith, despite emphasising his focus on winning an election, would perform any better.</p><br />
<p>Some Corbyn supporters accuse the right of the party of moving against the leader because they fear he <em>could&nbsp;</em>win a general election and implement a leftwing programme, rather than because he can not.</p><br />
<p>A large part of Corbyn&rsquo;s personal brand is his claim to do politics differently. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t do personal abuse,&rdquo; he insists. And frequently requests his supporters follow his lead.&nbsp;John McDonnell however, a close ally of Corbyn who serves as his shadow chancellor, is <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-celebrates-his-victory-over-fing-useless-labour-mps-who-plotted-against-him_uk_578571e7e4b0daae46fa86af?edition=uk&amp;utm_hp_ref=uk">known for putting things more bluntly</a>. The attempt by Labour MPs to topple Corbyn, he famously declared, was &ldquo;fucking useless&rdquo;. And he blames Blair, despite the former prime minister&rsquo;s three election victories, for taking Labour &ldquo;to the edge&rdquo; and ruining public trust in politics with the 2003 Iraq War.&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>In a sign of the deep split in the party between camp Corbyn and Labour HQ, McDonnell publicly accused party officials of&nbsp;&ldquo;rigging&rdquo; the leadership contest in Smith&rsquo;s favour.&nbsp;</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><blockquote class="twitter-video" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">John McDonnell: &quot;As plotters they were fucking useless..&quot; <a href="https://t.co/Kq2yY3qULY">pic.twitter.com/Kq2yY3qULY</a></p>&mdash; Ben Quinn (@BenQuinn75) <a href="https://twitter.com/BenQuinn75/status/752994128976285696">July 12, 2016</a></blockquote><br />
</div></div><br />
     <br />
<p>Corbyn&rsquo;s supporters have also been encouraged by the huge crowds the Labour leader has been able to draw at his campaign rallies. The sight of thousands of people enthusiastically shouting &ldquo;Jez we can&rdquo;, a phrase neatly adopted from President Obama&rsquo;s rally cry, is unusual in British politics. Party membership has surged to over 500,000 - making it the biggest in Europe. Corbyn hopes he can use this as a &ldquo;very strong campaigning basis&rdquo; to win power.</p><br />
<p>During the campaign, Corbyn held 59 rallies, raised over &pound;300,000 in small donations and his team made over 400,000 campaign calls.</p><br />
<p>Parallels have often, and deliberately, been drawn between Corbyn and Bernie Sanders as well as Donald Trump&rsquo;s insurgent campaigns. The &lsquo;Jeremy For Leader&rsquo;&nbsp;team hope to model their general election battle on Sanders&rsquo; digital mobilisation techniques. Corbyn was quick to highlight a message of support he received from Sanders - which <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/bernie-sanders-denies-sending-jeremy-corbyn-a-message-of-support_uk_57bda53ce4b042aee74e4aae">the Senator denies sending</a> - in his fight against Smith.</p><br />
<p>But for Corbyn&rsquo;s detractors, mass rallies do not necessarily translate into electoral success.&nbsp;No one can remember Cameron holding huge rallies. Because they did not happen. Tory party membership is only around 130,000. Yet he won an unexpected general election victory in 2015. Critics are also dismissive of the Sanders&rsquo; comparison,&nbsp;noting for all the noise around the Senator&rsquo;s Democratic primary campaign&nbsp;-&nbsp;he did not win.&nbsp;</p><br />
<h3>What now?</h3><br />
<p>Smith spent much of the campaign warning a Corbyn victory would split the party. He <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/owen-smith-interview-on-the-likelihood-of-a-labour-split-politics-of-the-street-and-a-real-living_uk_57a1e26ce4b0f42daa4ba666">told The Huffington Post a break-up was not just possible, but &ldquo;likely</a>&rdquo;. However that fear appears to have receded, not least as the UK&rsquo;s electoral system punishes smaller parties - and the splitters would find it almost impossible to gain electoral traction.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><br />
<p>And there is also a feeling on the Labour benches that they do not want to give up their party to Corbyn and his allies. As Lord Kinnock told a recent closed door meeting of Labour MPs and peers: &ldquo;There will be no retreat! Dammit, this is our party! I&rsquo;ve been in it for 60 years, I&rsquo;m not leaving it to anybody!&rdquo;</p><br />
<p>Even if an uneasy truce is brokered in parliament between Corbyn and his MPs - with some senior politicians returning to the shadow cabinet - the conflict may continue at a local level.</p><br />
<p>Momentum, the leftwing campaign group that grew out of Corbyn&rsquo;s 2015 leadership challenge, is a source of anger for many MPs. Smith has accused the group, which boasts thousands of members, of treating Labour as a &ldquo;host body&rdquo;&nbsp;for the hard-left as happened in the 1980s. It is a charge Momentum strongly denies.</p><br />
<p>MPs who are seen as disloyal fear deselection - the equivalent of an US Democratic Senator facing a primary challenge from the left. Corbyn, while not publicly encouraging local activists to try and oust sitting MPs, has been accused of tacitly endorsing it by insisting he does not want to &ldquo;interfere&rdquo;.</p><br />
<p>Demands of loyalty from Corbyn&rsquo;s supporters particularly wind-up Labour MPs. Corbyn, as a backbench MP, rebelled against successive Labour leaders over 500 times.</p><br />
<p>In 2015, Corbyn said annual leadership contests could be a good idea. Now leader, he has changed his mind. But another leadership contest, perhaps one every year, before the 2020 general election is entirely possible.</p><br />
<div class="embed-asset embed" data-type="embed-asset" data-provider="Embed" data-title=""><br />
<div class="embed-code"><div id="vidible_14745585291" class="vdb_player vdb_56c6056ee4b01f2b7e1b5f3556be00124076e70ee4171d93" vdb_params="m.fwkeyvalues=sponsorship%3DSPONSORSHIP_NAME&amp;m.fwsitesection=composer"></div><br />
      ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Spectator podcast: The indestructibles]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/283984341&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false" width="100%" height="166" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This weekend, the Labour party will convene in Liverpool for its annual conference. By that point it will have a new leader who, if all current polling is to be believed, will be the same as its old one. Jeremy Corbyn looks set to defy the wishes of his fellow MPs and strengthen his grip on the party. In his cover piece this week, <strong>James Forsyth</strong> looks at the whole of the far left movement, from the leader&rsquo;s office to the grass roots activists, and observes that &lsquo;they are tightening their grip over the party from top to bottom, something the Blairites never did.&rsquo; So, what&rsquo;s next for the Labour party? Does it have a future appealing to moderate social democrats? Or has it truly been lost to the momentum of this new movement? James Forsyth thinks the race is over:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;We await the result on Saturday, I don&rsquo;t think we can say with baited breath because everyone is operating under the assumption that Jeremy Corbyn has won. All of the arguments in the Labour party take it as a given that he has won and Owen Smith&rsquo;s message to his supporters this morning seems like a valedictory message rather than a short of &lsquo;keep your fingers crossed and see you on Saturday&rsquo; message.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Joining us on the podcast,&nbsp;<strong>Nick Cohen</strong> said that:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;What is very depressing for anyone who is opposed to Corbynism is: all the faults that make it so easy for the Conservatives and SNP to attack him, have made it very hard for Labour party lefties who are opposed to Corbyn to unseat him. There was one poll done of Corbyn supporters which said 90% believed a PR agency had organised what they called the &lsquo;coup against Corbyn&rsquo;. This is completely untrue.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is Hong Kong really the future of Britain&rsquo;s Brexit? In his column this week, <strong>James Delingpole</strong> says he&rsquo;s seen the future and it lies in the colony that Britain created when a Scottish colonial administration decided to cut taxes, cut regulation and see Hong Kong go from one of the poorest parts of the world to one of the richest. As James Delingpole observes:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;My step-son was like a lot of middle-class children in this country who were not uber-bright, but are currently being failed in Britain by our culture, which is not as can-do as Hong Kong. I wouldn&rsquo;t say that Hong Kong&rsquo;s success is all to do with the legacy of British administration, because I think you also have to factor in the business acumen of the Hong Kong Chinese, but nevertheless I think we British sowed the seeds for Hong Kong&rsquo;s success.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>But Spectator editor&nbsp;<strong>Fraser Nelson</strong> counters:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;I wish I was as sure as James about this. Of course, you can go to Hong Kong and you can admire it, but you have to work out how much of that Cantonese culture you can import in Britain. And the other thing, which underlines James&rsquo; optimism also underlines my sense right now of foreboding, because there is a certain logic amongst some Brexiteers that, once we pull out of the EU, we can start slashing regulations, start slashing the tax burden, start being a proper free trading country. I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s going to be anything like as easy as that.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, this week&rsquo;s sees the rare occasion that two of the Spectator&rsquo;s longest serving and most respected columnists are under the same roof. Taki&rsquo;s High Life and Jeremy Clarke&rsquo;s Low Life have been magazine favourites for decades, sitting side by side on the page, even as they describe two very different ways of living. I&rsquo;m joined now by <strong>Taki</strong> and <strong>Jeremy Clarke</strong> to answer the age old question: which is better, the high life or the low life? As Taki observes:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;With High Life, I have to keep a certain standard, where Jeremy has nothing to live up to except Jeffrey&nbsp;Bernard. I think both of us have a very good time &ndash; he&rsquo;s younger, so he has more stamina, but I have more experience.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>For the juiciest bits of Jeremy and Taki&rsquo;s conversation, tune into the full podcast!</p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-spectator-podcast/id793236670?mt=2" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft wp-image-9589192 size-full" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-620x210.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="76" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-620x210.jpg 620w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-300x101.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-146x49.jpg 146w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes.jpg 710w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px"></a><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-spectator-podcast" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9589212 size-full" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-620x210.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="76" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-620x210.jpg 620w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-300x101.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-146x49.jpg 146w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher.jpg 710w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px"></a></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9498652" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="244" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1-146x119.jpg 146w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></p>
<p><em>This podcast is sponsored by Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd, who have long supplied wine for The Spectator. If you&rsquo;ve always wanted to start a wine cellar, 2016 could be the perfect time. Whether you are looking to buy for future drinking, for investment or a little of both, Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd&rsquo;s Cellar Plan is designed to suit all tastes and budgets. A&nbsp;personal Account Manager will be on hand to offer advice and assistance, and enable you to benefit from three centuries&rsquo; worth of relationships with the leading wine growers. To find out more about starting a wine cellar with Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd, visit <a href="https://www.bbr.com/cellar-plan" target="_blank">bbr.com/cellarplan</a></em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spec_health_2" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/">The Spectator podcast: The indestructibles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Waugh Zone September 22, 2016]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/the-waugh-zone-september-_29_n_12131428.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2016/09/22/the-waugh-zone-september-_29_n_12131428.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:04:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://big.assets.huffingtonpost.com/the_waugh_zone.jpg" alt=“"><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<em>The five things you need to know on Thursday, September 22, 2016…</em><br />
<br />
<br />
<img alt="jeremy corbyn" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/4687352/thumbs/o-JEREMY-CORBYN-570.jpg?8" /><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>1) WARRING PEACE</strong><br />
<br />
After months of bitter infighting, the Labour leadership election ballot closed at midday yesterday. But is the war really over? That’s upto Jeremy Corbyn as he and his team meet Tom Watson, Rosie Winterton, PLP chair John Cryer to try to hammer out a deal over Shadow Cabinet elections.<br />
<br />
Jezza declared in his close-of-poll statement (and on the BBC too, so it was no slip of the tongue) that he wanted to ‘wipe the slate clean’ for all those former frontbenchers who had criticised him and backed Owen Smith. It proved that the ‘conciliators’ around the leader are playing to his natural instinct to avoid conflict, but there are some hardliners who still want him to ram his new mandate down the PLP’s throat.<br />
<br />
In his BBC interview, Corbyn showed Laura Kuenssberg his olive tree from which he’s offering his olive branches to MPs. But <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-purge-costs-party-majority-on-bristol-city-council_uk_57e13713e4b05d791371487b" target="_hplink">as HuffPost revealed this week</a>, the tree was itself given to him by a Labour councillor - who has been suspended for suggesting deselection of MPs. <br />
<br />
And on avoiding conflict more broadly, Corbyn underlined his preference for jaw-jaw to war-war in his Ken Loach interview, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/jeremy-corbyn-minister-for-peace-diasarmament-nuclear-non-proliferation_uk_57e29fc9e4b0e81629a8ab13?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">revealing his plan for a new Minister for Peace and a Minister for Disarmament</a> (full marks to the Telegraph’s Asa Bennett for spotting it at the end of the hour-long documentary). If he’d called it a ‘Minister for Peacekeeping’, that may have pre-empted the ridicule that followed online. Then again, it may not. And as a keen reader of novels, did Corbyn have any idea that 1984 included a ‘Ministry of Peace’?<br />
<br />
Ahead of the Liverpool conference, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-party-conference-staff-warning-aggressive-violent-conduct_uk_57e2ca0de4b0e81629a8da48?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">we reveal that party staff have been issued with an unprecedented advice note</a> on how to respond to threats of “aggression and potential violence” from activists.  Moreover, amid fears of a ‘clear out’ of alleged ‘moderates’ at HQ, staff weren’t exactly reassured when Corbyn wrote to them saying “at this stage” no “compulsory” redundancies were planned in the party.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>2) BONUS OF PROOF</strong><br />
<br />
Andrew Lansley is disliked on the Left for his NHS reforms and on the Right for his avid Remainer views. Now the former Health Secretary has combined his twin interests by calling for a £5bn-year ‘Brexit Bonus’ for the NHS.<br />
<br />
In his NHS Providers annual lecture, Lord (yes, he’s a peer don’t forget) Lansley tried to call the bluff of the Leavers by saying they’d promised extra cash post-Brexit, and should now prove they can deliver.<br />
<br />
As it happens, it’s Lansley’s own clinical commissioning group (CCG) structure that is causing controversy on several fronts today. Different CCGs have differing funding rates for a breast cancer drug that charities say could save thousands of lives. And on IVF treatment too, there’s a local lottery, with parts of England failing to hit the Nice guidelines, while Scotland guarantees three cycles. As with mental health funding (see below), that Lansley localism has a political downside.<br />
<br />
On the EU more generally, Leavers are delighted that the OECD has admitted it was too gloomy about the immediate impact of a Brexit vote (though it is still gloomy about 2017). <br />
<br />
As for Labour’s stance on free movement, more former shadow ministers are joining Rachel Reeves in saying curbs are crucial. <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/labour-freedom-of-movement-jonathan-reynolds_uk_57e2be9ee4b0db20a6e82ba3?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">Jonathan Reynolds today tells HuffPost</a>:”People who have a genuine emotional concern about the scale of immigration want to see that addressed.” Chuka Umunna said yesterday that immigration was the missing issue in his party’s leadership election. One to watch.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>3) A RATIO HORNBLOWER</strong><br />
<br />
It’s not just ‘hard Brexit’ that worries some in the Treasury.  Tory MPs believe the Chancellor has real concerns about some of the horn-blowing rhetoric from No.10 on taking on company ‘fatcats’ and plans to name and shame firms with large inequality ratios on pay.<br />
<br />
As part of her mission to be on the side of the ‘ordinary working class’ voter, May and her team want a US-style annual publication of the ratio “between the CEO’s pay and the average company worker’s pay”.<br />
<br />
But the FT reports that officials have warned the PM that the calculation could produce perverse results where some big banks (like Goldman Sachs) end up looking “fairer” than retailers such as John Lewis/Waitrose, which prides itself on an enlightened pay policy.  Simply because banks have fewer low-paid staff, they come out with a better ratio.<br />
<br />
Downing Street seems undeterred by what it calls ‘anomalies’. But May is famously a Waitrose shopper (and unafraid to say so), and officials are hinting they may reconsider the ‘one size fits all’ approach to how the data is presented.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>BECAUSE YOU’VE READ THIS FAR…</strong><br />
<br />
Watch this pizza delivery guy’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KNMFmT4V_60" target="_hplink">wheelie fail in Clapham</a><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>4) GIANT LEAP FOR MANC KIND</strong><br />
<br />
George Osborne’s shot across Theresa May’s bows over the Northern Powerhouse looks like it may have paid off. Having launched his new think tank to boost his pet project last week (accompanied by a slightly menacing interview on the Today prog) the former Chancellor appears to have got his way.<br />
<br />
<a href="http://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/prime-minister-theresa-may-olympic-11909364" target="_hplink">Writing for the Manchester Evening News</a>, May has lavished praise on the Northern Powerhouse.  Having struggled to even utter the phrase after she entered No.10, the PM uses it no fewer than five times in her short article. May pledged that she “will ensure the whole machinery of government gets behind it.” <br />
<br />
The Sun reports that Osbo has however ducked the chance to put his own political future where his mouth is.  Asked if he would run for the Tory candidacy for Manchester’s Metro Mayor, he replied that he was “flattered by the interest and committed to making the new Greater Manchester mayor a success, but I will do that from the House of Commons, not the town hall.” The fact that the Tories have a snowball’s chance in hell of winning is, of course, a mere detail.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<strong>5) MENTAL WEALTH SPENDING</strong><br />
<br />
Long the ‘cinderella’ of the NHS and care system, mental health has in recent years risen up the political agenda. But according to Luciana Berger, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/government-to-slash-mental-health-funding-again-figures-show_uk_57e29667e4b004d4d8618eb3?ir=UK+Politics&utm_hp_ref=uk-politics" target="_hplink">the Government is still failing to deliver</a>. <br />
<br />
The former shadow health minister has some new figures showing that funding will be cut again in many areas and the postcode lottery will keep on producing losers as well as winners. At least 73 local areas will see their GP mental health budgets slashed in 2016/2017.<br />
<br />
The gap between the smallest and largest spends will also widen: Haringey’s Clinical Commissioning Group (CCG) will put 16 percent of its budget on mental health, for West Hampshire that figure will be 5 percent.<br />
<br />
Jeremy Hunt had promised that CCGs are committed to increasing the proportion of their funding that goes into mental health. But Berger said the commitment had not been met. As an aside, I wonder if she is one of the ex shadow ministers planning a return to the Corbyn frontbench? She worked well with him on mental health, and he’s been a lifelong campaigner on the issue…<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
If you’re reading this on the web, sign-up <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/newsletter/uk-politics?pop=nls&nls=uk-politics&ncid=tweetlnkushpmg00000067" target="_hplink">HERE</a> to get the WaughZone delivered to your inbox.<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<em>Got something you want to share? Please send any stories/tips/quotes/pix/plugs/gossip to Paul Waugh (paul.waugh@huffingtonpost.com), Ned Simons (ned.simons@huffingtonpost.com), Martha Gill (martha.gill@huffingtonpost.com) and Owen Bennett (owen.bennett@huffingtonpost.com)<em><br />
 ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Britain has shown Germany how to handle a migrant crisis]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Only now does Angela Merkel <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/19/angela-merkel-admits-mistakes-asylum-seekers-election">concede</a> that she made mistakes when&nbsp;admitting a million refugees last year. It was obvious to most people in Europe at the time that her undoubtedly warm-hearted gesture would lead to catastrophic results. In declaring that all Syrian refugees would be welcome if they made it to Germany, she doubled the fortunes of the human trafficking industry. The asylum seekers came from Syria and North Africa through Austria and Hungary, having landed on the shores of Italy and Greece. Thousands died on the way.</p>
<p>When Theresa May addressed the United Nations in New York yesterday, she was able to point to a British way of handling the crisis. Rather than reward those with the strength or money to make it to a western country, Britain has ploughed hundreds of millions of pounds into giving food, shelter and support to far more refugees in Jordan, Turkey and Lebanon. Mrs May didn&rsquo;t quite say it, but the lessons from the British approach are clear: the 1951 Refugee Convention (the obligation to shelter those who arrive) was designed to prevent a recurrence of problems seen in the 1930s. It needs updating. The world is on the move, but its migration policies are not.</p>
<p>The consequences of getting this wrong are political as well as humanitarian. In Germany, in particular, there is a sense that the authorities have lost control and that established political parties cannot think or talk plainly about the problem. Last weekend, the anti-immigrant Alternative f&uuml;r Deutschland (AfD) won 14 per cent of the popular vote in Berlin state elections, and is now set to become the third-largest party in the Bundestag after next year&rsquo;s national elections. In Berlin, the Social Democrats, led by the city&rsquo;s mayor Michael M&uuml;ller, scraped victory with 22 per cent of the vote. Never in Germany&rsquo;s postwar history has a winner attracted such a small share.</p>
<p>Merkel&rsquo;s Christian Democrats finished behind the AfD in elections held in her home state of Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania three weeks ago. As Marine Le Pen remarked at the time, things that haven&rsquo;t happened for decades are now happening all of the time. Her Front National looks likely to make the final round in the coming French presidential election.</p>
<p>The three-year-old AfD is no German version of Ukip. In January, its leader Frauke Petry called for firearms to be used against migrants trying to enter Germany from Austria. A manifesto it published in May declared that Islam is not compatible with the German constitution, and called for a ban on minarets and burkas. The party&rsquo;s rise is accompanied by an increase in street violence in Germany. Fighting broke out last weekend between neo-Nazis and asylum seekers in the hilltop town of Bautzen in Saxony; a hundred police were needed to restore order. Two years ago there were 199 criminal attacks on refugee shelters; so far this year there have been 726.</p>
<p>Similar stories can be seen across the continent, where the shock of the summer terror attacks has not subsided. In Austria, a re-run of the presidential election could well lead to a victory for Norbert Hofer of the anti-immigrant Freedom party. The sense of government incompetence has been underlined by the election itself, postponed due to defective glue being used in postal ballot envelopes. Spain is now bracing itself for its third parliamentary election in a year, the various political factions having failed to form a coherent government. The coming Italian referendum on constitutional reform will be more a referendum on Matteo Renzi and his pro-EU government. If he loses, then the beneficiary will be Beppe Grillo&rsquo;s populist Five Star movement, whose inability to rule is being shown by the chaotic reign of Virginia Raggi, elected mayor of Rome three months ago. No wonder that Jean-Claude Juncker, president of the European Commission, has been talking about an &lsquo;existential crisis&rsquo;.</p>
<p>And in Britain? Racist and xenophobic politics here have never been weaker. Brexit was a vote to control, rather than reverse, immigration &mdash; and a vote to avoid the kind of problems now fermenting on the continent. The explicitly anti-racist Ukip is one of many parties now demanding that Theresa May grants permanent residency rights to all EU migrants living in Britain. The BNP is the only party that disagrees with this, but its vote fell by 99 per cent at the last election. Attempts to create alternative racist parties in recent years have ended in failure.</p>
<p>As Mrs May said in New York, borders serve a purpose. Failure to manage them erodes public confidence, and also undermines support for immigration and for helping refugees. The&nbsp;European no-borders project was conceived at an era where there was very low movement of people &ndash; the picture has transformed, now.</p>
<p>Britain has managed a recession and mass immigration with barely a fraction of the xenophobic backlash seen on the Continent.&nbsp;No one would be so bold as to say that racism has been eradicated from Britain &ndash; but we&nbsp;have no&nbsp;equivalent of AfD. When you consider the size of the&nbsp;immigration into Britain, and the depth and duration of the recent recession, it&rsquo;s&nbsp;something&nbsp;rather remarkable &ndash; and underlines Britain&rsquo;s claim to be not only one of most tolerant countries in the world but the greatest melting pot in Europe.</p>
<p>Mrs May has, so far, failed in her attempts to control immigration. But British refugee policies have been more innovative and effective.&nbsp;We may accept fewer people to our shores, but we do process a&nbsp;significant number. Not so long ago, this magazine was arguing&nbsp;for more Syrians to be admitted &ndash; David&nbsp;Cameron responded. The balance is, now, about right. And it&rsquo;s right because Britain now does more than perhaps any other European country to help refugees &ndash; precisely because our help is concentrated in countries where help can go furthest.</p>
<p>Mass migration on the scale of recent years is unprecedented. This is a very new problem, but only Britain has responded with a new approach &mdash; one that Europe&rsquo;s leaders might well end up adopting.</p>
<p><em>This is an extract from this week&rsquo;s magazine, available from tomorrow</em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/">Britain has shown Germany how to handle a migrant crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Rules Of The Game]]></title>
            <link>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/john-watson/the-rules-of-the-game_1_b_12128794.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</link>
            <guid>http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/john-watson/the-rules-of-the-game_1_b_12128794.html?utm_hp_ref=uk-politics&amp;ir=UK+Politics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[What is this talk of gerrymandering?<br />
<br />
"I have never believed in questioning or second-guessing the decision of the referee." The words appear in the final paragraph of David Laws' book Coalition and the referee he is referring to is the British electorate which so brutally rejected his party in May 2015.  Obviously Laws himself must have regarded the decision as a very disappointing one but his acceptance of the verdict made in accordance with the system is refreshing, and a pleasant break from the usual whinge that rules which produce the wrong result (according to the preferences of the speaker) must in some way be wrong or unfair.  The  proposals for changes in constituency boundaries have brought the whingers out in force.<br />
<br />
"An affront to democracy", "A dog's dinner", that is the very least of it.  No lesser person than Emily Thornberry, the Shadow Foreign Secretary, is reported as saying, "it's very obvious gerrymandering.  The whole thing stinks".  Well that sounds terrible, doesn't it?  No one suggests that the Boundary Commissioners themselves have misbehaved, of course.  They are an independent body under the control of the Speaker but in practice chaired by a High Court Judge, so it must be the rules which they have to apply in making their recommendations which are wrong.  Yes, that must be it, a recommendation made in accordance with wicked Tory rules to be forced through in due course by a wicked Tory majority.  Labour's prospects at the next election unfairly trashed.  No wonder that it has given the Thornberrys of this world indigestion.<br />
<br />
Most normal people have better things to do than read the rules which the Boundary Commission use to make recommendations.  Still, in view of the appalling threat to our democracy, perhaps it would be a good thing to take a peep inside the Guide to the 2018 Review of Parliamentary Constituencies which sets them out at schedule D.  Well no, they won't win the Booker Prize and the lack of racy language betrays that they are simply copied from the Parliamentary Constituencies Act 1986, but they are short and fairly clear.  For those with a taste for such things here is a <a href="http://boundarycommissionforengland.independent.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/2016-07-11-Guide-to-2018-review-Final-Version.pdf" target="_hplink">link</a>.<br />
<br />
Of course the fact that the rules are in the 1986 act does not make all of them thirty years old. They were added to in 1992 and 2011 and it is the latter changes which require that the current review should reduce the number of constituencies in the UK to 600 and provide that (save in certain exceptional circumstances - e.g. constituencies of over 12,000 km², etc.) no constituency may have more than 95% or less than 105% of the average number of electors.  As the average is 74,769 that sets a maximum of 78,507 and a minimum of 71,031.<br />
<br />
This requirement, which must be strictly applied, can be contrasted with a number of factors which the Boundary Commission may take into account if they think fit.  Those include existing constituency boundaries, special geographical considerations and things of that sort; but, although that may help the Commissioners to select boundaries, they cannot override the maximum and minimum limits.<br />
<br />
It is these limits on constituency size which seem to have caused the outrage.  For obvious reasons the review process has to work from historic data, and the law requires that the calculations are done by reference to the register of voters two years and ten months before a final report has to be presented to the House of Commons.  The final report arising from the present review is to be presented in 2018 and so boundaries are to be drawn on the assumption that the number of electors in any area is the number who were registered in December 2015.  No account is taken of those who have registered since or, indeed, of foreigners living in the area who are not entitled to register.  MPs from areas where there is more than the usual number of these think this unfair.  If unregistered voters were included, or if the rules had set a later date, their area would have more representation.<br />
<br />
One would like to say that these protests arose from aspirations to achieve the purest possible form of democracy but, alas, it is hard to do so.  For many years a failure to update the system biased it heavily against the Conservatives and the fact that the latter could not outvote the combination of Labour and the Liberal Democrats blocked any reform in 2013.  Labour MPs did not protest then, of course.  They simply sat on the advantage given them and toasted the fact that Tories did not have the majority they needed to level the playing field.<br />
<br />
This article is not about hypocrisy, however, but about something rather different.  Maybe you would get a different result if the "review date" was a month or two later.  Maybe it would be better if foreigners without votes were counted.  Perhaps it would or perhaps it would not, but the fact is that we have a system which on the face of it is reasonably fair, and it is no good ranting on about it being unfair if the result doesn't happen to suit you.<br />
<br />
We have seen much of the same in relation to the Brexit referendum, of course.  I have always been a Remain and didn't particularly care for the result, but I accept that the referendum was the route chosen to decide the matter, that that route has been followed and that a decision has been made.  It is tedious in the extreme to hear those who argue for a second referendum biased towards a Remain view by giving votes to 16-year-olds (after all they have to live with the system for longer, poor dears), weighting the vote against those who are sixty-five (after all they haven't got long to go, poor dears) or simply removing the vote from everyone who lives south of the River.  Maybe these would be wonderful systems or maybe they would not, but they don't happen to be the one chosen.<br />
<br />
There comes a stage, of course, when systems of decision-making have to be updated.  Sometimes that means wholesale change, as with the 1832 reform act or the introduction of female suffrage; more often it is just a question of adjusting rules or changing their application.  At that stage a decision has to be made as to what the optimum rules will be and usually there is a choice with much to be said for one version or another.  Once that choice has been made it will dictate the results when the rules come to be applied.<br />
<br />
That is how rules work and for the system to be successful it is important to keep to the order.  First you make the rules. Then you apply them.  If you cry "foul" and start changing the rules every time the result of their application does not suit you, you might as well not have rules at all.  Then there would be nothing to stop the strongest from imposing their will on the weakest.  That would be a bad result in a country which claims to work by the rule of law.<br />
<br />
The Report of the Boundary Commission is the beginning of a process of consultation and that process will no doubt throw up a number of changes to the plan before it is finally adopted.  What cannot be changed, however, are the minimum number of electors in a constituency and how that number is measured.  Emily Thornberry and her friends should accept that.  It is one thing to argue in the consultation how the rules should be applied.  That is what the process is for.  It is quite another to start shouting "gerrymandering" or "disgraceful" simply because on this occasion the result of applying the rules does not suit you.<br />
<br />
Frst oublished in the <a href="http://www.shawsheet.com" target="_hplink">Shaw Sheet.</a> ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>