<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BriefBot</title>
        <description>Brexit, explained</description>
        <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 22:26:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>BriefBot</title>
            <url>http://example.com/image.png</url>
            <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2016, Explaain</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit Britain 'MUST accept free movement if it wants access to single market']]></title>
            <link>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/brexit-britain-must-accept-free-8920220</link>
            <guid>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/brexit-britain-must-accept-free-8920220</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 21:32:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[&#xa; Two EU leaders have said they &quot;can&#x27;t imagine&quot; their citizens would not receive equal treatment after Britain quits the EU&#xa; ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Senior Tories to urge Theresa May not to sleepwalk out of single market in pursuit of 'hard Brexit']]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-tories-theresa-may-hard-brexit-eu-referendum-single-market-a7331396.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-tories-theresa-may-hard-brexit-eu-referendum-single-market-a7331396.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 19:08:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Dominic Grieve says leaving the association would put jobs and livelihoods at risk]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour must hold the Tories to account on Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/theres-no-point-analysing-john-mcdonnells-policy-statement/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/theres-no-point-analysing-john-mcdonnells-policy-statement/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 11:40:03 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John McDonnell is now speaking at the Labour conference, and will pledge to match the regional funding that communities will lose as a result of Brexit. This has been billed as &lsquo;one of the Labour Party&rsquo;s biggest policy statements since the Brexit vote&rsquo;, which is another way of saying &lsquo;one of the Labour Party&rsquo;s only policy statements since the Brexit vote&rsquo;.</p>
<p>The turmoil in the party since that vote and its dismal performance in the polls (which, despite urban legend, was the case before the attempted coup against Corbyn) means that it&rsquo;s largely pointless to evaluate this policy statement as though it might actually happen. Labour isn&rsquo;t going to be in government any time soon.</p>
<p>But what Labour can do right now is hold the Tories to account on Brexit. Representatives from businesses were disappointed to hear the Shadow Chancellor criticising the Remain campaign for going too far in scaremongering about the economy when he spoke at a reception last night. They felt this showed that he would be insufficiently robust in ensuring that the terms of Britain&rsquo;s exit were as positive for businesses and trade as possible. This shouldn&rsquo;t have been much of a surprise, given McDonnell has always been a critic of the EU. But it shows the difficulty Labour has in merely doing what it can while it is so far from government.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/284698304&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false" width="100%" height="166" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/theres-no-point-analysing-john-mcdonnells-policy-statement/">Labour must hold the Tories to account on Brexit</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why isn't Labour debating Brexit at its conference?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/why-isnt-labour-debating-brexit-at-its-conference</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/why-isnt-labour-debating-brexit-at-its-conference</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 09:33:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK’s decision to leave EU is not one of the eight subjects chosen for debate but that doesn’t mean it isn’t being discussed</p><p><strong>Is it true that Labour won’t be discussing Brexit at its conference? </strong></p><p>Yes and no. Britain’s vote to leave the EU is widely seen as the biggest historical event in a generation and as such, of course, it will be discussed at Labour’s conference. But it is not on the formal agenda as a conference topic.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/why-isnt-labour-debating-brexit-at-its-conference">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit is an ultra-delicate manoeuvre that needs a measured approach | Mohamed El-Erian]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-ultra-delicate-manoeuvre-that-needs-measured-approach-may-government</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-ultra-delicate-manoeuvre-that-needs-measured-approach-may-government</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 14:28:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The May government will need to show a level of resilience and agility far beyond what has been required of its predecessors</p><p>The aftermath of the UK’s unexpected vote in June to leave the EU is being monitored closely. People all over the world – and particularly in Europe – want to know <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/focal-points/brexit-limbo">how Brexit will unfold</a>, not just to manage its specific effects but to gain insight into what is likely to happen if other upcoming votes tip in favour of nationalist agendas.</p><p>Those agendas are certainly making a political comeback. In Germany, which will hold a general election in 2017, support for the far-right Alternative für Deutschland (AfD) is on the rise, exemplified in the party’s <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/germany-growing-support-far-right-by-michael-broening-2016-09">strong showing</a> in recent state elections. In France, the Front National leader, Marine Le Pen, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/jun/17/marine-le-pen-france-national-front-brexit-austria-far-right-rally">hopes to ride nationalism to power</a> in next year’s presidential election.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-ultra-delicate-manoeuvre-that-needs-measured-approach-may-government">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laws made in a British Parliament and enforced by British judges - Brexit will make us an independent country once again]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/26/laws-made-in-a-british-parliament-and-enforced-by-british-judges/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/26/laws-made-in-a-british-parliament-and-enforced-by-british-judges/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 16:33:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit means Brexit: the only thing that has changed is the arithmetic]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-means-brexit-only-change-arithmetic-jonathan-lynn-yes-minister</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-means-brexit-only-change-arithmetic-jonathan-lynn-yes-minister</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 13:36:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Yes Minister co-creator Jonathan Lynn’s weekly column, the chancellor and the trade minister compare notes</p><p><em>High-level inter-departmental talks.</em></p><p><strong>Trade minister </strong>It’s great that little Owen thingy person lost.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/brexit-means-brexit-only-change-arithmetic-jonathan-lynn-yes-minister">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Britain will suffer 'economic shock' if there is no free trade deal with the EU after Brexit, minister suggests]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/britain-will-suffer-economic-shock-if-there-is-no-free-trade-dea/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/britain-will-suffer-economic-shock-if-there-is-no-free-trade-dea/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 06:19:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour guarantees £10bn of European Union funding to deprived areas of Britain]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/labour-guarantees-10bn-european-union-funding-deprived-areas-britain-emily-thornberry-john-mcdonnell-a7329976.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/labour-guarantees-10bn-european-union-funding-deprived-areas-britain-emily-thornberry-john-mcdonnell-a7329976.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 05:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[It comes as shadow chancellor John McDonnell promises a more interventionist government]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How my party leader Nicola Sturgeon could get 'neo-independence' from Brexit - without another referendum]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/how-my-party-leader-nicola-sturgeon-could-get-neo-independence-f/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/how-my-party-leader-nicola-sturgeon-could-get-neo-independence-f/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 21:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nicola Sturgeon could win 'neo-independence' by focusing on Brexit powers, not referendum]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/nicola-sturgeon-could-win-neo-independence-by-focusing-on-brexit/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/25/nicola-sturgeon-could-win-neo-independence-by-focusing-on-brexit/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Business pessimism, pensions, tax credits and online banking]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-62/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-62/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 09:04:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="story-body__introduction">UK financial services firms are becoming more pessimistic about their prospects in the wake of the Brexit vote, an industry survey suggests.</p>
<p>Optimism fell for the third consecutive quarter according to the CBI employers group.&nbsp;It is the sector&rsquo;s longest period of falling sentiment since 2009 &ndash; in the midst of the financial crisis.</p>
<p>The survey of 115 companies found low interest rates and potential restricted EU market access were seen as risks.&nbsp;But while 28 per cent of the respondents were gloomier, 15 per cent were more optimistic.&nbsp;And almost 40 per cent of the firms surveyed reported healthy profits in the last quarter.</p>
<p>Meanwhile,&nbsp;Sterling is&nbsp;trading near a five-week low as lingering worries about Brexit prompted&nbsp;investors to sell the pound. &nbsp;The currency&nbsp;was knocked late on Thursday after Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson said he expected Article 50 to be triggered early next year &ndash; a claim later&nbsp;denied by Downing Street.</p>
<p><strong>Pensions</strong></p>
<p>The cost of running generous pension schemes at Britain&rsquo;s biggest firms is set to double to an unaffordable &pound;14 billion-a-year over the next three years, according to a warning from a retirement consultancy.</p>
<p><em>The Telegraph</em> reports that FTSE 100 firms that run defined benefit pensions, which offer workers a guaranteed income for life once they retire, currently pay &pound;7 billion a year to fund their obligations and manage their sizeable investments, JLT Employee Benefits said.</p>
<p>Almost all of the running costs, around &pound;6.23 billion last year, is used to plug funding shortfalls, which totalled &pound;87 billion by March for the 100 biggest firms and has risen further since.</p>
<p>In other pensions news, <em>The Times</em> reports that&nbsp;Tesco could be called before the Commons inquiry into workplace pensions amid claims that the hole in its pension fund could be up to &pound;6.5 billion.</p>
<p>Exane BNP Paribas suggested that Tesco&rsquo;s pension deficit may have grown by as much as &pound;3.3 billion since the company&rsquo;s last stated numbers because of low interest rates and bond yields. Barclays, Tesco&rsquo;s own broker, put the increase at up to &pound;3.1 billion. A soaring deficit could threaten a resumption of dividend payments.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, millions of workers could have to delay the age when they retire by several years because they are paying steep fees on their pension fund, exclusive new research suggests.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><em>Thisismoney</em> reports that cutting back fees by just 1.5 percentage points can mean the difference between being able to retire at 63 or 80, according to the new data by&nbsp;advice firm Profile Financial.&nbsp;However many middle-aged and older workers do not even realise they are paying fees that sap their savings, which can prolong&nbsp;the amount of time they have to carry on working.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Financial exclusion</strong></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><span lang="EN-AU">A new report from cross-party think tank Demos finds that a lack of coordination between sectors involved in financial services provision and advice is stymying attempts to address the problem of financial exclusion.</span><span lang="EN-AU">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><i><span lang="EN-AU">Banking for All&nbsp;</span></i><span lang="EN-AU">reveals the tremendous scale of the challenge, with 1.5 million British adults without a bank account, and thousands more building up problematic debt and falling prey to payday loans each year. The report explains that many ordinary Britons also simply lack the financial and digital know-how to manage their money effectively.</span><span lang="EN-AU">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><span lang="EN-AU">Financial exclusion can be a vicious cycle, as the under-banked miss out on deals that are only available online or through direct debit payments (such as energy bills, mobile phone contracts and internet plans), and often struggle to access the credit needed to make investments, such as buying property, or the financial products to help them plan and save for the future.</span></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><strong>Tax credits</strong></p>
<p class="story-body__introduction">A firm used by the Government to cut tax credit payments has received calls from &lsquo;suicidal&rsquo; clients, the <em>BBC</em> has been told.</p>
<p>A whistleblower at Concentrix&rsquo;s call centre said most staff &lsquo;weren&rsquo;t even trained&rsquo; to deal with such calls.&nbsp;He said staff were not offered counselling, but were instead told: &lsquo;Have a smoke&hellip; you&rsquo;ll be fine.&rsquo;</p>
<p>But Concentrix said, in the case of suicidal callers, staff were trained in accordance with guidelines from HMRC.&nbsp;It told the<em> BBC</em>&lsquo;s Victoria Derbyshire programme: &lsquo;Our staff are supported as much as possible where we have encountered this type of scenario.&rsquo;</p>
<p><strong>Online banking</strong></p>
<p>Almost half of UK banking customers are still not comfortable managing their finances solely online or by mobile, according to the 2016 EY Global Consumer Banking Survey.</p>
<p>Although digital banking is on the rise, with around a third of respondents claiming they use online and mobile banking more than they did a year ago, people still want to deal with someone face-to-face for certain banking queries. In addition, a third claim to actively distrust a bank that has no high street presence, even if they predominantly use digital banking.</p>
<p><strong>Home insurance</strong></p>
<p>Home insurer NFU Mutual has revealed that it paid out just over &pound;25 million in home fire claims in 2015 and that 52 per cent of the cost of these claims arose from electrical fires.</p>
<p>Nicki Whittaker, a high value home specialist at NFU Mutual, said:<strong>&nbsp;&lsquo;</strong>Where household appliances were directly responsible for causing fire, cookers, dishwashers and fridges/freezers were the worst offenders. Tumble driers, electric blankets and irons were also named as a source of home fires.</p>
<p>&lsquo;It will come as a great shock to many householders to learn that everyday appliances designed to make life easier could present a fire risk. We urge homeowners never to overload plug sockets, regularly check for frayed or worn cables and wires and to unplug appliances when not in use.</p>
<p>&lsquo;Programming appliances such as tumble driers or dishwashers to run while homeowners are at work or asleep could also expose people to increased risk if a fire does occur and it goes without saying smoke alarms should be fitted and regularly tested.&rsquo;
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-62/">Business pessimism, pensions, tax credits and online banking</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The racist ideas of slave owners are still with us today | Catherine Hall]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/racist-ideas-slavery-slave-owners-hate-crime-brexit-vote</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/racist-ideas-slavery-slave-owners-hate-crime-brexit-vote</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 19:32:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The surge in hate crime since the Brexit vote is one legacy of an overlooked period of British history</p><p>On Sunday evening, the ITV series Victoria imagined Prince Albert addressing the great anti-slavery convention at Exeter Hall, on the continued existence of the slave trade and slavery. It went so far as to show an encounter between Albert, a freed African-American and American feminists attending the convention.</p><p>It was engaging television. But don’t be fooled. People of colour and women were in reality marginalised at this famous 1840 event. And while Albert supported anti-slavery causes, other significant royals, including Victoria’s uncle the Duke of Cumberland, opposed the ending of the slave trade and slavery.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/racist-ideas-slavery-slave-owners-hate-crime-brexit-vote">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In an endless sea of financial press releases, there’s always a gem]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/lego-children-home-insurance/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/lego-children-home-insurance/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 11:36:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you write for <em>The Spectator</em>, it&rsquo;s tempting to stick to the more cerebral issues of the day. As money editor, this can include tracking the progress of Sterling post-Brexit, ruminating on the downward trajectory of house price growth or reflecting on the merits of equity release.</p>
<p>Some days, however, that&rsquo;s the last thing you want to do &ndash; Monday mornings being a case in point. We&rsquo;re only a few hours in to the working week and already I&rsquo;ve&nbsp;been invited to breakfast with the Austrian federal minister of finance, Hans J&ouml;rg Schelling, to an obesity lecture, a hotel show, and a FinTech launch. Sometimes I wish I&rsquo;d never gotten out of bed.</p>
<p>As a financial journalist, I&rsquo;m inundated with press releases, invitations, unsolicited requests for coverage and phone calls. There&rsquo;s a permanent Post-it on my desk which reads &lsquo;deal with inbox&rsquo;. It&rsquo;s a never-ending task that, in my heart of hearts, I know will never reach completion.</p>
<p>Consider some of this morning&rsquo;s emails. &lsquo;Over 50s enjoy a flutter&rsquo; read one. &lsquo;2 million Brits still financially tied to their ex-partner&rsquo; said another. Others included &lsquo;Easing L&amp;G back into auto-enrolment&rsquo;, &lsquo;Comment on the latest insurance premium tax increase&rsquo;, and &lsquo;The cost of a happy birthday &ndash; Brits spend more than &pound;850 each year on gifts and celebrations&rsquo;.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s exhausting and exhaustive. On a typical working day, I estimate that I receive a minimum of 100 emails, often many more, and that&rsquo;s before I check my junk box, two other email accounts, social media messages, texts and my answerphone. Then there are the follow-up calls, the &lsquo;just checking you have seen my email&rsquo;. It&rsquo;s enough to make one long for the days of faxes and snail mail.</p>
<p>So you&rsquo;ll forgive me if, today, just for a change, I depart from the usual serious fare on <em>Spectator Money</em> and tell you about Lego&nbsp;bricks being flushed down the loo. Yes, you read that right.&nbsp;I&rsquo;ve got your attention now.</p>
<p>According to new research by Direct Line (you have to admire a PR who can turn a humdrum press release about home insurance into a story about bogs), children under 10 have dropped&nbsp;2.5 million Lego blocks down the&nbsp;U-bend. As any parent will know, Lego is expensive so that&rsquo;s a lot of money down the drain.</p>
<p>How on earth did Direct Line arrive at this figure? According to the press release&rsquo;s &lsquo;notes to editor&rsquo;, the amount of Lego bricks was calculated by &lsquo;multiplying the base size of children that have dropped an item by the population total. This was then multiplied by the number of items dropped, and were then added altogether for the cumulative total of items dropped.&rsquo; To be honest, I&rsquo;m none the wiser but I don&rsquo;t care. I like the stats regardless, especially Direct Line&rsquo;s assertion that these lost&nbsp;Lego bricks could build a tower four times taller than the current world record&nbsp;of 35.05 metres, which was built with an estimated 550,000 of these plastic blocks.</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s more. The insurer&rsquo;s study also suggests that kids aged under 10 have flushed 4 million dolls down the loo and dropped millions of phones in the toilet. Pens and crayons have met a similar watery fate, as have house and car keys, credit cards, and board game pieces.</p>
<p>Of course, Direct Line&rsquo;s point to all this is the damage caused by blocked toilets and overflowing pipes, and the benefits of having a robust home insurance policy in place. But when the alternative to this release is one asking &lsquo;Are billionaires feeling the pressure?&rsquo;, I&rsquo;ll opt for Lego down the loo every time.</p>
<p><em>Helen Nugent is Online Money Editor of The Spectator</em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/lego-children-home-insurance/">In an endless sea of financial press releases, there&#8217;s always a gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Has Great Britain's Brexit referendum brought Ireland closer to reunification?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/14/has-britains-brexit-referendum-brought-ireland-closer-to-reunification</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/14/has-britains-brexit-referendum-brought-ireland-closer-to-reunification</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 11:02:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We want to hear about whether the UK’s decision to leave the European Union means a unified Ireland is more likely</p><p>Despite the fact Brexit has yet to actually happen, there are many predictions about its possible impact. One of the issues under discussion is what effect it will have on relations between Northern Ireland and Ireland. </p><p>The leader of the Republic of Ireland’s main opposition party is one of several politicians who believes Brexit could move <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/ireland">Ireland</a> closer to reunification. <br></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/14/has-britains-brexit-referendum-brought-ireland-closer-to-reunification">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Theresa May allies publish letters to Cameron calling for immigration brake]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/theresa-may-allies-publish-letters-showing-she-sought-emergency-brake-on-immigration</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/theresa-may-allies-publish-letters-showing-she-sought-emergency-brake-on-immigration</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 08:42:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Allies say letters prove it is ‘untrue’ to suggest she did not back former PM after two books questioned her role in referendum campaign</p><p>Allies of Theresa May have released details of letters they say the then home secretary wrote to David Cameron making the case for an emergency brake on EU migration amid negotiations before the Brexit referendum, rejecting charges she did not back him on the issue.</p><p>The unusual move happened after May came under criticism for her role in the EU vote in two new books. </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/26/theresa-may-allies-publish-letters-showing-she-sought-emergency-brake-on-immigration">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour conference, day two: The Spectator guide]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/labour-conference-day-two-spectator-guide/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/labour-conference-day-two-spectator-guide/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 06:36:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s day two of the Labour Party conference. Here&rsquo;s the Spectator&rsquo;s guide to what to look out for today:</p>
<p><strong>Main conference:</strong></p>
<p><strong>11am:</strong> <em>Shadow Chancellor John McDonnell&rsquo;s speech</em></p>
<p><strong>Fringe events:</strong></p>
<p><strong>9am:</strong> <em>&lsquo;You can&rsquo;t build peace with concrete: ending our relationships with Israel&rsquo;s illegal settlements&rsquo;</em><br>
Speakers include: Jeremy Corbyn (possibly); Emily Thornberry</p>
<p><strong>12.30pm:</strong> <em>Where Next for Britain in Europe?</em><br>
Speakers include: Chuka Umunna; John Mann</p>
<p><strong>12.30pm:</strong> <em>Brexit: Unite against racism and hatred</em><br>
Speakers include: Diane Abbott</p>
<p><strong>12.30pm:</strong> <em>How do Labour win the general election?</em><br>
Speakers include: Angela Eagle</p>
<p><strong>2.30pm:</strong> <em>The case for Labour to back electoral reform</em><br>
Speakers include: John McDonnell</p>
<p><strong>5.30pm</strong>: <em>What does Brexit mean for students?</em><br>
Speakers include: Malia Bouattia, President of the NUS</p>
<p><strong>5.30pm:</strong> <em>The Labour business fringe</em><br>
Speakers include: John McDonnell; Stephen Kinnock</p>
<p><strong>5.45pm:</strong> <em>Divided Britain: How should we put the One Nation back together again?</em><br>
Speakers include: Alan Johnson and John McTernan</p>
<p><strong>6.30pm:</strong> <em>Prepare for Power</em><br>
Speakers include: John McDonnell speaking; Jackie Walker, vice-chair Momentum; Diane Abbott</p>
<p><strong>7.15pm:</strong> <em>After Brexit: Reclaiming patriotism from the Right</em><br>
Speakers include: Tristram Hunt</p>
<p><strong>Momentum events:</strong></p>
<p><strong>12 &ndash; 2pm:</strong> <em>What is Momentum for?</em></p>
<p><strong>5 &ndash; 7pm:</strong> <em>Building a Progressive Majority</em><br>
Speakers include: Jon Lansman &ndash; Chair of Momentum;&nbsp;Caroline Lucas MP</p>
<p><strong>7-9pm:</strong> <em>Corbyn and Media Bias</em><br>
Speakers include: Diane Abbott MP
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/labour-conference-day-two-spectator-guide/">Labour conference, day two: The Spectator guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fifa says it’s solved racism in football – but it’s nowhere near | Archie Bland]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/fifa-anti-racism-football-taskforce-solved-nowhere-near</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/fifa-anti-racism-football-taskforce-solved-nowhere-near</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 10:54:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Football’s governing body obviously isn’t taking the problem of racial abuse seriously if it thinks its mission is complete. There’s a long way to go</p><p>Fifa has disbanded its anti-racism taskforce, because its <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/25/fifa-anti-racism-task-force-russia-2018-world-cup" title="">mission</a> has been “completely fulfilled”. This news will reverberate across football and beyond, and presumably herald a wholesale changing of the guard. <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/sam-allardyce" title="">Sam Allardyce</a> will immediately stand down as England manager, having steered the national team to a World Cup. Theresa May will give up the premiership now that she’s proved, incontrovertibly, exactly what it is that Brexit means. Philosophers, having nailed down the meaning of life, will tend to their gardens.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/25/fifa-anti-racism-task-force-russia-2018-world-cup">Fifa disbands its anti-racism taskforce declaring that the job is done</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/26/fifa-anti-racism-football-taskforce-solved-nowhere-near">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Poland Might Change Its Abortion Law But The Internet Is Fighting Back]]></title>
            <link>https://www.buzzfeed.com/krishrach/people-on-twitter-are-wearing-black-to-protest-this-countrys?utm_term=4ldqpia</link>
            <guid>https://www.buzzfeed.com/krishrach/people-on-twitter-are-wearing-black-to-protest-this-countrys?utm_term=4ldqpia</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 13:42:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>The new law would prevent women from receiving an abortion unless they are dying.</p>











 

 
	<h1>Poland already has one of the European Union's strictest abortion laws, but the country is considering new legislation that would basically amount to a total ban.</h1>

   <p><img src="https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2016-09/23/9/asset/buzzfeed-prod-web12/sub-buzz-15164-1474637010-1.jpg?resize=625:454" width="625" height="454" alt="Poland already has one of the European Union's strictest abortion laws, but the country is considering new legislation that would basically amount to a total ban." /></p>
 
	<p>The new law would allow abortion only in cases where the woman is in "imminent" life-threatening danger, and it would otherwise punish those seeking abortions &mdash; and medical providers performing them &mdash; with five years in jail.</p>


 <p><small>Kacper Pempel / Reuters</small></p>















 

 
	<h1>It could also make any woman who suffers a miscarriage criminally suspect.</h1>

   <p><img src="https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2016-09/23/9/asset/buzzfeed-prod-web11/sub-buzz-18844-1474636813-3.jpg?resize=625:417" width="625" height="417" alt="It could also make any woman who suffers a miscarriage criminally suspect." /></p>
 
	<p>"There is a clear situation with the new proposal that it will lead to criminalization of women who had miscarriage," said Draginja Nadazdin, country director for Amnesty International in Poland. "This means that actually, every single woman could be suspected. This would be really a very, very dangerous legal change."</p>

<p>Nadazdin said those draconian consequences should have led to the bill's demise. "We would&rsquo;ve expected it to be rejected immediately, without support for further discussion," she told BuzzFeed News by telephone.</p>


 <p><small>Wojtek Radwanski / AFP / Getty Images</small></p>















 

 
	<h1>Poland's parliament voted on Friday to refer the new law to a legislative committee, keeping the possibility of the almost-ban very much alive.</h1>

   <p><img src="https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2016-09/23/9/asset/buzzfeed-prod-web12/sub-buzz-15051-1474636997-1.jpg?resize=625:421" width="625" height="421" alt="Poland's parliament voted on Friday to refer the new law to a legislative committee, keeping the possibility of the almost-ban very much alive." /></p>
 
	<p>The proposal has the backing of the Catholic Church; more than 92% of Poland is Catholic, according to the Pew Research Center.</p>

<p>The parliamentary committee will review the bill and make recommendations before referring it back for a full vote. But there's no deadline for its work, and in Poland, as in the US, bills referred to committees sometimes just die there.</p>

<p>The Polish parliament also defeated another, more liberal abortion bill on Friday.</p>

<p>Both proposals were "citizens' initiatives," which means they were drafted by citizens groups outside of parliament and supported by over 100,000 citizens' signatures.</p>


 <p><small>Kacper Pempel / Reuters</small></p>















 





<hr /><p><a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/krishrach/people-on-twitter-are-wearing-black-to-protest-this-countrys">View Entire List &rsaquo;</a></p>











]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full speech: John McDonnell at Labour conference]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/full-speech-john-mcdonnell-labour-conference/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/full-speech-john-mcdonnell-labour-conference/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:00:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now the leadership election is over, I tell you, we have to become a government in waiting. An election could come at any time. Theresa May has said that she will not be calling an early election, but when could anyone trust a Tory leader?</p>
<p>We have to prepare ourselves not just for fighting an election but for moving into Government. To do that successfully we have to have the policies and the plans for their detailed implementation on the shelf, in place for when we enter government whenever that election comes.</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/284698304&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false"></iframe></p>
<p>Everybody in the Party, at every level and in every role, needs to appreciate the sense of urgency about this task, the mess we will inherit. So in this speech I want to address some of the key issues we will face and how we will face them.</p>
<p>First though, we need to appreciate the mess that the Tories are leaving behind for when we go into Government. Six years on from when they promised to eliminate the Government&rsquo;s deficit in five years, they are nowhere near that goal. The national debt burden was supposed to be falling by last year, and it is still rising. In money terms, it now stands at &pound;1.6 trillion. Our productivity has fallen far behind. Each hour worked in the US, Germany or France is one-third more productive than each hour worked here. Our economy is failing on productivity because the Tories are failing to deliver the investment it needs, and government investment is still planned to fall in every remaining year of this Parliament.</p>
<p>In the real world economy that our people live in wages are still lower than they were before the global financial crisis in 2008. There are now 800,000 people on zero hours contracts, unable to plan from one week to the next, and the number continues to rise. Nearly half a million in bogus self-employment, 86 per cent of austerity cuts fall on women, nearly 4 million of our children are living in poverty.</p>
<p>As the fifth richest economy in the world, it shoudn&rsquo;t be like this.</p>
<p>So let&rsquo;s talk about the immediate issues facing us. On Brexit, we campaigned to remain but we have to respect the decision of the referendum. That doesn&rsquo;t mean we have to accept what the Tories serve up for our future relationship with Europe.</p>
<p>Since the Brexit vote, the Tories have come up with no plan whatsoever. They have no clue. Half of them want a hard Brexit, to walk away from 30 years of investment in our relationship with Europe. Some are just paralysed by the scale of the mess they created. Working with our socialist and social democratic colleagues across Europe, our aim is to create a new Europe which builds upon the benefits of the EU but tackles the perceived disbenefits.</p>
<p>I set out Labour&rsquo;s red lines on the Brexit negotiations a few days after the vote. Let&rsquo;s get it straight, we have to protect jobs here. So we will seek to preserve access to the Single Market for goods and services. Today, access to the Single Market requires freedom of movement of labour. But we will address the concerns that people have raised in the undercutting of wages and conditions, and the pressure on local public services.</p>
<p>We will not let the Tories to bargain away our workers&rsquo; rights. We will defend the rights of EU nationals that live and work here and UK citizens currently living and working in Europe. We were all appalled at the attacks that took place on the Polish community in our country following the Brexit vote. Let&rsquo;s be clear that, as a Party, we will always stand up against racism and xenophobia in any form.</p>
<p>In the negotiations we also want Britain to keep its stake in the European Investment Bank. At the centre of negotiations is Britain&rsquo;s financial services industry.Our financial services have been placed under threat as a result of the vote to leave. Labour has said we will support access to European markets for financial services. But our financial services must understand that 2008 must never happen again. We will not tolerate a return to the casino economy that contributed to that crash.</p>
<p>We will support financial services where they deliver a clear benefit to the whole community &ndash; not just enriching a lucky few. We&rsquo;ll work with the finance sector to develop this new deal with finance for the British people.</p>
<p>We will fight for the best possible Brexit deal for the British people.</p>
<p>There will be no more support for TTIP or any other trade deal that promotes deregulation and privatisation, here or across Europe. And we&rsquo;ll make sure any future government has the power to intervene in our economy in the interests of the whole country.</p>
<p>For Britain to prosper in that new Europe and on the world stage, our next major challenge is to call a halt to this government&rsquo;s austerity programme.<br>
The Conservative Party built upon the disaster of the 2008 financial crisis by introducing an austerity programme that has made the impact of the economic crisis more prolonged, protected the corporations and the rich, and made the rest of society pay for the mistakes and greed of the speculators that caused the crash.</p>
<p>Last year this Conference determined that this party would oppose austerity and that&rsquo;s exactly what we&rsquo;ve done. We have had some major successes. We&rsquo;ve forced the reversal of tax credit cuts.We also fought and won to have the Personal Independence Payment cuts scrapped.</p>
<p>Sometimes we don&rsquo;t thank people enough in our movement. So I want to thank Owen Smith for the work he&rsquo;s done working with Jeremy to defeat the Tories on this.</p>
<p>These are tangible victories that are making a real difference to people&rsquo;s lives. This is what we can achieve when we are united.</p>
<p>So when we go into government united, be clear, we will end this government&rsquo;s austerity programme that has damaged the lives of so many of our communities. The first step is opposing austerity; the second step is creating the alternative.</p>
<p>Exactly as our economic advisor, Nobel Prize winner, Joe Stiglitz, says: &ldquo;we have to rewrite the rules of our economy&rdquo;.</p>
<p>We will rewrite the rules to the benefit of working people on taxes, investment, and how our economic institutions work. So on tax, we know we can&rsquo;t run the best public services in the world on a flagging economy with a tax system that does not tax fairly or effectively.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll congratulate the Christians on the Left for their campaign promoting the hashtag &ldquo;patriots pay their taxes&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s a great slogan. Patriots should pay their taxes. Labour are already setting the pace on tackling tax avoidance and tax evasion.</p>
<p>We launched our Tax Transparency and Enforcement Programme to force the Government into action. I&rsquo;d like to thank Rebecca Long-Bailey for leading the Labour charge in Parliament to hold the tax dodgers to account.</p>
<p>The publication of the Panama papers threw just some light on the scale of tax evasion and avoidance. Some of the largest firms in the City of London are up to their necks in it. HSBC alone accounted for more than 2,300 shell companies established to help the super-rich duck their taxes.</p>
<p>In government we will end the social scourge of tax avoidance. We will create a new Tax Enforcement Unit at HMRC, doubling the number of staff investigating wealthy tax avoiders. We will ban tax-dodging companies from winning public sector contracts. And we will ensure that all British Crown Dependencies and Overseas Territories introduce a full, public register of company owners and beneficiaries.</p>
<p>Our review of HMRC has also exposed the corporate capture of the tax system, and how staff cutbacks are undermining our ability to collect the taxes we need. I want to thank PCS, Professor Prem Sikka, John Christiansen and their team for the expertise they have provided us in drawing up this review.</p>
<p>The next stage of our work will be to develop the legislation and international agreements needed to close tax havens and end tax abuse. I&rsquo;ll give you this assurance that when we go back into government, we&rsquo;ll make sure HMRC has the staffing, the resources, and the legal powers to close down the tax avoidance industry that has grown up in this country.</p>
<p>But we have to do more than stop tax avoidance. The burden of taxation as a whole now falls too heavily on those least able to pay. So let me make it clear: in this coming period we will be developing the policies that will shift the tax burden more fairly, away from those who earn wages and salaries and onto those who hold wealth.</p>
<p>Turning to investment, as I&rsquo;ve said before, Labour as a party of government needs to think not just how we spend money but how we earn it. I&rsquo;ve announced a &pound;250billion investment programme that will ensure no community is left behind. This is the scale of investment that independent experts say will start to bring Britain&rsquo;s infrastructure into the 21st century.</p>
<p>It means putting the investment in place that will transform our energy system, providing cheap, low-carbon electricity. It means ensuring every part of the country has access to superfast broadband, matching the best in the world. It means delivering the transport improvements, including HS3 in the north of England, that will unlock the potential of our whole country.</p>
<p>For too long major decisions about what and where to invest have been taken by Whitehall and the City. The result has been underinvestment and decline across the country. It&rsquo;s time for our regions and localities to take back control. So we will create new institutions, not run by the old elite circles.</p>
<p>Our &pound;250 billion National Investment Bank will supply the long-term, patient finance needed to sustain a new, more productive economy. It will be backed up by a network of regional development banks, with a clear public mandate to supply finance to regional and local economies.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a disgrace that our small businesses can&rsquo;t get the finance they need to grow. Our financial system is letting them down badly. The new regional development banks will have a mandate to provide the patient, long-term investment they need.</p>
<p>But we&rsquo;ll go further than this. We&rsquo;ll shake up how our major corporations work and change how our economy is owned and managed. We&rsquo;ll clamp down on the abuses of power at the very top. There&rsquo;ll be no more Philip Greens under Labour and we will legislate to rewrite company law to prevent them.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll introduce legislation to ban companies taking on excessive debt to pay out dividends to shareholders. And we&rsquo;ll rewrite the Takeover Code to make sure every takeover proposal has a clear plan in place to pay workers and pensioners.</p>
<p>But we can do more to transform our economy for working people. Theresa May has spoken about worker representation on boards. It&rsquo;s good to see her following our lead. We know that when workers own and manage their companies, those businesses last longer and are more productive.</p>
<p>If we want patient, long-term investment, and high-quality firms, what better way to do it than give employees themselves a clear stake in both? Co-operation and collaboration is how the emerging economy of the future functions. We&rsquo;ll look to at least double our co-operative sector so that it matches those in Germany and the US.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll build on the good example of Labour Councils like Preston, here in the north-west, using public procurement to support co-operatives where they can. We&rsquo;ll help create 200 local energy companies and 1,000 energy co-operatives, giving power back to local communities and breaking up the monopoly of the Big Six producers. And we&rsquo;ll introduce a &ldquo;Right to Own&rdquo;, giving workers first refusal on a proposal for worker ownership when their company faces a change of ownership or closure.<br>
So the next Labour government will promote a renaissance in co-operative and worker ownership. The new regional development banks will be tasked with supplying the capital a new generation of business owners will need to succeed.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll support business hubs across the country. I visited Make Liverpool yesterday, where an abandoned warehouse is being turned into a shared workshop space for small businesses and the self-employed. The next Labour government will provide support to establish business hubs in every town and city.</p>
<p>We know the economy is changing, with more people self-employed than ever before. We need to think creatively about how to respond and so we&rsquo;ll be taking a serious look at how to make the welfare system better support the self-employed.</p>
<p>And I am also interested in the potential of a Universal Basic Income &ndash; to learn from its potential from the experiments currently taking place across Europe.</p>
<p>But until working people have proper protections at work, the labour market will always work against them. To achieve fair wages, the next Labour government will look to implement the recommendations of the Institute of Employment Relations.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll reintroduce sectoral collective bargaining across the economy, ending the race to the bottom on wages. And let me give you this commitment: in the first hundred days of our Labour government, we&rsquo;ll repeal the Trade Union Act.</p>
<p>And what happens when trade unions are weakened? Over 200,000 workers in the UK are receiving less than the minimum wage set down in law. This is totally unacceptable.</p>
<p>Under Labour, we will properly resource HMRC and the Gangmasters and Labour Abuse Authority to make sure there are no more national scandals like Mike Ashley of Sports Direct. And our vision for a high-wage economy, with everyone receiving their fair dues, does not end there.<br>
I have spoken before about building on the great achievements of previous Labour governments. One of the greatest achievements of the government elected in 1997 was the establishment of a national minimum wage, lifting millions out of poverty. The Tories opposed it, claiming it would cost millions of jobs, but &ndash; united in purpose &ndash; we won the argument.</p>
<p>Under the next Labour government, everyone will earn enough to live on. When we win the next election we will write a real Living Wage into law. We&rsquo;ll charge a new Living Wage Review Body with the task of setting it at the level needed for a decent life. Independent forecasts suggest that this will be over &pound;10 per hour. This will be a fundamental part of our new bargain in the workplace.</p>
<p>But we know that small businesses need to be a part of the bargain. That&rsquo;s why we will also be publishing proposals to help businesses implement the Living Wage, particularly small and medium-sized companies. We will be examining a number of ideas, including the expansion and reform of Employment Allowance, to make sure that this historic step forward in improving the living standards of the poorest paid does not impact on hours or employment.</p>
<p>Backed up by our commitment to investment, we will end the scourge of poverty pay. Decent pay is not just fundamentally right, it&rsquo;s good for business, it&rsquo;s good for employees, and it&rsquo;s good for Britain. We need a new deal across our whole economy.Because whatever we do in Britain, the old rules of the global economy are being rewritten for us.</p>
<p>The winds of globalisation are blowing in a different direction.They are blowing against the belief in the free market and in favour of intervention. Look at the steel crisis. With the world market flooded by cheap steel, major governments moved to protect their domestic steel industries. Ours did not, until we pushed them to. They are so blinkered by their ideology that they can&rsquo;t see how the world is changing.</p>
<p>Good business doesn&rsquo;t need no government. Good business needs good government. And the best governments today, right across the world, recognise that they need to support their economies because the way the world works is changing.</p>
<p>For decades, manufacturing jobs disappeared as producers looked for the cheapest labour they could find. Today, one in six manufacturers in the UK are bringing jobs back to Britain. That&rsquo;s because production today is about locating close to markets and drawing on highly-skilled labour and high-quality investment.</p>
<p>Digital technology means production can be smaller-scale, in smaller, faster firms dependent on co-operation and collaboration, not dog-eat-dog competition. The economies that are making best use of this shift are those with governments that understand it is taking place, and support their new industries and small businesses. We could be a part of that change here.<br>
There is a huge potential in this country, and in every part of this country. We have an immense heritage of scientific research, and engineering expertise. Today, our science system is a world-leader. We have natural resources that could make us world-leaders in renewables. We have talent and ambition in every part of the country.</p>
<p>Yet at every single stage we have a government that fails to reach that potential. It has cut scientific research spending, it has slashed subsidies to renewables, threatening tens of thousands of jobs, and it plans to cut essential public investment in transport, energy, and housing across the whole country.</p>
<p>Be certain, the next Labour government will be an interventionist government. We will not stand by like this one has and see our key industries flounder and our future prosperity put at risk. Like Rebecca Long-Bailey has said, when we return to government we will implement a comprehensive industrial strategy.</p>
<p>After Brexit, we want to see a renaissance in British manufacturing and as we&rsquo;ve committed ourselves, our government will create an entrepreneurial state that works with the wealth creators, the workers and the entrepreneurs to create the products and the markets that will secure our long term prosperity.</p>
<p>Let me just say this in conclusion, on a personal note. I&rsquo;m so pleased that this conference is being held in Liverpool. I was born in the city, not far from here. My dad was a Liverpool docker and my mum was a cleaner who then served behind the counter at British Homes Stores for 30 years. I was part of the 1960&rsquo;s generation. We lived in what sociological studies have described as some of the worst housing conditions that exist within this country. We just called it home.</p>
<p>As a result of Labour government policies, I remember the day we celebrated moving into our council house. My brother and I had our own bedrooms for the first time. We had a garden front and rear, both of us were born in NHS hospitals, and both of us had a great free education. There was an atmosphere of eternal optimism.</p>
<p>Our generation always thought that from here on there would always be a steady improvement in people&rsquo;s living standards. We expected the lives of each generation would improve upon the last. Successive Tory governments put an end to that.</p>
<p>Under Jeremy&rsquo;s leadership, I believe that we can restore that optimism, people&rsquo;s faith in the future. In the birthplace of John Lennon, it falls to us to inspire people to imagine.</p>
<p>Imagine the society that we can create. It&rsquo;s a society that&rsquo;s radically transformed, radically fairer, more equal and more democratic. Yes, based upon a prosperous economy but an economy that&rsquo;s economically and environmentally sustainable and where that prosperity is shared by all.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s our vision to rebuild and transform Britain.&nbsp;In this party you no longer have to whisper it, it&rsquo;s called Socialism.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/full-speech-john-mcdonnell-labour-conference/">Full speech: John McDonnell at Labour conference</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alan Duncan struggles to preserve his modesty]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/alan-duncan/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/alan-duncan/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 09:55:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the EU referendum campaign, Alan Duncan penned a piece for <em>the Telegraph</em> entitled &lsquo;why this lifelong Eurosceptic is now voting to stay in&rsquo;. In this, the Conservative MP explained the heartfelt reasons he backed Remain. Alas, these were later placed in doubt when Vote Leave&rsquo;s Matthew Elliott claimed that Duncan had met with him prior to as for a position on their board and then plumped for the In camp after his request was refused.</p>
<p>Now it turns out that Duncan&rsquo;s interactions with the Remain camp weren&rsquo;t all plain-sailing either. In an extract in the <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3805954/The-dynamite-text-flip-flopping-Boris-Johnson-told-Cameron-thought-Brexit-crushed.html">Mail on Sunday</a> from Craig Oliver&rsquo;s new book on the EU referendum <em>Unleashing Demons</em>, David Cameron&rsquo;s former director of communications reveals the statement Duncan drafted &mdash; and suggested No.10 use &mdash; to reveal the news that he was an In-er:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&lsquo;In a major blow to the campaign to leave the EU, senior Tory MP Sir Alan Duncan has today announced we should remain a member. As one of the few undeclared MPs, he is seen as an experienced and reasonable figure of influence.</p>
<p>Known as a longstanding but thoughtful Eurosceptic, his declaration will be seen to have a pivotal bearing on the many voters who are still undecided.</p>
<p>To have won over such a senior and experienced political figure will be seen as a significant coup both for the Prime Minister and the campaign to remain, all the more so as Alan Duncan is seen as independent-minded and someone who cannot be pushed around.&rsquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>No.10&rsquo;s response? &lsquo;Maybe it needs a little rewriting,&rsquo; came the reply. With Duncan recently savaging Boris Johnson by claiming that the Foreign Secretary only wanted to be Prime Minister &mdash; rather than achieve Brexit, Mr S suspects that Duncan may actually be the one with ideas above his station.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"> </div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/alan-duncan/">Alan Duncan struggles to preserve his modesty</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>