<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BriefBot</title>
        <description>Brexit, explained</description>
        <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 16:36:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>BriefBot</title>
            <url>http://example.com/image.png</url>
            <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2016, Explaain</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit: UK must leave EU by early 2019, says European Parliament president Martin Schulz]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-must-leave-eu-by-2019-theresa-may-martin-schulz-european-parliament-president-a7323411.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-uk-must-leave-eu-by-2019-theresa-may-martin-schulz-european-parliament-president-a7323411.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[He has warned that it would not be good for the British to vote in Brussels elections while Brexit talks are on-going]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK economy faces challenging period after Brexit vote, says Bank]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:11:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Financial policy committee warns withdrawal from the EU poses risks but will not be used to reduce regulation of banks</p><p>The vote for Brexit has created a “challenging period of uncertainty and adjustment” Bank of England policymakers have said.</p><p>In a quarterly update on the health of the financial system on Thursday, the Bank’s policy makers also said the UK’s withdrawal from the European Union would not be used as a way to reduce regulation on the banking sector.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson never wanted Brexit and only backed Leave to become 'heir apparent' to Tory throne, says minister]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/alan-duncan-boris-johnson-brexit-a-very-british-coup-backed-leave-to-become-heir-to-tory-throne-a7321406.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 23:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[In a BBC documentary to be broadcast this week the Foreign Office Minister claims the now Foreign Secretary, who was his boss, wanted Brexit to lose]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK universities draw up plans for EU campuses ahead of Brexit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:25:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Higher education chiefs, struggling with uncertainty and challenges in regulation and funding, look to soften blow of EU exit</p><p>British universities are considering plans to open branches inside the European Union in an effort to soften the blow of Britain’s exit, as they struggle to navigate new challenges in regulation and funding.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-building-schemes-tuition-fees-new-students">Bricks and mortar boards: UK universities embark on major building schemes</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/sep/22/uk-universities-mull-eu-campuses-in-new-era-of-uncertainty">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Brexit economy: post-referendum data defies gloomy UK predictions]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:35:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guardian analysis of key economic figures gives rounded assessment three months after the vote</p><p>• Help fund our journalism by becoming a <a href="https://membership.theguardian.com/uk/supporter?INTCMP=gdnwb_copts_editorial_mem_brexitdashboardstoryfooter_footer">Guardian supporter</a></p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/ng-interactive/2016/sep/21/how-has-the-brexit-vote-affected-the-uk-economy-september-verdict">How has the Brexit vote affected the UK economy? September verdict</a> </p><p>Fears that Britain will slide into a post-referendum recession have been allayed after a Guardian analysis showed the latest news on the economy has confounded analysts’ gloomy expectations, with consumer spending strong, unemployment low and the housing market holding steady.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/post-referendum-gloom-fears-confounded-economic-evidence">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit, insurance, debt and help to buy]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:37:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fears that Britain will slide into a post-referendum recession have been allayed after a <em>Guardian</em>&nbsp;newspaper analysis showed the latest news on the economy has confounded analysts&rsquo; gloomy expectations, with consumer spending strong, unemployment low and the housing market holding steady.</p>
<p>The finding comes as a leading think tank toned down its earlier dire warnings of&nbsp;economic turmoil for the UK and its neighbours in the event of a leave vote.</p>
<p>The Paris-based Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development said prompt action by the Bank of England to cut interest rates had cushioned the blow from June&rsquo;s Brexit vote but it still believes the UK will suffer a sharp slowdown next year amid heightened uncertainty.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the boss of&nbsp;Kier Group,&nbsp;one of the country&rsquo;s biggest construction firms, says the London property market has &lsquo;definitely softened&rsquo; since the Brexit vote.</p>
<p>Haydn Mursell told the <em>BBC</em> that&nbsp;demand around&nbsp;the rest of the country is still&nbsp;good, but the capital had&nbsp;taken most&nbsp;of the impact.&nbsp;Housebuilders and estate agents were already reporting a slowing of London&rsquo;s housing market before the referendum.</p>
<p><strong>Insurance rip-off</strong></p>
<p>Elderly&nbsp;drivers and homeowners are being ripped off by insurance providers catering specifically to over 50s, consumer campaigners have warned, as they are paying up to four times as much for cover offered by regular providers.</p>
<p>A mystery shop by Which? found some year-long policies offered by specialist providers were between &pound;110 and &pound;1,134 more expensive than the best deal given by a normal insurer.</p>
<p><em>The Telegraph</em> reports that, last night, experts said it was &lsquo;unacceptable&rsquo; for trusted brands including Age UK and Saga to overcharge old and vulnerable customers just because were less likely to question the value of deals.</p>
<p>James Daley, director at Fairer Finance, said: &lsquo;These firms should be more careful about claiming they offer good value to over 50s and then in practice offering some of them very bad value.&rsquo;</p>
<p><strong>Microsoft</strong></p>
<p class="story-body__introduction">Microsoft has been criticised over its Windows 10 software by consumer rights group Which?.</p>
<p>The body said it had received hundreds of complaints about the upgrade, including lost files, emails no longer syncing and broken wi-fi and printing.&nbsp;In some cases, it said, users had had to pay for their computer to be repaired.</p>
<p>Microsoft defended its software and highlighted that it provided help online and by phone.</p>
<p>Which? surveyed more than 5,500 of its members in June, and said that 12 per cent of the 2,500 who had upgraded to Windows 10 had later reverted to an earlier version.</p>
<p><strong>Living wage</strong></p>
<p>The national living wage (NLW) falls short of providing a decent standard of income to low-paid staff and will need to increase sharply to offset rising rents and slowing wages growth,&nbsp;<em>The Guardian</em> reports.</p>
<p>After a six-month review, <a class="u-underline" href="http://www.livingwage.org.uk/living-wage-commission" target="_blank" data-link-name="in body link">the Living Wage Commission</a> said it had assessed the &lsquo;best available evidence on living standards&rsquo; and concluded that the &pound;7.20 an hour NLW for the over 25s, introduced in April, was failing to provide the basic needs of low-paid households.</p>
<p><strong>Debt</strong></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Bailiffs, utility companies and local councils who chase struggling parents over unpaid debts may be unwittingly inflicting real damage to children&rsquo;s mental health, The Children&rsquo;s Society has warned.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">A report by the charity, <a href="https://www.childrenssociety.org.uk/breathing-space-embargo" target="_blank"><i>The Damage of Debt</i></a><i>,</i> finds that children in low-income families with multiple debts are at far higher risk of suffering from mental health problems than those in families who owe money to a single type of creditor.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">For families in poverty, the crucial factor is the number of types of debts rather than the total amount owed. The more types of debt the worse a child&rsquo;s mental health is likely to be.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The findings suggest that having to juggle a range of creditors, from utility companies to stores, banks and payday loan companies, all of which may be seeking to claw back debts at the same time, ramps up the pressure on financially stressed households, who may also owe money to friends, family and other members of the community.</p>
<p><strong>Help to Buy</strong></p>
<p>The Bank of England says use of&nbsp;the Help to Buy mortgage guarantee scheme has &lsquo;declined significantly&rsquo; over the past year.</p>
<p>In the first three months of 2016, the scheme made up only 3 per cent of total mortgage lending for house purchases, the Bank&rsquo;s Financial Policy Committee says.</p>
<p>In other housing news, the Council of Mortgage Lenders estimates that gross mortgage lending reached &pound;22.5 billion in August &ndash; 7 per cent higher than July&rsquo;s lending total of &pound;21.1 billion. In addition to the month-on-month rise, lending rose 15 per cent year-on-year, from &pound;19.5 billion in August 2015. This is the highest August figure since 2007 when gross lending reached &pound;33.6 billion.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">&nbsp;<strong>Energy</strong></p>
<p>Angry customers who waited-in for&nbsp;energy supplier&nbsp;E.On&nbsp;are to receive some recompense.</p>
<p>The company has paid &pound;3.1 million after admitting to&nbsp;Ofgem, the&nbsp;energy watchdog,&nbsp;that its agents missed 35,000&nbsp;appointments between 2011 and 2015.&nbsp;E.On came forward to Ofgem and has paid out &pound;1.2 million to householders and &pound;1.9 million to energy charities.</p>
<p>Under Ofgem rules,&nbsp;if an appointment is&nbsp;missed, customers&nbsp;should receive &pound;20 to&nbsp;&pound;22. Because that&nbsp;wasn&rsquo;t paid immediately, those affected have received double.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-60/">Brexit, insurance, debt and help to buy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Brexit bounce continues – ten forecasters up their predictions for 2016 growth]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:49:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Brexit bounce continues. HM Treasury has today <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/554343/PU797forecast_for_the_uk_economy_sept.pdf" target="_blank">released forecasts</a> of the economists it follows, as it does every month. Last time, there was a flurry of downgrades and forecasts of an immediate recession. Now, these forecasts are being torn up by everyone, including by the FT (although you can bet the FT won&rsquo;t report on the upgrades as eagerly as it did the downgrades).</p>
<p>The average new forecast suggests GDP will grow by 1.8 per cent this year, far better than the 1.5 per cent forecast last month. This back to where the consensus was <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/529303/forecast_for_the_uk_economy_june_2016.pdf">before</a> the Brexit vote. The OECD, which had previously predicted &ldquo;immediate&rdquo; uncertainty after a Brexit vote, has today also upgraded to 1.8pc for this year, saying instead that the pain will be felt next year (it predicts 0.9pc growth).</p>
<p>When you take a look at the forecasts made by city heavyweights, the signs are also encouraging. Bank of America Merrill Lynch, Barclays Capital, JP Morgan, Citigroup and Morgan Stanley are amongst ten forecasters to hike their GDP growth predictions from two months ago. Of these, three &ndash; Pantheon, Bank of America and Barclays &ndash; have boosted their forecasts by a healthy 0.4 points. And Daiwa Capital Markets makes the biggest revision: shifting its July prediction of 1.4 per cent GDP growth up to 1.9 per cent. Admittedly, not everyone is as optimistic: three of the city forecasts keep their predictions the same, whilst two firms &ndash; Capital Economics and Scotiabank &ndash; have revised their GDP bets downwards by 0.1 per cent. But the panic that seemed to grip the financial experts in the run-up to the referendum, and in the immediate aftermath, seems to be subsiding.</p>
<p>The Office of National Statistics, in its snapshot of the health of the UK economy which is also published today, agrees with that assessment. In the words of their chief economist Joe Grice:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;As the available information grows, the referendum result appears, so far, not to have had a major effect on the UK economy. So it hasn&rsquo;t fallen at the first fence but longer-term effects remain to be seen. The index of services published soon and the preliminary estimate of third quarter GDP, published at the end of October will add significantly to the evidence.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>This sounds as if Q3 growth &ndash; July, August and September &ndash; is shaping up rather nicely. The ONS adds that sterling slump (badly needed for a country with a trade deficit as large as Britain&rsquo;s) has not jacked up prices in the way that many had feared. Nor has George Osborne&rsquo;s suggestion of an 18 per cent <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/may/20/eu-referendum-george-osborne-house-prices-brexit">house price crash</a> materialized. At the time, Osborne&rsquo;s allies said he was not exaggerating and that the economic advice he received was far more pessimistic than he let on. If true, this raises serious questions about the quality of economic advice being issued at the Treasury.</p>
<p>The theory was that consumer confidence would collapse, as Britain would panic about Brexit. But <a href="http://www.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/the-brexit-bounce-thats-making-doom-mongers-look-foolish/">as Ross Clark argued in his cover piece recently</a>, why would that be the case? Brexit would only happen if a majority voted for it, and if they did then why would they go on to suffer a crisis of confidence if they got what they wanted?</p>
<p>The ONS today says &lsquo;there are no signs of a sharp collapse in consumer confidence as some early fears had suggested&rsquo; and that there was no indication that &lsquo;referendum fears&rsquo; were biting any sub-sectors in the manufacturing industry. Of course, Brexit hasn&rsquo;t happened yet &ndash; and&nbsp;nor will the turbulence be over for some time. But&nbsp;the wilder forecasts issued by HM Treasury &ndash; and&nbsp;immediate recession, house price crash, half-a-million&nbsp;job losses &ndash; don&rsquo;t seem to be in the pipeline just yet.</p>
<p>Indeed,&nbsp;Britain&rsquo;s healthy employment rate of 74.5 per cent fits, in the ONS&rsquo;s own words, &lsquo;with a picture of broad strength in the UK economy in the run up to and in the period immediately following the EU referendum&rsquo;. Not that you&rsquo;d have known by reading most of the economic and financial commentary at the time. This isn&rsquo;t surprising: economists are not clairvoyants, nor are pundits. None saw the crash coming. But not so long ago, there was a lot of panic about a populist post-fact Britain that didn&rsquo;t believe in experts. The picture now emerging is of a healthy and sceptical Britain that values its experts but knows that, sometimes, they&rsquo;re capable of all being wrong.
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/">The Brexit bounce continues &#8211; ten forecasters up their predictions for 2016 growth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit U-turns: who is rowing back on their Project Fear warnings?]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:35:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the run-up to the referendum, we were warned Brexit would unleash misery. George Osborne suggested a vote for Brexit would lead to a DIY recession. And numerous business bosses and the great and the good piled in to add their warnings to the doom-mongering. Yet in the weeks since the referendum, their predictions of chaos have not come true. What&rsquo;s more, many of those shouting the loudest about the consequence of Brexit are&nbsp;now furiously rowing back on their warnings. Here, The Spectator compiles the&nbsp;Brexit u-turns and&nbsp;referendum backtracking:</p>
<p>In the aftermath of the vote, many major banks and financial institutions continued to warn that Brexit spelt bad news for the economy. <strong>Credit Suisse</strong> were among them; in a Treasury report in August, they predicted the UK&rsquo;s economy would go into <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/546720/2016_08_forecomp_august_2016.pdf">recession</a> next year. Now, just weeks later, they&rsquo;ve cancelled that forecast to suggest&nbsp;instead that the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ad13cdf6-7428-11e6-bf48-b372cdb1043a">economy would grow</a> by 0.5 per cent next year. <strong>Morgan Stanley</strong> also cancelled their prediction of a 2017 &lsquo;Brecession&rsquo; to&nbsp;offer a similar, more optimistic picture of the UK economic outlook. The investment bank also <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-bounce-continues/?_ga=1.192455779.83446721.1455897487">upped its GDP forecast</a> again this month.</p>
<p><strong>London City Airport</strong>&lsquo;s boss Declan Collier <a href="http://www.cityam.com/243707/brexit-would-leave-london-isolated-according-boss-city">warned</a> before Brexit that a vote to &lsquo;Leave&rsquo; would &lsquo;undermine the free flow of trade and travel&rsquo;. Yet just a month after the referendum, things were <a href="http://www.itv.com/news/london/2016-07-27/london-city-airport-gets-344m-expansion-and-a-promise-of-a-boost-to-the-economy/">looking much rosier</a> for the airport following the announcement of a &pound;344m expansion. Collier said the news &lsquo;sent a strong message that London and the UK are very much open for business&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Nissan</strong> is one of the most important foreign investors in the UK, so when&nbsp;the carmaker&rsquo;s boss Carlos&nbsp;Ghosn said that Brexit could cause the company to reconsider its investments in Britain, people sat up and listened. That was in <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-24859486">November 2013</a>, yet after the referendum Ghosn has struck a <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36981182">somewhat more positive note</a> about how he is &lsquo;reasonably optimistic&rsquo; over Brexit, whatever happens.</p>
<p><strong>Donald Tusk</strong> couldn&rsquo;t have been clearer in making his thoughts known about Brexit in the run-up to the referendum. The European Council president said a British exit from the EU <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-eu-referendum-36515680">could</a> trigger &lsquo;the end of Western political civilisation&rsquo;. Yet the day after the vote, he was somewhat more sober-minded, saying that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/live/eu-referendum/donald-tusk/">it was business as usual</a>: &lsquo;What has happened happened, and we have to move on with our regular agenda.&rsquo;</p>
<p><strong>GlaxoSmithKline</strong>&lsquo;s boss made it clear he thought&nbsp;Brexit was bad news for business. Sir Andrew Witty&nbsp;said that it was better for Britain to stay in the EU than &lsquo;trying to plot a new course&rsquo; outside. And he went on to say, <a href="http://www.cityam.com/240597/eu-referendum-now-top-life-science-bosses-warn-of-brexit-risk-including-gsk-astrazeneca-and-pfizer-in-open-later">back in May</a>, that &lsquo;leaving the EU would create uncertainty and potentially add complexity&rsquo;. Just weeks after the referendum, though, GSK announced plans to invest &pound;275m in three of its British plants. And here is Witty speaking about their post-Brexit investment:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;It [the investment] is testament to our skilled UK workforce and the country&rsquo;s leading position in life sciences.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Rob Wainwright, the British head of <strong>Europol</strong>, said in the run-up to the referendum that Brexit &lsquo;would make it harder for Britain to fight terrorism and crime.&rsquo; But in the aftermath of the vote, he struck a <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/07/europol-chief-rows-back-brexit-project-fear-warnings/">more positive note</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;We&rsquo;re dealing very much with a globalised problem that requires close co-operation with our European neighbours, particularly in information sharing. That&rsquo;s going to continue of course, even after the UK leaves the EU.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Siemens</strong>&lsquo;s Chief Executive waited until after the EU referendum to say that Brexit <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36680572">could hit investment</a>.&nbsp;Juergen Maier said the company&rsquo;s short-term investments in Britain were &lsquo;on ice&rsquo;. Yet, just weeks later, it was announced Siemens would continue to pump money into Britain. In an apparent contradiction of the company&rsquo;s&nbsp;earlier warnings, Maier&nbsp;said that whether the UK was in or out of the EU, it <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-36771595">remained</a> a &lsquo;good place to do business&rsquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Barack Obama</strong> was undoubtedly one of the highest profile figures from overseas to intervene in the Brexit debate. He famously warned that a Britain outside the EU would find itself &lsquo;at the back of the queue&rsquo; in trade talks with the US. Afterwards, however, the President&rsquo;s spokesman&nbsp;Eric Schultz made it clear that the special relationship &lsquo;had not suffered because of the vote&rsquo;.</p>
<p>As the architect of Project Fear, <strong>George Osborne</strong> was one of the first to backtrack following Brexit. In the lead-up to the vote, the then-Chancellor indicated there would be a recession&nbsp;if Britain voted &lsquo;Leave&rsquo;. But speaking days&nbsp;after the referendum vote emerged, he softened his rhetoric to say the economy would merely undergo an &lsquo;adjustment&rsquo;. And where was his much-touted &rsquo;emergency budget&rsquo;? Osborne wasn&rsquo;t keen to be drawn on that either, and booted the budget football away by saying there would &lsquo;have to be action&rsquo; &ndash; without daring to mention his original plan of action.</p>
<p><strong>Michael Saunders&nbsp;</strong>was all doom and gloom about Brexit when he joined the&nbsp;Monetary Policy Committee earlier this year. Speaking in May, he said privately that a vote to leave the EU could force interest rates up to as much as 3.5 per cent <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/personal-banking/mortgages/brexit-will-force-rates-up-to-35pc-within-18-months-says-newest/">by Christmas</a>. Yet in an interview in September, Saunders changed his tune by suggesting that a <a href="http://www.cityam.com/249761/uk-economy-slow-less-than-expected-after-brexit-vote-says">further cut</a> in interest rates could be on the cards.</p>
<p><em>We&rsquo;ll keep all the backtracking up to date over the weeks and months ahead. If there&rsquo;s a Brexit U-turn that you think should be included, then email tgoodenough@spectator.co.uk</em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/brexit-u-turns-rowing-back-project-fear-warnings/">Brexit U-turns: who is rowing back on their Project Fear warnings?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boris Johnson 'didn't want Brexit win']]></title>
            <link>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37439890</link>
            <guid>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37439890</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:00:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Boris Johnson campaigned to leave the EU to become the Conservative "heir apparent" - and did not expect to win, Sir Alan Duncan claimed the day before June's referendum.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foreign Office minister Alan Duncan insults boss Boris Johnson as he claims he never wanted Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/foreign-office-minister-alan-duncan-insults-boss-boris-johnson-a/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/foreign-office-minister-alan-duncan-insults-boss-boris-johnson-a/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 14:27:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brexit is risking student numbers and vital research funding, says head of Oxford University after school is named world's best]]></title>
            <link>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</link>
            <guid>http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/politics/brexit-latest-oxford-university-worlds-best-funding-research-louise-richardson-vice-chancellor-a7322186.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The institution's Vice Chancellor says other universities are already trying to poach her academics]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supermarkets plan to shrink packets and use cheaper ingredients to save money after Brexit]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/22/supermarkets-plan-to-shrink-packets-and-use-cheaper-ingredients/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 07:06:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[With a Brexiteer in charge, the UK's ghastly, hypocritical, wasteful aid policy might change. And I say that as a Remainer]]></title>
            <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</link>
            <guid>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2016/09/21/with-a-brexiteer-in-charge-the-uks-ghastly-hypocritical-wasteful/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:23:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Watch top Tory insult and do scathing impression of Boris Johnson - who's now his boss]]></title>
            <link>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/watch-top-tory-insult-scathing-8892872</link>
            <guid>http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/uk-news/watch-top-tory-insult-scathing-8892872</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 15:21:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[&#xa; Sir Alan Duncan claims Boris never wanted to win the Brexit vote because then he&#x27;d have to deal with the &quot;s&#x2a;&#x2a;&#x2a;&quot;&#xa; ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swiss climbdown over free movement may deal blow to UK hopes]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:13:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MPs vote for local preference in job hires but plan does not include fixed limits on EU immigration</p><p>The Swiss parliament has largely caved in to EU intransigence on free movement in a decision that could deal a blow to British government hopes of being able to both control immigration and retain enhanced single market access after Brexit. </p><p>Swiss MPs approved legislation on Wednesday that would promote some local preference in job hires, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/06/swiss-eu-standoff-striking-similarities-uk-predicament">a compromise they hope will allow</a> vital economic relations with the bloc to be preserved following a 2014 referendum vote to cap EU immigration.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/22/switzerland-votes-for-compromise-to-preserve-relations-with-eu">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thursday September 22 2016]]></title>
            <link>http://www.theweek.co.uk/am/thursday-september-22-2016</link>
            <guid>http://www.theweek.co.uk/am/thursday-september-22-2016</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:37:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="short-teaser"> Company news, markets and financial talking points, available from 8am Monday to Friday</p> <div class="field-collection-container clearfix"><div class="field field-name-field-items field-type-field-collection field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25482" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Next leg of crisis 'to bring greatest debt jubilee'</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> The approaching third leg of the global financial crisis will prompt the greatest ever debt jubilee, says a report from the UN. "Alarm bells have been ringing over the explosion of corporate debt levels in emerging economies, which now exceed $25 trillion. Damaging deflationary spirals cannot be ruled out," it says. The Daily Telegraph says the chapter may prove to be the "definitive crisis of globalised capitalism". </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25483" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Supermarkets 'to shrink sizes rather than raise prices'</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Supermarkets will shrink packet sizes and switch to cheaper ingredients to offset an increase in costs after the Brexit vote, warns the Bank of England, saying food retailers are planning to "re-engineer products" rather than increase prices because of the slide in the pound. Shoppers are "highly price-sensitive" so grocers will use other means to hold prices at pre-referendum levels, it adds. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25484" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Fed policymakers expect rates rise this year</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> The majority of Federal Reserve policymakers expect a hike in US interest rates by the end of the year, minutes from the group's September meeting show. At the gathering, the Fed opted to hold rates between 0.25% and 0.5%, but three officials opposed the decision - the most dissents since December 2014. The Fed said: "The case for an increase in the federal funds rate has strengthened”. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25485" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Apple in talks for F1 team owner McLaren</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Apple is reportedly in talks for a shock £1.5bn deal to buy McLaren Technology Group, the F1 team owner and supercar-maker. A deal would shake up both the technology and motoring industries. The tech giant's interest in McLaren also highlights its ambition to produce an electric and driverless car. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25486" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Brexit: small business confidence at four-year low</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> Confidence among small businesses is at a four-year low amid growing anxiety that the economy will weaken dramatically as Britain prepares for Brexit. A survey by the Federation of Small Businesses shows that confidence has fallen for the third consecutive quarter. The lobby group described the study as a wake-up call for politicians to act to "avoid an economic slowdown". </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item odd"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25487" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">Quote of the day… The trouble with low interest rates</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> "As Donald Trump, Bernie Sanders and plenty of others have argued by keeping the interest rates low, the Fed has created a 'false economy' flooding the market with cheap money, via ultra-low interest rates, and driving stock markets to unsustainable highs (emphasis on the unsustainable)." The Guardian’s Jana Kasperkevic on the trouble with US interest rates policy. </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> <div class="field-item even"><div class="field-collection-view clearfix view-mode-full field-collection-view-final"><div class="entity entity-field-collection-item field-collection-item-field-items clearfix" about="/field-collection/field-items/25488" typeof=""> <div class="content"> <div class="field field-name-field-item-title field-type-text field-label-hidden">THE NUMBERS... AT 0730 GMT</div><div class="field field-name-field-item-body field-type-text-long field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><p> FTSE 100: up +0.06 to 6834.77<br /> Dow Jones: up +0.90 to 18293.70<br /> Dax: up +0.41 to 10436.49<br /> Cac 40: up +0.48 to 4409.55<br /> Nikkei: up +1.91 to 16807.62<br /> Hang Seng: up +0.30 to 23740.96<br /> US dollar: buys €0.89100 and £0.76480<br /> Sterling: buys $1.30750 and €1.16490<br /> Oil: $47.07 up +0.26 </p> </div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div></div> </div></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mortgages, wealth, banking and students]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 08:20:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fixed interest rate of mortgages could fall to less than 1 per cent next year if the Bank of England cuts the base rate again, in a move that would give the housing market a boost, <em>The Guardian</em> reports.</p>
<p>Rates on two-year, fixed-rate mortgages &ndash; already at record lows &ndash; could fall even further because of tough competition among lenders to attract new customers, according to leading City analysts.</p>
<p>Super-cheap home loans could give the market a boost after the vote for Brexit, which forced Threadneedle Street to cut rates to 0.25 per cent&nbsp;in August. This was the first rate-cut for more than seven years and economists expect the Bank to cut the base rate again &ndash; to just 0.1 per cent, possibly in November.</p>
<p>According to analysts at Bernstein, which is based in the City, another rate cut from the Bank of England would drive standard two-year fixed-rate mortgages to 1.1 per cent &ndash; and to less than 1 per cent for customers with a good credit rating.</p>
<p><strong>Housing</strong></p>
<p>The prices of London&rsquo;s most expensive homes will remain depressed until 2019, suffering from&nbsp;a cocktail of stamp duty hikes and post-referendum uncertainty, according to <em>The Telegraph</em>.</p>
<p>The first post-Brexit forecast for the&nbsp;prime central London housing market&nbsp;from Savills suggested there will be a 9 per cent fall in house prices this year, followed by two years of flat prices.&nbsp;It said that in 2019, prices in the capital will start to rise with an increase of 8 per cent.</p>
<p>This is far less downbeat than estimates from&nbsp;Soci&eacute;t&eacute; G&eacute;n&eacute;rale soon after the referendum, which claimed that house prices in&nbsp;the most expensive postcodes of central London could fall by as much as 50 per cent.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth</strong></p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font">British citizens have become the third-richest in the world after average wealth grew last year but it is those at the very top who have benefited most, research claims.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font">On average, Britons had &euro;95,600 (&pound;86,000) in savings, pensions and investments in 2015, after debts had been taken away &ndash; up 0.8 per cent compared to the previous year.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><em>Thisismoney</em> reports that the increase has seen Britain move up from fifth position in 2014 to third last year, when it was second only to Switzerland and USA in the net per-capital wealth league compiled by insurer and asset manager Allianz SE.</p>
<p class="mol-para-with-font"><strong>Banking</strong></p>
<p>Forty per cent of 55,000 consumers surveyed worldwide report decreased dependence on their traditional bank and increased excitement about alternatives, according to EY <em>2016 Global Consumer Banking Survey.</em></p>
<p>A lack of trust, changing consumer behaviors and expectations set by digital innovators and increased competition from new players are eroding traditional bank relevance. Retail banks scored just 75.1 out of a maximum value of 100 on inaugural EY Bank Relevance Index, which evaluates how customers interact with banks now and how they expect to in the future.</p>
<p><strong>Utility providers</strong></p>
<p>Employees waste an average of &pound;210 and &pound;310 a year on electricity and dual fuel bills respectively because they have not switched providers, according to new data from Mercer Harmonise. The data shows that, on average, employees could reduce their electricity bills by 18 per cent and their gas bills by 22 per cent.</p>
<p>Mercer Harmonise, a service from Mercer, a global consulting&nbsp;company, analysed data from 330 users of its latest service, a price comparison tool&nbsp; which allows employees to find the best provider across a range of services.</p>
<p><strong>Amazon</strong></p>
<p>Amazon&rsquo;s algorithms encourage customers pay more than they need to for popular products and appear to give more prominence to items that benefit the retail giant, according to an <a class="u-underline" href="https://www.propublica.org/article/amazon-says-it-puts-customers-first-but-its-pricing-algorithm-doesnt" target="_blank" data-link-name="in body link">investigation by ProPublica</a>.</p>
<p><em>The Guardian</em> reports that the investigation looked at 250 frequently purchased products over several weeks to see which ones were chosen to appear in the highly-prized &lsquo;buy box&rsquo; that pops up first as a suggested purchase.</p>
<p>Amazon not only sells products directly itself, but also allows other retailers to sell their own products through its platform. This means that the same product &ndash; say a particular set of headphones &ndash; could be offered by dozens of different vendors at different prices and with different shipping costs.</p>
<p><strong>Students</strong></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As more than half a million&nbsp;young people prepare to start university over the next two weeks, instead of enjoying Fresher&rsquo;s Week many will be preparing rent strike action&nbsp;and drawing up strict budget plans to stay in the black.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The latest research from SunLife reveals that despite stereotypes of blowing cash on going out, students actually budget more carefully than their parents and grandparents.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">According to SunLife&rsquo;s Cash Happy report, young people (18-24) are the most likely of all age groups to keep close track of their finances, with 60 per cent saying they formally budget, up from 59 per cent last year.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">In comparison, among their parent&rsquo;s generation and older (over 55s) just over a third formally budget.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/money-digest-59/">Mortgages, wealth, banking and students</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Labour has no option but to hold together | Jonathan Reynolds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[History is littered with examples of failed breakaway parties. A split is out of the question if we are to challenge Conservative hegemony<p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/labour" title="">Labour</a> has a had a torrid time of late. Since last summer the tone of the party’s internal debate has been shrill and bitter. Views have become increasingly polarised, and speculation about a possible split commonplace. We have been likened to a couple who want to divorce but who choose to stay together because we cannot afford to sell the house. Now the polls have closed and, in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/21/corbyn-camp-predicts-comfortable-victory-as-leadership-polls-close" title="">the aftermath of Jeremy Corbyn’s anticipated victory</a> on Saturday, people will almost certainly again raise the question of whether Labour should simply split and let its warring factions walk away from each other.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/20/get-serious-labour-rebels-deal-with-brexit-catastrophe">Get serious, Labour rebels, and deal with the Brexit catastrophe | Polly Toynbee</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/sep/22/labour-party-must-hold-together">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amber Rudd's offshore business past exposed]]></title>
            <link>http://www.theweek.co.uk/76848/amber-rudds-offshore-business-past-exposed</link>
            <guid>http://www.theweek.co.uk/76848/amber-rudds-offshore-business-past-exposed</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 11:15:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="primary-image"> <div id="file-100884" class="file file-image file-image-jpeg file-default"> <div class="content"> <img src="http://cdn2.theweek.co.uk/sites/theweek/files/styles/article_main_image/public/2016/09/160922_tax_returns_cameron.jpg?itok=99PwLQQD" alt="" /><div class="field field-name-field-file-credits field-type-text field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">Credits&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even">Jack Taylor/Getty Images</div> </div></div> </div> </div> </div> <p class="short-teaser"> Home Secretary&#039;s role in Bahamas-based companies shines fresh spotlight on politicians&#039; links to tax havens</p> <span class="field field-name-field-article-type field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden"> <span class="field-item even"><a href="/one-minute-read">One-Minute Read</a></span> </span><div class="field field-name-field-published-date field-type-datetime field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><span class="date-display-single">Thursday, September 22, 2016 - 12:15pm</span></div> </div></div><div class="field field-name-field-related-articles field-type-node-reference field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">See related&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"> <div class="node node-article node-promoted even node-inline-teaser"> <h5><span><a href="/panama-papers/71379/panama-papers-david-camerons-tax-returns-show-hypocrisy-is-rife">Panama Papers: David Cameron&#039;s tax returns show hypocrisy is rife</a></span></h5> <div class="content"> </div> </div> </div> </div></div><div class="field field-name-body"> <div class="field-item even"> <div class="field field-name-field-related-articles field-type-node-reference field-label-above"> <div class="field-label">See related&nbsp;</div> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><a href="/75644/ford-aims-to-sell-first-driverless-car-by-2021">Ford aims to sell first driverless car by 2021</a></div> <div class="field-item odd"><a href="/67776/google-accepts-blame-for-self-driving-car-crash">Google and Fiat-Chrysler team up for self-driving car</a></div> </div></div><p>Five months after the sensational Panama Papers laid bare David Cameron's past involvement in an offshore investment fund, another top Tory has been linked with a tax haven.</p> <p>Home Secretary Amber Rudd has been named as a past director of two companies registered in the Bahamas, which imposes no income, corporate or wealth taxes and was named among 30 "unco-operative tax havens" by the European Union last year.</p> <p>The politician was among the directors of more than 175,000 companies in the Caribbean island named in a cache of 1.3 million files passed to German newspaper Suddeutsche Zeitung and shared with the International Bureau of Investigative Journalists and media partners including <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/21/bahamas-leaks-reveal-amber-rudd-involvement-offshore-firms">The Guardian</a> and the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-37432666">BBC</a>.</p> <p>In its report, the Guardian also revealed that Rudd, in a separate business venture, was a director of Monticello plc, which found itself at the centre of an investigation into alleged "share ramping" that led to a co-director being jailed.</p> <p>Rudd, who supported Cameron when he faced questions over his own offshore dealings, has not commented personally on the reports.</p> <p>A spokesperson said: "It is a matter of public record that Amber had a career in business before entering politics. Monticello was thoroughly investigated 16 years ago and those who acted wrongly were identified and prosecuted."</p> <p>Following the revelations, Green Party speaker on finance Molly Scott Cato MEP said: "[Prime Minister] Theresa May made clear that she would lead a government that works for everyone and would encourage a more ethical approach to business.</p> <p>"In this context it is difficult to see how she can continue to have confidence in Amber Rudd as home secretary."</p> <p>Liberal Democrat leader Tim Farron tweeted Rudd "must provide clarity".</p> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en-gb"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Serious questions for Amber Rudd-she must provide clarity. The public are sick of the idea of politicians tying to dodge the rules they make</p> <p>&mdash; Tim Farron (@timfarron) <a href="https://twitter.com/timfarron/status/778662949401559044">21 September 2016</a></p></blockquote> <p> According to the documents, Rudd was director of the Bahamas-based Advanced Asset Allocation Fund and Advanced Asset Allocation Management between 1998 and 2000. It is not clear if she invested in the firms or if they were used to avoid any tax and there is no suggestion of any wrongdoing.</p> <p>Former associate Alistair Buchanan told the BBC the companies were used to market an investment fund to investors and were registered in the Bahamas purely for administrative purposes. "You could not set up those funds in England at that time, now you can," he said.</p> <p>Rudd's links to Monticello came after it bought out The Zinc Corporation, at which she was a director, in 1999.</p> <p>She resigned her position the following year, five months after trading in Monticello's shares was suspended following co-director Mark O'Hanlon making false statements that massively inflated the company's value.</p> <p>O'Hanlon was eventually convicted of making a false statement and sentenced to 18 months in prison in 2007. He was later jailed again in 2013 on an unrelated fraud charge. </p> </div> </div><div class="field field-name-field-category-secondary field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden"> <div class="field-items"> <div class="field-item even"><a href="/economy">Economy</a></div> </div></div>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Nate Silver on his high horse over Trump – again?]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 17:12:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few years ago, the pollster Nate Silver wrote a best-selling book saying (in effect) that political pundits talk&nbsp;rot and that only data-armed policy&nbsp;analysts like him could be relied on to know&nbsp;what was going on. He&rsquo;d based his reputation on the 2012 US election, whose results he predicted. YouGov predicted it too, but Silver has a greater gift for self-publicity.</p>
<p>His theory was later placed in doubt when he failed to predict the result of the UK General Election in a BBC documentary &mdash; which later <a href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2015/07/revealed-the-documentary-the-bbc-dont-want-you-to-see/" target="_blank">mysteriously disappeared</a>. Despite this, he continues to&nbsp;encourage epigones in Britain, who can (and still do) come out with columns attacking folk&nbsp;for their inferior, prejudice-driven analysis. Today, Nate Silver is&nbsp;at it again &mdash; over Trump:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Never seen otherwise-smart people in so much denial about something as they are about Trump&rsquo;s chances. Same mistake as primaries, Brexit. <a href="https://t.co/qBPRKoZV4R">https://t.co/qBPRKoZV4R</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Nate Silver (@NateSilver538) <a href="https://twitter.com/NateSilver538/status/778563584888627200">September 21, 2016</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Yes, a lot of&nbsp;people feel&nbsp;certain that America just won&rsquo;t choose Trump &ndash; but&nbsp;Mr S&nbsp;suspects that doesn&rsquo;t really make them in &lsquo;denial&rsquo;. Given the recent performance of pollsters, from the Israeli election to Brexit,&nbsp;who&rsquo;s to say that the figures are any more accurate than the instinct of someone with decent judgement?</p>
<p>The idea that pollsters have &lsquo;done a Newton&rsquo; on politics is one of the great comic vanities of our times. The polls are all over the shop:&nbsp;witness last year&rsquo;s general election, and Brexit. If your starting position is that you&rsquo;re simply smarter than anyone else, or can see more clearly due to your superior grasp of data, then you can end up getting egg on your face. &nbsp;A bit like the person who wrote this:-</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9622242" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48.png" alt="Screen Shot 2016-09-21 at 15.21.48" width="629" height="446" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48.png 629w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-300x213.png 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-582x413.png 582w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/09/Screen-Shot-2016-09-21-at-15.21.48-146x104.png 146w" sizes="(max-width: 629px) 100vw, 629px"></p>
<p>Might the media have been justified in freaking out about Donald Trump&rsquo;s polls, even if the numbers&nbsp;were small?
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/spectator_money_daily_digest_2" name='&ldquo;money"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/nate-silver-high-horse-trump/">Why is Nate Silver on his high horse over Trump &#8211; again?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Spectator podcast: The indestructibles]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/283984341&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false" width="100%" height="166" frameborder="no" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This weekend, the Labour party will convene in Liverpool for its annual conference. By that point it will have a new leader who, if all current polling is to be believed, will be the same as its old one. Jeremy Corbyn looks set to defy the wishes of his fellow MPs and strengthen his grip on the party. In his cover piece this week, <strong>James Forsyth</strong> looks at the whole of the far left movement, from the leader&rsquo;s office to the grass roots activists, and observes that &lsquo;they are tightening their grip over the party from top to bottom, something the Blairites never did.&rsquo; So, what&rsquo;s next for the Labour party? Does it have a future appealing to moderate social democrats? Or has it truly been lost to the momentum of this new movement? James Forsyth thinks the race is over:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;We await the result on Saturday, I don&rsquo;t think we can say with baited breath because everyone is operating under the assumption that Jeremy Corbyn has won. All of the arguments in the Labour party take it as a given that he has won and Owen Smith&rsquo;s message to his supporters this morning seems like a valedictory message rather than a short of &lsquo;keep your fingers crossed and see you on Saturday&rsquo; message.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Joining us on the podcast,&nbsp;<strong>Nick Cohen</strong> said that:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;What is very depressing for anyone who is opposed to Corbynism is: all the faults that make it so easy for the Conservatives and SNP to attack him, have made it very hard for Labour party lefties who are opposed to Corbyn to unseat him. There was one poll done of Corbyn supporters which said 90% believed a PR agency had organised what they called the &lsquo;coup against Corbyn&rsquo;. This is completely untrue.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is Hong Kong really the future of Britain&rsquo;s Brexit? In his column this week, <strong>James Delingpole</strong> says he&rsquo;s seen the future and it lies in the colony that Britain created when a Scottish colonial administration decided to cut taxes, cut regulation and see Hong Kong go from one of the poorest parts of the world to one of the richest. As James Delingpole observes:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;My step-son was like a lot of middle-class children in this country who were not uber-bright, but are currently being failed in Britain by our culture, which is not as can-do as Hong Kong. I wouldn&rsquo;t say that Hong Kong&rsquo;s success is all to do with the legacy of British administration, because I think you also have to factor in the business acumen of the Hong Kong Chinese, but nevertheless I think we British sowed the seeds for Hong Kong&rsquo;s success.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>But Spectator editor&nbsp;<strong>Fraser Nelson</strong> counters:</p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;I wish I was as sure as James about this. Of course, you can go to Hong Kong and you can admire it, but you have to work out how much of that Cantonese culture you can import in Britain. And the other thing, which underlines James&rsquo; optimism also underlines my sense right now of foreboding, because there is a certain logic amongst some Brexiteers that, once we pull out of the EU, we can start slashing regulations, start slashing the tax burden, start being a proper free trading country. I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s going to be anything like as easy as that.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And finally, this week&rsquo;s sees the rare occasion that two of the Spectator&rsquo;s longest serving and most respected columnists are under the same roof. Taki&rsquo;s High Life and Jeremy Clarke&rsquo;s Low Life have been magazine favourites for decades, sitting side by side on the page, even as they describe two very different ways of living. I&rsquo;m joined now by <strong>Taki</strong> and <strong>Jeremy Clarke</strong> to answer the age old question: which is better, the high life or the low life? As Taki observes:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&lsquo;With High Life, I have to keep a certain standard, where Jeremy has nothing to live up to except Jeffrey&nbsp;Bernard. I think both of us have a very good time &ndash; he&rsquo;s younger, so he has more stamina, but I have more experience.&rsquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>For the juiciest bits of Jeremy and Taki&rsquo;s conversation, tune into the full podcast!</p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-spectator-podcast/id793236670?mt=2" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft wp-image-9589192 size-full" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-620x210.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="76" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-620x210.jpg 620w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-300x101.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes-146x49.jpg 146w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-iTunes.jpg 710w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px"></a><a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-spectator-podcast" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-9589212 size-full" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-620x210.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="76" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-620x210.jpg 620w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-300x101.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher-146x49.jpg 146w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/08/Spec-Stitcher.jpg 710w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px"></a></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9498652" src="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="244" srcset="//cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1.jpg 300w, //cdn2.spectator.co.uk/files/2016/06/image004-300x244-1-1-146x119.jpg 146w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></p>
<p><em>This podcast is sponsored by Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd, who have long supplied wine for The Spectator. If you&rsquo;ve always wanted to start a wine cellar, 2016 could be the perfect time. Whether you are looking to buy for future drinking, for investment or a little of both, Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd&rsquo;s Cellar Plan is designed to suit all tastes and budgets. A&nbsp;personal Account Manager will be on hand to offer advice and assistance, and enable you to benefit from three centuries&rsquo; worth of relationships with the leading wine growers. To find out more about starting a wine cellar with Berry Bros. &amp; Rudd, visit <a href="https://www.bbr.com/cellar-plan" target="_blank">bbr.com/cellarplan</a></em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"> </div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/spectator-podcast-indestructibles/">The Spectator podcast: The indestructibles</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Britain has shown Germany how to handle a migrant crisis]]></title>
            <link>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/</link>
            <guid>http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 09:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Only now does Angela Merkel <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/sep/19/angela-merkel-admits-mistakes-asylum-seekers-election">concede</a> that she made mistakes when&nbsp;admitting a million refugees last year. It was obvious to most people in Europe at the time that her undoubtedly warm-hearted gesture would lead to catastrophic results. In declaring that all Syrian refugees would be welcome if they made it to Germany, she doubled the fortunes of the human trafficking industry. The asylum seekers came from Syria and North Africa through Austria and Hungary, having landed on the shores of Italy and Greece. Thousands died on the way.</p>
<p>When Theresa May addressed the United Nations in New York yesterday, she was able to point to a British way of handling the crisis. Rather than reward those with the strength or money to make it to a western country, Britain has ploughed hundreds of millions of pounds into giving food, shelter and support to far more refugees in Jordan, Turkey and Lebanon. Mrs May didn&rsquo;t quite say it, but the lessons from the British approach are clear: the 1951 Refugee Convention (the obligation to shelter those who arrive) was designed to prevent a recurrence of problems seen in the 1930s. It needs updating. The world is on the move, but its migration policies are not.</p>
<p>The consequences of getting this wrong are political as well as humanitarian. In Germany, in particular, there is a sense that the authorities have lost control and that established political parties cannot think or talk plainly about the problem. Last weekend, the anti-immigrant Alternative f&uuml;r Deutschland (AfD) won 14 per cent of the popular vote in Berlin state elections, and is now set to become the third-largest party in the Bundestag after next year&rsquo;s national elections. In Berlin, the Social Democrats, led by the city&rsquo;s mayor Michael M&uuml;ller, scraped victory with 22 per cent of the vote. Never in Germany&rsquo;s postwar history has a winner attracted such a small share.</p>
<p>Merkel&rsquo;s Christian Democrats finished behind the AfD in elections held in her home state of Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania three weeks ago. As Marine Le Pen remarked at the time, things that haven&rsquo;t happened for decades are now happening all of the time. Her Front National looks likely to make the final round in the coming French presidential election.</p>
<p>The three-year-old AfD is no German version of Ukip. In January, its leader Frauke Petry called for firearms to be used against migrants trying to enter Germany from Austria. A manifesto it published in May declared that Islam is not compatible with the German constitution, and called for a ban on minarets and burkas. The party&rsquo;s rise is accompanied by an increase in street violence in Germany. Fighting broke out last weekend between neo-Nazis and asylum seekers in the hilltop town of Bautzen in Saxony; a hundred police were needed to restore order. Two years ago there were 199 criminal attacks on refugee shelters; so far this year there have been 726.</p>
<p>Similar stories can be seen across the continent, where the shock of the summer terror attacks has not subsided. In Austria, a re-run of the presidential election could well lead to a victory for Norbert Hofer of the anti-immigrant Freedom party. The sense of government incompetence has been underlined by the election itself, postponed due to defective glue being used in postal ballot envelopes. Spain is now bracing itself for its third parliamentary election in a year, the various political factions having failed to form a coherent government. The coming Italian referendum on constitutional reform will be more a referendum on Matteo Renzi and his pro-EU government. If he loses, then the beneficiary will be Beppe Grillo&rsquo;s populist Five Star movement, whose inability to rule is being shown by the chaotic reign of Virginia Raggi, elected mayor of Rome three months ago. No wonder that Jean-Claude Juncker, president of the European Commission, has been talking about an &lsquo;existential crisis&rsquo;.</p>
<p>And in Britain? Racist and xenophobic politics here have never been weaker. Brexit was a vote to control, rather than reverse, immigration &mdash; and a vote to avoid the kind of problems now fermenting on the continent. The explicitly anti-racist Ukip is one of many parties now demanding that Theresa May grants permanent residency rights to all EU migrants living in Britain. The BNP is the only party that disagrees with this, but its vote fell by 99 per cent at the last election. Attempts to create alternative racist parties in recent years have ended in failure.</p>
<p>As Mrs May said in New York, borders serve a purpose. Failure to manage them erodes public confidence, and also undermines support for immigration and for helping refugees. The&nbsp;European no-borders project was conceived at an era where there was very low movement of people &ndash; the picture has transformed, now.</p>
<p>Britain has managed a recession and mass immigration with barely a fraction of the xenophobic backlash seen on the Continent.&nbsp;No one would be so bold as to say that racism has been eradicated from Britain &ndash; but we&nbsp;have no&nbsp;equivalent of AfD. When you consider the size of the&nbsp;immigration into Britain, and the depth and duration of the recent recession, it&rsquo;s&nbsp;something&nbsp;rather remarkable &ndash; and underlines Britain&rsquo;s claim to be not only one of most tolerant countries in the world but the greatest melting pot in Europe.</p>
<p>Mrs May has, so far, failed in her attempts to control immigration. But British refugee policies have been more innovative and effective.&nbsp;We may accept fewer people to our shores, but we do process a&nbsp;significant number. Not so long ago, this magazine was arguing&nbsp;for more Syrians to be admitted &ndash; David&nbsp;Cameron responded. The balance is, now, about right. And it&rsquo;s right because Britain now does more than perhaps any other European country to help refugees &ndash; precisely because our help is concentrated in countries where help can go furthest.</p>
<p>Mass migration on the scale of recent years is unprecedented. This is a very new problem, but only Britain has responded with a new approach &mdash; one that Europe&rsquo;s leaders might well end up adopting.</p>
<p><em>This is an extract from this week&rsquo;s magazine, available from tomorrow</em>
</p><div class="spectator-promo"><iframe src="http://newsletters.spectator.co.uk/k/The-Spectator/copy_of_evening_blend_inline_form" name='&ldquo;coffee-house"' scrolling="no" frameborder="no" align="center" height="475px" width="100%"><br></iframe></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/2016/09/britain-shown-germany-handle-migrant-crisis/">Britain has shown Germany how to handle a migrant crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk">Coffee House</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>