<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>BriefBot</title>
        <description>Brexit, explained</description>
        <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 23:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <title>BriefBot</title>
            <url>http://example.com/image.png</url>
            <link>https://briefbot.github.io/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2016, Explaain</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lloyds considers opening EU subsidiary to be ready for Brexit]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 10:33:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Insurance market working on ‘contingency plan’ so it can continue trading across Europe once article 50 is triggered</p><p>Lloyd’s of London is looking at opening an office in another EU state to protect its insurance underwriting business from the impact of the UK’s Brexit vote.</p><p>Lloyd’s confirmed on Thursday that the world’s oldest insurance underwriting market was drawing up a contingency plan that could be implemented as soon as Theresa May’s government triggers article 50 to begin formal negotiations to leave the EU, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/16/theresa-may-likely-trigger-article-50-brexit-talks-early-2017">which is expected early next year</a>. </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/brexit-vote-imajor-lloyds-insurance-markets-profits-rise">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK economy faces challenging period after Brexit vote, says Bank]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:35:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Financial policy committee warns withdrawal from the EU poses risks but will not be used to reduce regulation of banks</p><p>Bank of England financial policymakers have warned that the UK economy faces a “challenging period of uncertainty and adjustment” following the Brexit vote. </p><p>However the Bank, providing a quarterly update on the health of the financial system, said the UK’s withdrawal from the European Union would not be used as a way to reduce regulation on the banking sector.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/sep/22/uk-economy-faces-challenging-period-after-brexit-vote-says-bank">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Battles of Britain, table-tennis trickery and the brilliant Lamar Jackson | Classic YouTube]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 09:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week’s roundup also features drone surfing, hardcore whiff-whaff, and the best way to overtake a peloton</p><p>1) It doesn’t get easier for Brendan Rodgers. A fortnight after his side <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/13/barcelona-celtic-champions-league-match-report">took a pasting in Spain</a>, it’s ‘Battle’ of Britain week: Celtic versus Manchester City on Wednesday. He can take heart, though, from some notable BoB classics – including <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qsDPlK2qpEw">Celtic’s 2-1 1970 European Cup semi-final win </a>over Don Revie’s Leeds in front of 136,000 at Hampden Park; Rangers winning both legs of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ndai-x2F1GM&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=30s">1992’s clash with Leeds</a>; Alex Ferguson’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s3xh4-t9fwg">Aberdeen undoing Uefa Cup holders Ipswich</a> in 1981; and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vZIXnyLboOY">Celtic beating Liverpool</a> on the way to the 2003 Uefa Cup final. </p><p>2) Life’s good right now for Lamar Jackson – Louisville Cardinals’ Heisman Trophy favourite and teen <a href="http://www.campusrush.com/lamar-jackson-louisville-cardinals-football-2010380683.html">Sports Illustrated coverstar</a>. Here’s a flavour: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZHiKOxR9XU8">an Eminem backed showreel</a>, a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC-bMQWpM7I">high-school highlight</a>, some more <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=65Y5YR7zGqg">high-school highlights</a>, an engaging <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=avhiLsvHAtY">post-game chat</a>, and this: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W90diVFAZVU">HE HAS THE JETS, AND HE TURNS THEM ON</a>. He’s the American football version of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RoUc0iAjHvY">this kid</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/classic-youtube-best-sports-clips">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Revolutionary’ European Tour proposals risk turning golf into a gimmick | Ewan Murray]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 08:59:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Last week the European Tour announced details of the World Super 6 Perth which includes 54 holes of stroke play, six-hole match play games and a 90m knockout hole. Will hitting shots on the run or through rings of fire be next?<p>At times like these, the PGA Tour properly flexes its financial muscle. This week’s Tour Championship at East Lake concludes a four-event series which delivers $34m in prize monies. That’s before the epic bonus pool for the FedEx Cup, starting with a $10m first prize, is even taken into account.</p><p>These riches are deemed grotesque by some, even if they still lag behind the peak of American team sports. It also raises a smile that the PGA Tour’s strength is endorsed immediately before the Ryder Cup, an iconic competition to which it has no commercial attachment. Perhaps the proximity of this playoff series is actually detrimental to the biennial meeting of Europe and the United States, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/20/jordan-spieth-ryder-cup-fedex-cup-10m" title="">given how narratives overlap</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/blog/2016/sep/22/european-tour-world-super-6-perth-golf-gimmick">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lloyd's Of London rues Brexit vote result]]></title>
            <link>http://news.sky.com/story/lloyds-of-london-sees-europe-trading-threat-after-eu-vote-10588019</link>
            <guid>http://news.sky.com/story/lloyds-of-london-sees-europe-trading-threat-after-eu-vote-10588019</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Lloyd's of London has described the UK's vote to leave the EU as a "major issue for us", saying it is working on a plan to ensure it can still trade across Europe.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May more trusted than Corbyn on Britain's key issues, poll finds]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 06:00:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protecting NHS, reducing immigration and Brexit trade deals emerge as voter priorities in survey and PM wins on all three</p><p>Theresa May is more trusted than Jeremy Corbyn to tackle the most urgent problems in post-Brexit Britain, including safeguarding the NHS, according to a new poll seen exclusively by the Guardian.</p><p>Asked what politicians’ priorities should be, the top three choices in the Britain Thinks poll were safeguarding the health service, significantly reducing immigration and striking new trade deals as Britain leaves the European Union.<br></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/22/theresa-may-more-trusted-than-jeremy-corbyn-britains-key-issues-poll">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FA: Brexit will not derail plans to host final stages of Euro 2020 or 2028 bid]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 20:23:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[• FA’s Martin Glenn says vote to leave EU will not affect hosting of 2020 games<br />• Chairman Greg Clarke says FA is reaching out to friends in Uefa over 2028 bid<p>The Football Association has insisted Brexit will not derail its plans to hold the final stages of Euro 2020 at Wembley, hoping it will act as precursor to an England bid to host the 2028 European Championship.</p><p>Since the FA won the right to stage the 2020 semi-finals and final at Wembley as one of 12 venues for the tournament, which will be scattered across Europe under a plan drawn up by the former Uefa president Michel Platini, the UK has voted to leave the European Union.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2016/sep/21/brexit-will-not-derail-plans-host-final-stages-euro-2020-2028">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What's next for Apple's €13bn tax battle?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:50:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Margrethe Vestager is on a US charm offensive, making the case about recovering alleged unpaid taxes – but she has been met with more offense than charm</p><p>In the wake of last month’s controversial decision by the European Commission to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2016/aug/30/apple-pay-back-taxes-eu-ruling-ireland-state-aid">seek “recovery of illegal state aid” for alleged unpaid taxes in Ireland</a> from Apple of up to €13bn – plus interest – the European competition commissioner, Margrethe Vestager, went to the United States this week on a “charm offensive” to make her case to government officials, lawmakers and trade officials.</p><p>Vestager met with US treasury secretary Jacob Lew, had a closed-door session with members of the US Senate finance committee, and spoke at the Global Antitrust Enforcement Symposium at Georgetown University, where she gave a vigorous defense of the EC’s decision.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/sep/21/apple-tax-battle-ireland-state-aid-laws">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ryder Cup 2016: Tiger Woods may have adverse influence, claims Westwood]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 16:49:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[• Westwood: ‘He could have an adverse effect in the USA team room’<br />• Ryder Cup veteran also queries ‘non-selection’ of Bubba Watson<p>The first blow of the phoney war which always precedes a Ryder Cup has been landed by Lee Westwood, who has pointed towards the potentially “adverse” influence of Tiger Woods as a vice-captain of the USA.</p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/paul-casey-fedex-cup-finale-european-tour-ryder-cup">Paul Casey’s FedEx finale may spring change in Europe’s qualification rules</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/sep/21/ryder-cup-2016-tiger-woods-lee-westwood">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Philip Pullman calls for UK to adopt EU plans to protect authors' royalties]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 13:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>His Dark Materials author has appealed for EU directive to be introduced in Britain, to block ‘unfair practices that currently prevent authors making a living’</p><p>His Dark Materials author Philip Pullman has welcomed a “badly need[ed]” new proposal from the European Commission that would protect authors who achieve unexpected success from missing out on royalties.</p><p>Pullman was speaking as president of the Society of Authors, which is pressing the UK government to adopt clauses from the <a href="http://ec.europa.eu/transparency/regdoc/rep/1/2016/EN/1-2016-593-EN-F1-1.PDF">new EU draft directive on the digital single market</a> in order to “avoid unfair practices that currently prevent authors making a living from writing”. The Society highlighted the case of Horrid Henry author Francesca Simon, who has not received any royalties from the television and film adaptations of her <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/childrens-books-site/2016/may/25/francesca-simon-i-love-writing-in-the-first-person">Horrid Henry books</a>, despite the series being broadcast in 44 countries with more than 1.5m DVDs sold.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2016/sep/21/philip-pullman-calls-for-uk-to-adopt-eu-plans-to-protect-authors-royalties">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brits in the EU: are you applying for citizenship?]]></title>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship</link>
            <guid>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 08:45:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you live or work in an EU country and are applying for citizenship due to the Brexit vote, we want to hear from you<br></p><p>After Britain’s vote to leave the European Union, British citizens living and working across the EU <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/jun/27/leave-vote-prompts-rush-dual-nationality-eu-passports">have been weighing up their futures</a>.<br></p><p> <span>Related: </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/13/zero-chance-eu-citizens-keep-same-rights-post-brexit-expert">Zero chance EU citizens in UK will keep same rights post-Brexit, says expert</a> </p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2016/sep/14/brits-in-the-eu-are-you-applying-for-citizenship">Continue reading...</a>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>